<corpus>
  <document>
    <document_id>bc1944</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/liege-airport-inks-three-major-contracts-with-orange-belgium-alibaba-cloud-qatar-airways-air-cargo</url>
    <title>Liege Airport inks three major contracts with Orange Belgium, Alibaba Cloud, Qatar Airways</title>
    <author>STAT Times</author>
    <published_time>2019-11-15T13:29:00+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Liege Airport</topic>
      <topic>WeCargo</topic>
      <topic>Orange Belgium</topic>
      <topic>Alibaba Cloud</topic>
      <topic>Qatar Airways</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Liege Airport has forged three important partnership agreements with Orange Belgium, Alibaba Cloud and Qatar Airways on the sidelines of the WeCargo event, which brought together start-ups, air cargo industrialists and investors.</p>
      <p>Qatar Airways Cargo will extend its contract with Liege Airport and grow its operations. For Guillaume Halleux, Chief Officer of Cargo Qatar Airways, the Liege Airport hub is an important asset in his company's network, "We are very satisfied with the services received at Liege and its logistic connections with the major European cities. Liege Airport is a guarantee of future growth and we are happy to contribute to the increase of jobs in the Liege region."</p>
      <p>Another deal was signed with Alibaba Cloud, the technology subsidiary of Alibaba, which has a successful AI platform and which "has the skills and experience needed to transform, digitise and support our airport's operations and handling procedures," read the official statement.</p>
      <p>Finally, a partnership agreement to develop the internet of things and smart services was signed with Orange Belgium. Under the terms of this deal, Orange Belgium and Liege Airport will select together which cargo activities to study and for which technological solutions will be implemented. These case studies will serve the operators and businesses working at the airport.</p>
      <p>"We are delighted to work with Liege Airport in developing innovative solutions. The logistics sector presents many opportunities to make the most of our technological expertise concerning connected objects or track &amp; trace solutions. We also welcome the possibility to help develop this economic activity hub, which is so important for the Liege region," said Michaël Trabbia, CEO of Orange Belgium.</p>
      <p>Speaking about these partnerships, Luc Partoune, CEO of Liege Airport, said, "If we want to stay at the cutting edge and continue to grow as a cargo-only airport, we must energise our ecosystem. This was the main goal of WeCargo: to energise and inspire the international cargo community. This goal was met and we are already preparing the next WeCargo event. The partnership agreements with Alibaba Cloud and Orange Belgium covering digital matters, as well as the extension and growth of Qatar Airways on the site, are leading the airport towards excellence."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>c53ff3</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/dnata-signs-contract-implement-ibs-icargo-network/</url>
    <title>dnata signs contract to implement IBS iCargo across its network</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2018-03-13T10:30:59+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Cargo Handling News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Ashok Rajan</topic>
      <topic>Bernd Struck</topic>
      <topic>Dnata</topic>
      <topic>dnata iCargo</topic>
      <topic>IBS Software</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Dnata has signed a contract with IBS Software to implement the iCargo terminal operation suite across all of its stations.</p>
      <p>It is the first ground handler to launch a global roll out of iCargo and have its operations on one united platform using unified processes.</p>
      <p>The system is expected to be gradually implemented by 2020, and iCargo will have a user base of over 5,000 staff members across 27 stations, in 10 countries from the USA to Australia, interfacing seamlessly with a host of other system applications within the IT landscape of the business.</p>
      <p>Dnata senior vice president UAE cargo &amp; DWC airlines services, Bernd Struck says: "We are always in pursuit of delivering exceptional service and improving safety and efficiencies. With iCargo as our technology platform, we are confident that we can stay agile and adapt to the fast changing needs of our customers across the globe."</p>
      <p>IBS Software senior vice president and head of airline cargo services, Ashok Rajan says: "iCargo is a strong, stable and modern IT platform widely accepted to be best suited to bring about transformational change in the airline cargo industry. Over the years, significant investment has gone in to give iCargo a strong product roadmap, continuously incorporating technology led innovation and building a collaborative community model of development.</p>
      <p>"I am extremely pleased and excited to welcome dnata, one of the fastest growing Ground Handling companies in the world, as our latest customer for iCargo and look forward to a mutually beneficial long-term partnership."</p>
      <p>Through iCargo, dnata will automate key business and operational functions including ULD management, quality monitoring and mail management with the single integrated platform.</p>
      <p>The companies say that real-time availability of operational information through iCargo will help provide actionable insights that will greatly improve revenue generation and operational efficiencies.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>0942b7</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/eqt-acquire-chep-aerospace-solutions/</url>
    <title>EQT to acquire CHEP Aerospace Solutions</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2016-11-02T09:21:55+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Airfreight Industry Supplier News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Brambles</topic>
      <topic>CHEP Aerospace Solutions</topic>
      <topic>Dr Ludwig Bertsch</topic>
      <topic>EQT Infrastructure II</topic>
      <topic>Ulrich Kollensperger</topic>
      <topic>Unit load device</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>CHEP Aerospace Solutions is to be sold to infrastructure fund company, EQT Infrastructure II, in a transaction due to be completed during November 2016.</p>
      <p>CHEP was formed by Brambles in 2011 following the acquisition and integration of a number of unit load device (ULD) companies. The Australian logistics firm has sold it to EQT in a $130 million Australian dollar deal.</p>
      <p>The existing CHEP leadership team will remain in place and EQT Infrastructure says it will continue to strengthen the company's capabilities.</p>
      <p>CHEP Aerospace Solutions president, Dr Ludwig Bertsch says: "We are excited to join EQT Infrastructure, one of the world's most respected infrastructure funds, which combines the very best people with the industry expertise in infrastructure management that will allow us to continue to grow and provide smarter solutions and unparalleled customer service to the aviation industry."</p>
      <p>EQT Partners director and investment advisor to EQT Infrastructure, Ulrich Kollensperger adds: "The Company has a proven business model, an impressive customer base and a promising pipeline of prospective airline clients.</p>
      <p>"The industrial board of directors including senior leaders with aviation expertise will support CHEP Aerospace Solutions in growing its asset base and offer pooling, management, maintenance and repair to more airlines globally."</p>
      <p>CHEP manages approximately 100,000 ULDs and serves more than 90 airlines across a network of 48 global services centres and 420 airports. It will retain its headquarters in Switzerland, along with regional operations centres in the UK, Thailand and the USA, and global service centres in Europe, Middle East and Africa, Asia Pacific and the Americas.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>69514b</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/cargo-airport/van-stekelenburg-to-succeed-schiphols-osinga/</url>
    <title>Van Stekelenburg to succeed Schiphol's Osinga</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time>2015-04-14T10:57:24+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>cargo-airport</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic/>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Jonas van Stekelenburg is to succeed Amsterdam Airport Schiphol cargo director Enno Osinga who is retiring in September. Van Stekelenburg has worked on sustainability, energy efficiency and carbon reduction for the Netherlands gateway and was also responsible for establishing the Mainport Innovation Fund. He has also worked on The Grounds, a Schiphol Group initiative to work with other companies and knowledge institutes to develop innovations for a sustainable airport. According to an airport statement, Van Stekelenburg "will be involved in the continued development of Schiphol's cargo marketplace" and "will find the extensive work performed by Enno Osinga, in collaboration with the Schiphol Cargo team, a solid foundation to build upon." Schiphol Group director and chief commercial officer Maarten de Groof added: "Jonas has earned his spurs at Schiphol Group, both in Amsterdam and abroad."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>60ff41</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/american-airlines-cargo-releases-enhanced-air-waybill-tracking-on-website/</url>
    <title>American Airlines Cargo releases enhanced air waybill tracking on website</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time>2016-02-10T10:03:17+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic/>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>American Airlines Cargo has introducedredesigned tracking functionalities on its website. Developed to "increase visibility into the entire shipping process", the customised tracking capabilities will improve shipment visibility from booking to delivery. The features include: • Live "at-a-glance" status updates via color-coded progress bars • Detailed flight, AWB and Customs information • Simple access and navigation to shipping history • Added sorting and viewing capabilities for logged-in users Logged-in users can also sort their shipments by origin and destination, which gives them the ability to quickly simplify and consolidate the information displayed on their screens. "We gathered feedback from our customers on the tracking process and used that valuable information to make needed changes — overall it's just a simpler and more user-friendly experience," said Eric Mathieu, Cargo's director of customer experience. "Our customers wanted better organization, increased transparency into their flights and shipments, and real-time updates from point A to point B. This is a much easier tool to use."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>abc767</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/freighter-operator/maskargo-to-increase-real-time-shipment-visibility-with-unisys-system/</url>
    <title>MASkargo to increase real-time shipment visibility with Unisys system</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time>2019-02-06T09:00:33+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic/>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>MASkargo will use cloud-based Unisys logistics solutions' Digi-IQ and Digi-Portal to provide "complete visibility" in the cargo shipment lifecycle. The cargo division of Malaysia Airlines is the largest cargo ground handling agent in Malaysia and handles more than 30 customer airlines at its Advanced Cargo Centre, processing more than 800,000 air waybills per year. Ibrahim Mohamed Salleh, chief executive of MASkargo, said: "Kuala Lumpur is a vital and growing cargo transit hub for Asia. Using Unisys Digi-Portal we will be able to reach an even wider market of forwarders and shippers with an easy-to-use and secure online booking tool. "Digi-IQ will provide us and our customers with greater visibility of their supply chain via real-time continuous monitoring of shipments tracked against key milestones. "This will also help us identify and forecast potential service disruptions and take proactive measures to address them in advance. This will help us to provide a better service and reliability for our customers." Under a five-year engagement signed in November 2018, MASkargo will join the Unisys Digi-Portal e-commerce platform to promote its inventory to a wider global community of more than 25,000 buyers at forwarders, airlines, general sales agents and handlers across more than 140+ countries. MASkargo will also use Unisys Digi-IQ to track, report and measure shipments, "meeting and exceeding the worldwide cargo industry standards set by IATA Cargo iQ," said an airlines spokesperson. MASkargo has used the core Digistics cloud-based logistics management system to manage its domestic and international cargo services since 2016. Added the spokesperson: "Digi-IQ automatically builds a route map for each shipment based on origin, destination, product, station operating hours, aircraft types and other factors. "It then uses continuous monitoring in real time to track each shipment against key route map milestones with pre-alerts, advance notifications and early exception warnings based on configuration options, alerting operators to any actual or potential delays." Andrew Whelan, vice president of commercial sector, Unisys Asia Pacific, said: "These two Digistics software-as-a-service solutions will provide MASkargo with additional agility, ability to generate new revenues and visibility to quickly take advantage of market opportunities such as quickly offering promotions via Digi-Portal to optimise air cargo capacity. "Using the Digi-IQ performance measurement system, advanced analytics will proactively identify early exception warnings so that MASkargo can take proactive measures to avoid service disruptions, to provide high service standards for its forwarder clients and the airlines it services as the Ground Handling Agent."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>a18cd6</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/tonnes-air-cargo-pass-through-fraport-speed-gate</url>
    <title>100,000 tonnes of cargo pass through Fraport AG's Speed Gate</title>
    <author>STAT Times</author>
    <published_time>2017-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Cargo News</topic>
      <topic>Aviation</topic>
      <topic>Logistics</topic>
      <topic>Supply Chain</topic>
      <topic>Shipping</topic>
      <topic>Air Freight</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Lufthansa Cargo has loaded the 100,000th tonne of cargo via Fraport AG's Speed Gate at Frankfurt Airport, on April 24, 2017. Lufthansa Cargo AG uses Speed Gate at CargoCity South, Europe's largest hub for global cargo logistics, since autumn 2014. Cargo is unloaded at four automated gates at the press of a button, security checked within the gates and subsequently brought directly to the aircraft.</p>
      <p>"With optional mobile add-ons, such as our 'Mobile Acceptance' and 'Customised Import' services, we are putting Speed Gate to the best possible use and offering our customers a service tailored to them at the Frankfurt hub. We collect the cargo from the customer, either loose or on pallets. As part of the cargo acceptance service, we also check the built-up pallets directly at the customer warehouse. With the import service, we offer our customers the option of having their cargo delivered directly from the aircraft to their warehouse via Speed Gate. This makes waiting times a thing of the past," said Board Member Operations Sören Stark, before ceremoniously pressing the button to send the 100,000th tonne of cargo airside through Speed Gate.</p>
      <p>"Our customers have responded very well to both service offerings: 81 percent of the cargo units built by our customers at CargoCity South, known as BUPs, were accepted via the mobile service in the latest quarter already."</p>
      <p>When Fraport AG opened Speed Gate almost four years ago at Frankfurt airport, the infrastructure was mainly aimed at cargo handlers without airside handling facilities.</p>
      <p>"In the meantime, we created an offering of benefit to many companies. With Speed Gate, we are helping to make the hub even faster and more agile for our cargo customers. We firmly expect Speed Gate to become a more important tool for other cargo companies and their customers as well," emphasised Anke Giesen, executive director operations at Fraport AG.</p>
      <p>Photo: L to R:  Sören Stark, Lufthansa Cargo AG and Anke Giesen, Fraport AG</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>10aed4</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/brussels-airport-starts-2020-with-a-reinforced-cargo-team/</url>
    <title>Brussels Airport starts 2020 with a reinforced cargo team</title>
    <author>Alex Brown</author>
    <published_time>2020-01-10T12:03:58+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics/>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>At the end of 2019 Brussels Airport decided to significantly expand and strengthen its cargo team. Cargo was already an import cornerstone in the strategy and development of the airport with a dedicated approach, but earlier in 2019, in line with the new business strategy in which cargo and logistics is 1 of the 4 central pillars, it was decided to centralise the entire responsibility of all activities in the cargo zone (operational, financial, commercial, real estate, …) within the cargo business unit. These activities will remain under the leadership of Steven Polmans, previously Head of Cargo, who at that time was appointed Director Cargo &amp; Logistics.</p>
      <p>Last months a new structure was drawn up to manage all existing and additional activities and as a result, the cargo team will be significantly expanded with new and adapted functions. In line with this, Nathan De Valck will as of beginning of this month, take up the new role of Head of Product and Network Development. He will report directly to the Director of Cargo &amp; Logistics and will be responsible with his team for all business development and key account activities for airlines, forwarders and shippers as well as the further development of the various specializations and products such as pharma, perishables, animal transport and e-commerce.</p>
      <p>In the coming months, the Cargo &amp; Logistics team will be further strengthened with, among others, a head of cargo real estate, business analyst, parc services manager and an operations manager. These reinforcements confirm the importance of cargo for the airport and the clear commitment to further develop Brussels Airport as a leading logistics platform in Europe.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>dcffd6</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/freight-forwarder/kerry-logistics-snaps-up-german-film-and-media-specialist/</url>
    <title>Kerry Logistics snaps up German film and media specialist</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time>2017-01-10T09:54:23+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>freight-forwarder</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic/>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Kerry Logistics Network, the Asia-based service provider, has further expanded its European operations by acquiring Germany's Multi Logistics, a specialist film and media logistics provider with 30 years' experience in the sector. The expansion will add four offices and bring in additional logistics expertise to Kerry Logistics' existing resources and network in Germany. Kerry Logistics will now operate seven offices in Germany, including its regional headquarters in Frankfurt as well as Bremen, Hamburg, Munich, and Berlin, each offering international freight forwarding (ocean/air/road), warehousing and distribution, and Customs brokerage. Besides its international freight forwarding operations, Multi Logistics' service portfolio includes door-to-door service, personal support service for film productions, security transport, storage of film copies, and handling of rental equipment, as well as Carnet A.T.A. preparation, and handling. Thomas Blank, managing director of Europe of Kerry Logistics, said: "The expansion is in line with our strategy to accelerate the business development of the European market." The move comes three weeks after Kerry Logistics' expansion in Spain with the takeover of the freight forwarding businesses of Bofill &amp; Arnan, a logistics and freight forwarding company with a focus on the China, Taiwan, and India trade lanes.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>6ed878</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/unilode-partners-with-nexxiot-to-digitise-uld-fleet-by-2021-air-cargo</url>
    <title>Unilode partners with Nexxiot to digitise ULD fleet by 2021</title>
    <author>STAT Times</author>
    <published_time>2019-08-19T20:00:00+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>aviation</topic>
      <topic>air freight</topic>
      <topic>ULDs</topic>
      <topic>Nexxiot</topic>
      <topic>Unilode Aviation Solutions</topic>
      <topic>Helmut Kaspers</topic>
      <topic>Benot Dumont</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Enabler of the digitised supply chain Nexxiot and Unilode Aviation Solutions have signed a contract to digitise the entire Unilode fleet within the next 18 months. By the beginning of 2021, all 1,25,000 ULDs supported by Unilode will be fitted with a digital twin.</p>
      <p>All Unilode Unit Load Device (ULDs) will be equipped with Bluetooth sensors, that will collect data which will then be processed, analysed and made available by Nexxiot for Unilode. This will enable continuous, automated tracking of ULDs both on the ground and in the air. Currently, around 10,000 ULDs are already equipped with the corresponding Bluetooth technology and can be activated digitally by Nexxiot.</p>
      <p>We're proud to be partner of @unilode now! Together we digitize the aviation industry &amp; enable continuous automated tracking of ULDs on the ground &amp; in the air.#iot #supplychainoptimization #aviation https://t.co/4WemHoSk4x</p>
      <p>"The strategic partnership with Unilode is an important step for us in scaling our business model. For the first time, we are now developing solutions to digitise the air freight market and make the handling of ULDs transparent worldwide. We achieve this by combining freight and movement data. Our extensive experience in the rail segment has helped us to master the problems in the air freight industry," said Helmut Kaspers, CEO, Nexxiot.</p>
      <p>Boarding ULDs digitally</p>
      <p>The first joint trials between the two companies have been running since September 2018. For the first time, Nexxiot is now working independently of its own sensors and will thus integrate external data on its platform.</p>
      <p>Welcoming the cooperation, Benoît Dumont, CEO of Unilode Aviation Solutions, said, "We are very diligent in selecting our partners and have high standards for the companies we cooperate with. After a long review, it turned out that Nexxiot is currently the only supplier worldwide with whom we can implement this kind of project in such a short time. That's why we've brought Nexxiot on board as a strategic partner and benefit from the company's vast expertise in the digitisation of large fleets."</p>
      <p>Next-gen ULDs come of age</p>
      <p>In addition to the digitisation project, Nexxiot has developed and currently maintains a neutral user interface for Unilode where customers can view the data of their ULDs and use various services such as ULD location, temperature, shock, light and humidity measurement, as well as inflight tracking. Based on the new partnership, the company will be able to offer spot leasing for load carriers in the future. Pooling of ULDs will also be simplified.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>6dadad</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/globalia-logistics-network-starts-accepting-membership-applications/</url>
    <title>Globalia Logistics Network starts accepting membership applications</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2016-09-15T08:41:00+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Forwarder News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Antonio Torres</topic>
      <topic>Conqueror Freight Network</topic>
      <topic>Globalia Logistics Network</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Applications for membership have begun being accepted for Globalia Logistics Network, which describes itself as "an exclusive network accepting only the highest calibre freight forwarders in each key air/seaport worldwide".</p>
      <p>Globalia applicants will undergo a tough selection process including external auditing and those accepted will enjoy the first six months free. The new network was founded by Antonio Torres, who launched Conqueror Freight Network seven years ago.</p>
      <p>Torres says: "Because of the unique nature of Conqueror, the amount of interest in membership is still unprecedented and in truth, there is simply not enough room to accommodate every qualifying company, so, I felt it was right to give more agents the opportunity to enjoy the same benefits through a new network."</p>
      <p>He adds: "Some might say that what we are launching is not new, and they would be right. We are offering the same opportunities as Conqueror but for a new group of first class companies, allowing them to work with the same calibre of agents as themselves worldwide."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>ec07cc</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/delhi-indira-ghandi-international-airport-amsterdam-airport-schiphol-to-open-trade-lane/</url>
    <title>Delhi  Indira Ghandi International Airport , Amsterdam Airport Schiphol to open trade lane</title>
    <author>acweek</author>
    <published_time>2015-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Airport News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics/>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Delhi Indira Ghandi International Airport has signed a memorandum of understanding (MoU) with Amsterdam Airport Schiphol to develop an airfreight trade lane.</p>
      <p>The MoU will see both airports collaborate on and promote airfreight between them. The collaboration includes business promotion, product development, knowledge sharing, training, performance benchmarking and regulatory agency cooperation. Delhi International Airport chief executive officer, Prabhakara Rao, says: "We aim to make Indian trade much more competitive in the global market." He adds it wants to bring its operations up to global standards.</p>
      <p>Schiphol senior vice president cargo, Enno Osinga, tells Air Cargo Week Amsterdam can be a gateway for Indian goods destined for Europe, as well as the US, Africa and Latin America. "We have been focusing on India for the last five years. Our first focus was on the Mumbai area and the logical next step is Delhi, which has a large pharma production market. Delhi is the next step rather than the beginning."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>4cfac2</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/freight-forwarder/kerry-adds-robots-to-hong-kong-warehouse/</url>
    <title>Kerry adds robots to Hong Kong warehouse</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time>2015-09-14T10:23:51+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>freight-forwarder</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic/>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Kerry Logistics has introduced six robotic butlers at its flagship facility in Hong Kong to speed up the picking process in line with trends in e-commerce.</p>
      <p> </p>
      <p>The robots operate 24/7 and can pick 280 items per hour compared to 50 items normally, and the pick rate is four times faster.</p>
      <p> </p>
      <p>Kerry said this made ideal for retail brands which sell a wide variety of consumer products with potentially expanding e-commerce business as speed-to-market was key to their success.</p>
      <p> </p>
      <p>Real time sales orders are transmitted from retailers and e-commerce providers to Kerry's warehouse management system and then to the robotic butlers.</p>
      <p> </p>
      <p>The system indicates the right items to be picked for shipments using a simple lighting system in which every item is tracked via barcodes.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>68ed11</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/ceva-opens-multi-user-warehouse-malaysia/</url>
    <title>CEVA opens new multi-user warehouse in Malaysia</title>
    <author>james.graham@azurainternational.com</author>
    <published_time>2015-11-25T12:09:22+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Asia News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Asia Pacific freight</topic>
      <topic>Asian freight forwarders</topic>
      <topic>CEVA Logistics</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>CEVA Logistics has opened Central Distribution Center (CDC) 2 in Shah Alam, Malaysia, 16 miles from Kuala Lumpur.</p>
      <p>Constructed on the same site as CEVA's CDC1 at Bukit Jelutong, Shah Alam, CDC2 gives it 33,000 square metres of additional warehousing and office space.</p>
      <p>The combined warehouse footprint of the new CDC2 and the existing CDC1 now totals approximately 67,000 square metres making it the largest site in CEVA's South East Asia (SEA) cluster, which comprises Singapore, Malaysia and Indonesia.</p>
      <p>CEVA's facility at Bukit Jelutong is in a strategic industrial area with excellent logistics infrastructure, connected to a highly-developed road network and an expanding rapid transit system, and located close to Malaysia's main port in Klang.</p>
      <p>The company says having two warehouse facilities on one site enables it to optimise the deployment of resources and equipment, for customers' benefit.</p>
      <p>The new, enlarged facility strengthens CEVA's capabilities to offer fully integrated logistics and supply chain solutions to new and existing customers in Malaysia.</p>
      <p>CEVA's chief executive officer, Xavier Urbain says: "Malaysia is one of our key markets in the Asia region. The country has excellent connectivity both domestically and internationally.</p>
      <p>"It is also in a region where a strong middle class is emerging to drive Asian consumption upwards, positively influencing trade and supply chain activities across various sectors. All these factors make Malaysia a strategic market for CEVA to invest in, allowing us to enhance the scope and quality of our services for customers."</p>
      <p>The new CDC2 is a double story warehouse facility with direct truck access to 40 loading docks on both levels. It is the first design of its type to be approved in Malaysia, as part of a drive to maximise the productivity of land used for warehousing space, thus catering to the growing demand for contract logistics.</p>
      <p>The facility is purpose-built, and designed to provide both ambient and temperature-controlled storage.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>99824e</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/oman-picks-champ-for-air-cargo-software-solutions/</url>
    <title>Oman picks CHAMP for air cargo software solutions</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-02-17T12:08:34+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>CHAMP</topic>
      <topic>CHAMP Cargosystems</topic>
      <topic>Oman Air</topic>
      <topic>Oman Air Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Oman Air Cargo has awarded CHAMP a five-year contract for its suite of e-cargo solutions.</p>
      <p>Seeking solutions for the next step of its digital transformation, Oman Air Cargo issued a request for proposals for cargo IT solutions.</p>
      <p>Oman Air not only decided to continue using Traxon cargoHUB and Traxon Global Customs, but also signed for two new solutions.</p>
      <p>"The solutions speak for themselves," said Mohammed Al Musafir, senior vice president – commercial cargo at Oman Air. "This is one more step towards our goal of 100% digitisation, offering information and transparency to our valued customers"</p>
      <p>"CHAMP is proud to win these contracts for Oman Air Cargo," added Nicholas Xenocostas, vice president commercial and customer Engagement. "Having a long-standing relationship, we are thrilled to have had the opportunity to compete in an open market and continue supporting Oman Air Cargo in their digital transformation while adding additional value to their business."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>d6e190</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/unilode-accelerate-digital-transformation-ulds/</url>
    <title>Unilode to accelerate digital transformation for ULDs</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2018-03-14T16:46:18+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Airfreight Industry Supplier News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Adam Crossno</topic>
      <topic>Benoit Dumont</topic>
      <topic>Bluetooth tracking</topic>
      <topic>OnAsset Intelligence</topic>
      <topic>ULD</topic>
      <topic>Unilode Aviation Solutions</topic>
      <topic>Unit load device</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Unilode Aviation Solutions plans to accelerate digital transformation in unit load device (ULD) management with Bluetooth tracking.</p>
      <p>The tracking solution is based on a Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE) tag fully embedded into the structure of the ULDs, which is supported by a global interoperable reader infrastructure.</p>
      <p>To implement the programme, Unilode has teamed up with technology provider OnAsset Intelligence and a ULD manufacturer.</p>
      <p>Customers including Cathay Pacific, Air Canada, Cargolux and AirBridgeCargo are among the airlines involved in the digitisation programme, which is being rolled out this year, along with several shippers.</p>
      <p>Unilode chief executive officer (CEO), Benoit Dumont says: "Unilode Aviation Solutions has decided to accelerate the use of modern technology in its ULD management solutions. Since winning the inaugural IATA Air Cargo Innovation Award in 2015 we have been working closely with our customers to enhance our digital tracking technology with user input across the end-to-end value chain.</p>
      <p>He adds: "Unilode does not intend to lock itself, its customers and industry partners into proprietary technologies, and therefore has decided to make public all APIs necessary to capture information from our digitally enabled platforms. This approach greatly enhances interoperability and flexibility, which is what the industry and our customers are looking for."</p>
      <p>OnAsset Intelligence CEO, Adam Crossno says: "Together with Unilode we have been focusing on making sure the technology is safe, compliant, fit for purpose and technically sound. Our common vision is that this technology should be accessible for all stakeholders in the value chain, so intelligent ULDs can be leveraged by airlines, ground handlers, freight forwarders and shippers.</p>
      <p>"This is extremely important because quite often the tracking challenges arise when shipments leave their expected route and are not found where they are expected to be."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>55ee96</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/dascher-eyes-logistics-innovation-new-university-partnership/</url>
    <title>Dachser eyes logistics innovation with new university partnership</title>
    <author>Alexander Whiteman</author>
    <published_time>2017-10-20T13:08:34+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Dachser</topic>
      <topic>DHL</topic>
      <topic>innovation</topic>
      <topic>Tomorrow's World</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Dachser has entered into a partnership with German research society the Fraunhofer Institute for Material Flow and Logistics to develop innovative solutions.</p>
      <p>Its employees will work alongside Fraunhofer researchers at the newly created Dachser Enterprise Lab in Dortmund.</p>
      <p>Dachser chief executive Bernhard Simon said collaboration with universities and other partners had "for many years been a mainstay" of the company's corporate strategy.</p>
      <p>He added: "The Dachser Enterprise Lab adds key competencies to our internal research and development capacity, and gives us flexible access to specialists.</p>
      <p>"Fraunhofer IML possesses outstanding expertise, state-of-the-art laboratories and a wide range of motivated and creative researchers. When coupled with the longstanding experience of Dachser's logistics experts, we believe this will further accelerate the company's rate of innovation."</p>
      <p>Director for corporate solutions, research and development Stefan Hohm said there were multiple advantages from working with academics, foremost of which was the ability to "flexibly boost" Dachser's access to knowledge and research and development resources.</p>
      <p>"Bringing the business knowhow of logistics experts and the scientific knowledge of Fraunhofer IML together creates a win-win situation for both partners."</p>
      <p>Describing Fraunhofer as "very much practice-oriented" in its research, he added it possesses "vast" experience in partnering with companies.</p>
      <p>Managing director of Fraunhofer Michael ten Hompel said Enterprise Labs had been set up to transfer research results over to products or business models as quickly as possible.</p>
      <p>"It puts us in a position where we can flexibly and speedily put new technologies, trends, or business strategies into practice and efficiently determine our priorities."</p>
      <p>Mr Hohm told The Loadstar any developments would be specifically for use by Dachser.</p>
      <p>"The developments are meant to be specifically for across-the-board deployment in the Dachser Road Logistics and Air &amp; Sea Logistics networks."</p>
      <p>The decision to keep developments in-house contrasts with Deutsche Post-DHL's innovation centre in Bonn, which is expanding production to cater for third-party sales.</p>
      <p>This month, DHL announced it was looking to roll out 20,000 of its Street Scooter e-vehicles a year, adding an additional 78,000sq metre warehouse in Duren to meet demand.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>80b876</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/bgl-finds-scope-for-success-with-api-launch/</url>
    <title>BGL finds scope for success with API launch</title>
    <author>James Graham</author>
    <published_time>2019-11-21T11:35:05+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>IT News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>AFKLM</topic>
      <topic>API</topic>
      <topic>Application programming interface</topic>
      <topic>Fast Forward Freight (FFF)</topic>
      <topic>Riege Software</topic>
      <topic>Riege Software. Air France KLM Martinair</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Dutch independent third-party logistics service provider Best Global Logistics (BGL), a customer of Riege Software, has utilised the newly developed direct airline booking API (Application Programming Interface). The API is available for Air France KLM Martinair Cargo bookings, enabling seamless operations in conjunction with Riege's forwarding software Scope as an integrated solution. Providing the benefits of direct booking while at the same time avoiding the disadvantage of system changes, the direct airline booking API marks another milestone in Riege's 'One System. One Record' approach to push Scope as the digital standard in logistics.</p>
      <p>BGL was the first Riege customer to seek integration and will be the first one to use it. After the pilot period, Amsterdam-based Fast Forward Freight (FFF) will follow. Both BGL and FFF have invested in the development of the API together with Riege, which allowed the completion in the shortest period of time possible.</p>
      <p>"It was our intention to benefit from this solution, the sooner the better, but we also had the ambition to be the first ones owning this API as an early adopter as well as a driver of future- oriented technology," said Michel Loots, CEO at BGL.</p>
      <p>With the new API Scope, users can directly send a booking request to Air France KLM Martinair Cargo, then receive flights and prices in real time and book the required flight directly without separate booking via web portals or phone and always with the latest dynamic prices at hand.</p>
      <p>"Technically, it is all about a real-time match between capacity and demand. In practice, it is about saving time and money by avoiding phone calls and system changes. Literally a significant win for us and our customers which simultaneously makes us stronger in a very competitive market. The money we invested together with FFF is well spent, and the ROI is calculated for within one year," said Loots focussing the economic aspect. "You rarely find companies co-investing in technological progress these days. With partners like BGL and FFF, Riege is blessed in the best meaning of the word. Of course, it is not limited to Air France KLM Martinair Cargo. All airlines are most welcome to join this community, gaining new customers with impressive volumes of freight," said Henk Boorsma, managing director and co-owner of Riege Software in the Netherlands.</p>
      <p>"I am glad and honoured to represent a company which not only can trust in the capabilities and loyalty of its employees, but also in the allegiance of its customers many of whom have proven more than once that real partnership goes beyond purely factual business relationships. That's priceless. I wish to express my thankfulness specifically to Michel Loots of BGL and Marc Terpstra of FFF. When we say that Scope is the future of digital logistics, guys like them are the driving force," said Dr. Tobias Riege, CEO of Riege Software.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>a76eda</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/kerry-logistics-expands-europe-acquiring-multi-logistics/</url>
    <title>Kerry Logistics expands in Europe by acquiring Multi Logistics</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2017-01-10T09:52:45+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Asia News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Berlin</topic>
      <topic>Bofill &amp; Arnan</topic>
      <topic>Bremen</topic>
      <topic>Frankfurt</topic>
      <topic>Germany</topic>
      <topic>Hamburg</topic>
      <topic>Kerry Logistics</topic>
      <topic>Multi Logistics</topic>
      <topic>Munich</topic>
      <topic>Thomas Blank</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Kerry Logistics has expanded its European operations through the acquisition of Multi Logistics, a specialist in film and media logistics.</p>
      <p>The acquisition will add four offices to Kerry's German network, bringing the total to seven, including its regional headquarters in Frankfurt as well as Bremen, Hamburg, Munich and Berlin.</p>
      <p>Each office offers local and multinational customers international freight forwarding, warehousing and distribution, customs brokerage and supply chain services.</p>
      <p>Kerry Logistics managing director of Europe, Thomas Blank says: "The expansion is in line with our strategy to accelerate the business development of the European market, and we are pleased to be able to provide our clients with enhanced network coverage, additional service offerings across Europe, and a further optimised local customer service in Germany."</p>
      <p>In addition to freight forwarding, Multi Logistics' service portfolio includes door-to-door service, personal support service for film productions, security transport, storage of film copies, and handling of rental equipment, as well as Carnet A.T.A. preparation, and handling."</p>
      <p>The move comes three weeks after Kerry Logistics' expansion in Spain with the takeover of the freight forwarding businesses of Bofill &amp; Arnan, logistics and freight forwarding company with a focus on the China, Taiwan, and India trade lanes.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>377182</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/freight-forwarder/wca-members-to-be-given-free-access-to-wins-e-awb-platform/</url>
    <title>WCA members to be given free access to WIN's e-AWB platform</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time>2016-03-14T15:56:32+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>freight-forwarder</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic/>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Independent forwarder members of the WCA network will all have free access to WIN's electronic air waybill (e-AWB) platform for the remainder of this year, delegates at the WCA's annual conference 2016 have heard. The WIN platform, designed specifically for independent cargo agents and which connects to over 90 airlines, will now allow WCA members to submit any International Air Transport Association (IATA) Resolution 672 (paperless) e-AWB free of charge, as well as to make electronic bookings and receive tracking alerts. "We are at a tipping point, with the level of e-AWB adoption in the industry approaching the halfway mark," said WIN's managing director, John DeBenedette. "Independents can act now to gain the same level of efficiencies already enjoyed by multinational forwarders and tap into the growing trend of airport fast lanes for cargo tendered with electronic data in advance." WCA's CEO, Dan March, added: "WCA takes pride in our long history as an innovative business development platform helping independent forwarders compete on a level playing field with their larger rivals. For our members, going electronic is not just about eliminating paper or helping airlines increase their efficiency which is all well and good, but equally important it's about benefiting from the real-time shipment visibility, system integration, and member collaboration features that we've also built into WIN." And Glyn Hughes, IATA's global head of cargo congratulated WCA's leadership for supporting the air cargo industry's drive to go paperless. "Air cargo needs to upgrade its value proposition as shipper expectations become ever more demanding and paper-based solutions just can't deliver the quality, transparency and predictability that is required," he declared.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>3b39e8</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/sharjah-aviation-services-goes-live-with-air-cargo-flash</url>
    <title>Sharjah Aviation Services goes live with Cargo Flash</title>
    <author>STAT Times</author>
    <published_time>2017-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>AirCargo</topic>
      <topic>Aviation</topic>
      <topic>Logistics</topic>
      <topic>Freight</topic>
      <topic>SupplyChain</topic>
      <topic>Shipping</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Sharjah Airport's sole ground handling agent, Sharjah Aviation Services (SAS) went live with a new- generation cargo management system that aims to provide real time shipment information and dramatically improve cargo operations at the UAE airport.</p>
      <p>The state-of- the-art warehouse and cargo management suite 'Cargo Flash nGen CMS' from Cargo Flash Infotech covers business areas including complete Landside operations for Export and Import, Warehouse Management, ULD management, Roster management, Workflow management, EDI management, all landside, warehouse and airside charges, SLA and contract management. As well as supporting management and operations teams in running daily operations, it also aims to provide business intelligence and digital transparency to bring Sharjah and its air freight community closer to reaching its e-freight and operational quality goals.</p>
      <p>Cargo Flash, established in 2001 is an emerging IT service provider based in Gurgaon, empowering the aviation and logistics industry with IT solutions.</p>
      <p>The objective of the warehouse handling system is to ensure smooth handling and process of daily operations for complete warehouse management.</p>
      <p>Photo: Gautam Mandal, Cargo Flash</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>a33d76</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/major-shippers-quick-to-form-a-link-with-new-ibm-blockchain-solution/</url>
    <title>Major shippers quick to form a link with new IBM blockchain solution</title>
    <author>Alexander Whiteman</author>
    <published_time>2019-08-05T13:22:57+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>blockchain</topic>
      <topic>IBM</topic>
      <topic>Nokia</topic>
      <topic>TradeLens</topic>
      <topic>Trust Your Supplier</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>IBM has launched a new blockchain solution, aimed at improving supplier validation, onboarding and life cycle information management.</p>
      <p>Together with Chainyard, the firm announced the launch of Trust Your Supplier (TYS) with news that some major shippers, including GlaxoSmithKline, Lenovo, and Vodafone, have already signed up to it.</p>
      <p>Chief supply chain officer for Lenovo's Data Centre Group Renee Ure said the new platform could prove "transformative".</p>
      <p>"Blockchain has the ability to completely transform how companies onboard and manage their supplier network. Through TYS, both buyers and suppliers will the see the procurement benefits of blockchain through reductions in cost, complexity and speed."</p>
      <p>TYS creates a 'digital passport' for supplier identity on the blockchain network that allows suppliers to share information with any permitted buyer on the network.</p>
      <p>By using blockchain, data sharing is permission-based, which IBM said "should" help reduce the time and cost associated with qualifying, validating and managing new suppliers.</p>
      <p>"Traditional methods of managing suppliers often involve cumbersome manual processes, which make it difficult to verify identities and track," it said. "By using a decentralised approach and an immutable blockchain audit trail, TYS is designed to eliminate manual time-consuming processes and help reduce risks of fraud and errors."</p>
      <p>Research firm Gartner recently claimed blockchain would track $2trn worth of goods a year by 2023, with IBM keen to onboard 4,000 of its own suppliers this year.</p>
      <p>Third-party validators, such as Dun &amp; Bradstreet, Ecovadis and RapidRatings provide outside verification or audit capabilities directly on the network.</p>
      <p>Vice president of procurement at Nokia, which has also signed up to TYS, Sanjay Mehta said: "This blockchain initiative represents a great opportunity for us. Using the latest technology to address a classical challenge will be of benefit for everyone, and further increase the speed of using innovative solutions."</p>
      <p>This is not the IT giant's first venture in supply chain blockchain technology, having jointly launched its TradeLens platform some 20 months ago with Maersk. Following a difficult start, when many questioned whether other carriers would be keen to work alongside a competitor, the platform has now got some pace behind it.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>bbdf08</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/unilode-to-install-digital-bluetooth-tags-in-pallets-air-cargo</url>
    <title>Unilode to install digital Bluetooth tags in pallets</title>
    <author>STAT Times</author>
    <published_time>2019-03-12T11:41:00+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>unilode ULDs</topic>
      <topic>Bluetooth ULDs</topic>
      <topic>ULD management</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Unilode Aviation Solutions, Safran and OnAsset Intelligence have completed their joint development project to develop Bluetooth digital pallet tags, for the digital enablement of aviation pallets.</p>
      <p>A statement in its official release said that its been less than a year ago that the parties collaborated to develop a unique design for a Bluetooth 5 digital tag.</p>
      <p>These tags can seamlessly be fitted into a pallet to prevent mishandling and stacking problems that may occur with bolt-on solutions positioned externally.</p>
      <p>Safran's engineering team designed a complementary corner piece solution to house the antenna of the tag in the pallet corner and the rest of OnAsset's innovative digital device will be entirely integrated inside the edge rail of the pallet, informs the ULD management solutions provider.</p>
      <p>The Switzerland-based company informs through a statement: "Unilode's new Safran pallets will be delivered with the integrated corner piece while existing units will be retrofitted to enable the provision of data on location and shock, which is important especially for time-critical cargo."</p>
      <p>The company added: "The technology has been approved for in-flight use. Unilode will start rolling out its digitally enabled ULDs along with the global reader infrastructure to set its digital transformation programme in motion."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>322b68</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/innovative-it-system-goes-live-at-hamburg-airport-cargo-center-air-cargo</url>
    <title>Innovative IT system goes live at Hamburg Airport Cargo Center</title>
    <author>STAT Times</author>
    <published_time>2019-10-31T10:30:00+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>hamburg airport</topic>
      <topic>DAKOSY systems</topic>
      <topic>DAKOSY software</topic>
      <topic>air cargo handling</topic>
      <topic>cargo center hamburg</topic>
      <topic>hamburg airport cargo center</topic>
      <topic>air freight market</topic>
      <topic>air freight goods</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>The new FAIR@Link portal, after a six-month test phase, goes into full operation for digitally-supported air cargo handling at Hamburg Airport Cargo Center.</p>
      <p>This new portal ensures more sustainability and transparency as well as faster and more efficient processes for the companies involved in air freight handling.</p>
      <p>The platform was developed by software firm DAKOSY, which also operates the Port Community System for the Port of Hamburg and the Cargo Community System for Frankfurt Airport.</p>
      <p>In addition to Hamburg Airport and DAKOSY, the pilot participants included the forwarders CROSS FREIGHT, Delta-Stallion, a.hartrodt and SABLE, the handling agents LUG and Swissport, the Hamburg Airport Customs Office and the Hamburg Forwarding Agents Association (VHSp).</p>
      <p>The pilot project started at Hamburg Airport Cargo Center on May 6, 2019.</p>
      <p>Hamburg Airport begins using DAKOSY air cargo community system</p>
      <p>All participants have already noticed clear improvements in their processes during the pilot phase.</p>
      <p>Hamburg Airport highlights the advantage of implementation of this platform. Out of many, one is that forwarders can book time slots for deliveries. This results in shorter waiting and handling times, more transparency along the transport chain and improved documentation for handling agents, who no longer need to re-enter duplicate data - thus avoiding mistakes and saving time.</p>
      <p>Hamburg Airport Cargo Center completes one year of operations</p>
      <p>Introducing this system brings in a major advantage, that is the system prepares export Customs declarations and then automatically submit the electronic forms to Customs upon entry to the Hamburg Airport Customs Office geofence area.</p>
      <p>Slot booking makes planning easier</p>
      <p>Jens Sorgenfrei, managing director of CROSS FREIGHT Internationale Speditionsges. mbH, sums up the advantages for freight forwarders: "Transports pre-registered via FAIR@Link are handled preferentially by the handling agents at the airport. The slot bookings save us several hours every day. Processes are easier to plan. All in all, we benefit in Customs and door clearances."</p>
      <p>Dr. Jürgen Vogt, managing director of LUG, also sees it as positive from the viewpoint of handling agents: "With slot booking, our EDP system receives all information before the arrival of the goods. The data does not have to be entered again when the document is received. This enables us to save a lot of time and speed up the receiving process. With FAIR@Link, we gain more transparency into all processes and can better manage our capacities with regard to door and personnel availability."</p>
      <p>Ulrich Wrage, CEO of DAKOSY said: "Through connectivity and intelligent process support, FAIR@Link can optimize the physical processes between companies and achieve significantly faster and more transparent processing. In addition, the platform promotes ecological concerns, as optimized traffic management and reduced check-in and waiting times lead to CO2 savings. And it saves paper, too."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>8d5722</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/delmotte-to-lead-heppners-overseas-network/</url>
    <title>Delmotte to lead Heppner's overseas network</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2019-10-21T09:55:40+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Europe News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>France</topic>
      <topic>Heppner</topic>
      <topic>Lille</topic>
      <topic>Sebastien Delmotte</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>French transport and logistics company Heppner has picked Sebastien Delmotte as overseas network director.</p>
      <p>In his role, Delmotte will be in charge of relations with all partners, optimising the network's global coverage and identifying trade synergies for products and procurement.</p>
      <p>The overseas service covers air freight, sea freight and customs, based on a network of independent partners in their markets.</p>
      <p>Delmotte began his career in 1996 working for various freight forwarders, and joined Heppner in 2013 as head of overseas, based in Lille, France.</p>
      <p>Commenting on his new role, Delmotte says: "International trade is in Heppner's DNA. The group intends to step up its expansion in France and internationally through the Overseas network by rolling out exceptional global coverage. We rely on selected partners who share our vision of the business: operational excellence and customer service."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>36aec7</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/flexport-adopts-champs-cuttingedge-datainterchange-format-cargojson</url>
    <title>Flexport adopts CHAMP's cutting-edge data-interchange format cargoJSON</title>
    <author>STAT Times</author>
    <published_time>2017-12-11T16:24:00+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Flexport</topic>
      <topic>CHAMP</topic>
      <topic>cargoJSON</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>California-based freight forwarding and customs brokerage company Flexport has recently integrated Luxembourg-based CHAMP Cargosystems's messaging platform—Traxon cargoHUB as well as its new cargoJSON data-interchange format.</p>
      <p>According to reports, cargoJSON is a language-independent data format which CHAMP has defined for air cargo messaging.</p>
      <p>cargoJSON was recently added to Traxon cargoHUB, which is fully interoperable with the existing IATA cargoIMP and IATA cargoXML formats. Flexport is CHAMP's first customer to have implemented it.</p>
      <p>"CHAMP and its partners are always in a pursuit to seek innovative and effective ways to create efficiencies and drive rapid adoption of digitization in the industry," said Laurent Jossa, head of sales- distribution services of CHAMP Cargosystems.</p>
      <p>"Flexport has been agile in implementing the services and the new messaging format and CHAMP has been quick to meet this need," he said.</p>
      <p>"We are constantly seeking new partners to get better information for our clients. We are glad to find CHAMP, which offers a modern cargoJSON API that makes it easy for our team to seamlessly integrate their information into our product.," said Phoebe Rockwood, air freight product manager of Flexport.</p>
      <p>"CHAMP has made this possible with its large community reach, comprehensive solution and related services, and state-of the-art communication technology," he said.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>79b79f</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/airbase-gse-scoops-iag-cargo-uld-repair-deal/</url>
    <title>Airbase GSE scoops IAG Cargo ULD repair deal</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2019-10-16T12:35:04+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>IAG Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>IAG Cargo has awarded its ULD repair and maintenance contract to Airbase GSE.</p>
      <p>The transition from the previous supplier was managed by IAG Cargo and Airbase GSE management teams working closely together to ensure a "seamless transition for IAG Cargo operations".</p>
      <p>Airbase GSE has repaired in excess of 30,000 ULDs for IAG Cargo since the contract started. It provides IAG Cargo customers with an average turnaround time of less than 20 minutes.</p>
      <p>The contract operates out of a 81,000 sq ft secure unit, including 6 loading docks, located under 2 miles from Heathrow Airport.</p>
      <p>Airbase GSE chief executive Nicholas Payne said: "We are really pleased with IAG Cargo's decision and are honoured to be working with and supporting at this exciting time of growth and change. We will strive to deliver the highest level of safety and industry practices while remaining scalable for IAG Cargo's future growth."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>566444</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/sats-and-psa-to-develop-singapores-air-sea-links/</url>
    <title>SATS and PSA to develop Singapore's air-sea links</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2019-05-13T09:38:17+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Asia News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Alex Hungate</topic>
      <topic>CALISTA</topic>
      <topic>COSYS+</topic>
      <topic>PSA International</topic>
      <topic>SATS</topic>
      <topic>Tan Chong Meng</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>PSA International and SATS have signed a memorandum of understanding to establish sea-air connectivity to promote Singapore as a key multimodal transport hub.</p>
      <p>Combining air and sea connections, the partnership strengthens Singapore's position as a global transhipment hub for air and sea cargo.</p>
      <p>The freight industry, including small and medium sized enterprises stand to benefit from improved multimodal linkages and transit systems for better supply chain efficiency, optimised transport costs, and faster delivery.</p>
      <p>The two companies will collaborate on a wide range of cross-industry initiatives, particularly in the perishables, electronics and e-commerce sectors.</p>
      <p>From yard-to-port data linkages and network extensions between both companies to enhance track-and-trace capabilities, the partnership will facilitate data transparency and ease of shipment movement within free-trade zones.</p>
      <p>SATS and PSA will also integrate their systems to aid regulatory compliance and build data analytics capabilities.</p>
      <p>COSYS+, a cargo terminal handling and management system operated by SATS will be linked with CALISTA, the global supply chain platform developed by PSA's subsidiary GeTS Asia to provide real-time updates and greater visibility for shipments.</p>
      <p>Alex Hungate, president and CEO of SATS says: "When SATS became the world's first ground handler to provide multimodal meat transhipment services between New Zealand and the EU, we demonstrated that multimodal connectivity can attract higher trade flows. Today, we hope our cross-industry initiatives with PSA will now enable the whole industry to market efficient multimodal solutions globally, through Singapore."</p>
      <p>Tan Chong Meng, group CEO of PSA International says: "Shippers are increasingly seeking innovative multimodal solutions for their cargo to reach their preferred markets competitively. This partnership with SATS will enhance Singapore's ability to offer unique air-sea multimodal connectivity to fulfil these demands."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>e0b985</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/turhan-ozen-of-turkish-airlines-becomes-the-latest-member-to-join-tiaca-board-air-cargo</url>
    <title>Turhan Ozen of Turkish Airlines becomes the latest member to join TIACA Board</title>
    <author>STAT Times</author>
    <published_time>2019-04-30T10:53:00+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>TIACA air cargo</topic>
      <topic>Turkish airlines</topic>
      <topic>Turhan Ozen</topic>
      <topic>Sebastiaan Scholte</topic>
      <topic>Ataturk Airport</topic>
      <topic>TIACA Board</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Turhan Ozen, chief cargo officer of Turkish Airlines, has been elected to the Board of The International Air Cargo Association (TIACA).</p>
      <p>He possesses extensive knowledge of the territories surrounding Turkey, as it has overseen business development in the Balkans, Middle East, and African regions.</p>
      <p>"Turkey is set to become a major aviation transport hub between Europe and Asia, with the opening of new airport," said Sebastiaan Scholte, chairman of TIACA and chief executive officer of Jan de Rijk Logistics.</p>
      <p>"Because Turhan will be present on the ground as this major project works towards completion, his insight will prove invaluable to the TIACA Board and its members."</p>
      <p>Earlier this month Turkish Airlines moved all operations from Ataturk Airport to the new Istanbul Airport. The new airport, due for completion in 2027, will be the busiest hub in the world, with six runways boosting capacity for cargo.</p>
      <p>Ozen is one of several new members recruited to join the TIACA board as part of an ongoing strategy launched in 2018 to focus more on members and content.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>f53053</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/unilode-wins-iata-air-cargo-innovation-award-2019/</url>
    <title>Unilode wins IATA Air Cargo Innovation Award 2019</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2019-03-20T09:43:38+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Airfreight Industry Supplier News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Benoit Dumont</topic>
      <topic>Glyn Hughes</topic>
      <topic>IATA</topic>
      <topic>IATA Air Cargo Innovation Award 2019</topic>
      <topic>IATA World Cargo Symposium 2019</topic>
      <topic>International Air Transport Association</topic>
      <topic>Unilode Aviation Solutions</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Unilode Aviation Solutions has won the IATA Air Cargo Innovation Award 2019 for its Bluetooth-based tracking system for unit load devices.</p>
      <p>The concept allows customers to use the ULD as a proxy for air cargo located inside to track location and transmit status updates on the temperature, light and shock exposure and humidity.</p>
      <p>Explaining that time and temperature sensitive products are the biggest areas of growth in air cargo, Glyn Hughes, global head of cargo at IATA says: "Customers for these products want to know where these items are, and their condition, at any time during their transport. Unilode's tracking innovation will make this a reality. I congratulate the company on their achievement and use of data to drive improvements in operational quality."</p>
      <p>Benoît Dumont, CEO of Unilode says the company is very proud to have won the award, saying: "Unilode's aim is to deliver enhanced value to various stakeholders including airlines, ground handlers, shippers and freight forwarders to solve common issues relating to ULDs and cargo, and is looking forward to continuing the development and roll-out of its award-winning digitalisation programme."</p>
      <p>The award was presented at the 13th World Cargo Symposium in Singapore, with an independent jury including experts, academics and CEOs evaluating 56 entries from across the industry.</p>
      <p>Projects were evaluated based on the idea, its potential to create value and likelihood of achieving success.</p>
      <p>Three companies were shortlisted to present their projects to over 500 audience members during the WCS closing plenary who cast their vote, with Unilode receiving $20,000 to develop the idea.</p>
      <p>Hughes says: "To attract demand in new market segments, the air cargo industry must improve its value proposition. Innovation holds the key to industry development, sustainability and success and we are committed to help unlock its potential. It's important to recognise the individuals and companies that are driving change."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>eb056e</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/champ-cargosystems-joins-air-cargo-belgium/</url>
    <title>CHAMP Cargosystems joins Air Cargo Belgium</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2018-03-13T09:20:22+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Association News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Cargo Belgium</topic>
      <topic>Arnaud Lambert</topic>
      <topic>CHAMP Cargosystems</topic>
      <topic>Information technology</topic>
      <topic>IT</topic>
      <topic>Steven Polmans</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>CHAMP Cargosystems has joined the Air Cargo Belgium community to share its insights in the IT sector and collaborate more closely with members.</p>
      <p>Air Cargo Belgium sets out strategic and ambitious goals for the development of air cargo on behalf of supply chain stakeholders.</p>
      <p>The community of over 100 air cargo organisations implements procedures for improved operations and takes the lead in projects by having contact with all stakeholders and government agencies to address topics of common interest.</p>
      <p>CHAMP Cargosystems chief executive officer, Arnaud Lambert says: "CHAMP is right at home in an organisation like Air Cargo Belgium. The wider organisation is filled with expertise and knowledge throughout the entire supply chain, with the common driver of cooperation, innovation, and shared success. We look forward to sharing these ideals with our new partners."</p>
      <p>Air Cargo Belgium chairman, Steven Polmans adds: "As a well-respected member of the industry, the community has much to benefit from its knowledge and leadership in air cargo supply chain IT. The biggest progress and change in our industry in the years to come will be in the area of IT and digitisation, I am sure CHAMP can help us as a community to take the lead in this change and innovation."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>a78f07</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/ifln-group-launches-ifln-global-projects-network/</url>
    <title>IFLN Group launches new IFLN Global Projects network</title>
    <author>james.graham@azurainternational.com</author>
    <published_time>2017-09-15T09:55:49+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Forwarder News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>cargo agents network</topic>
      <topic>freight forwarders</topic>
      <topic>Houston</topic>
      <topic>logistics</topic>
      <topic>network</topic>
      <topic>North America</topic>
      <topic>project forwarding</topic>
      <topic>The International Freight Logistics Network (IFLN)</topic>
      <topic>US</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>The International Freight Logistics Network (IFLN) – a global organization of freight forwarders and logistics companies headquartered in Houston – has launched a new IFLN Global Projects network.</p>
      <p>IFLN president, Michel Vanlerberghe says only cargo agents with experience and a high degree of capability in the field of project forwarding will form part of the rapidly expanding group, adding: "We want to be the new force in the world of project logistics management."</p>
      <p>Vanlerberghe explains the thinking behind the decision to establish a network dedicated to project forwarding. "First, the decision was driven by IFLN's desire to develop and to grow; and one way of doing this is to offer different specialisations that the market requires."</p>
      <p>He adds: "Second, we knew from talking to our members that a large number of them specialize in project forwarding – far more so than just handling an occasional outsize or heavy load.</p>
      <p>"Then, we discussed the option of launching a network dedicated to this market and assessed what the members would like to see from such a grouping. We got a lot of positive feedback from them and discovered just how we should structure and operate the network to best effect."</p>
      <p>Vanlerberghe explains thirdly, it saw a need from project freight customers that are looking for an alternative to multinational forwarders, who may not always have adequate coverage and equipment in every part of the world and don't offer the desired strategic flexibility and one on one customer care.</p>
      <p>He adds: "IFLN offers global project logistic services with a dedicated team and experts in every local market – we have the expertise and equipment in place to handle project shipping, wherever it may be required."</p>
      <p>IFLN's general manager, Randy Durham says: "There are other project cargo networks out there, but this one is different. IFLN Global Projects network only accepts as members those who are highly proficient project forwarders."</p>
      <p>He adds: "This is not about having as many members as possible. It's about having project freight forwarder experts who are also specialists in their local markets.</p>
      <p>"Indeed, no member is able to act as the network's representative in any more than three countries, and no country can be covered by more than three IFLN Global Projects network members with a maximum of two offices.</p>
      <p>"It's about quality not quantity," Durham notes, and IFLN will vet all prospective network members. Then again, IFLN does much more than that for the network, he continues. It offers a full range of cohesive support.</p>
      <p>It can put together a team of highly specialised global project members to support any bid or any project cargo shipping task. "As IFLN, we make the necessary introductions, coordinate member efforts and liaise with the customer if needed," Durham notes. "We also really go out and sell our members' expertise and services."</p>
      <p>The nascent network already has more than 40 members and is expanding quickly. "We are very happy with the response from our own IFLN members, and we are now growing the IFLN Global Projects membership with other cargo agents who are dedicated to project forwarding," Vanlerberghe concludes.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>0a9fc8</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/etihad-cargo-upgrades-customer-loyalty-schemes/</url>
    <title>Etihad Cargo upgrades customer loyalty schemes</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2019-05-08T09:28:22+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Airline News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Etihad Cargo</topic>
      <topic>Etihad Cargo Global Customer programme</topic>
      <topic>Etihad Cargo PayLoadRewards</topic>
      <topic>Haleema Al Hosani</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Etihad Cargo has rebranded its "PayLoadRewards" cargo loyalty scheme and renewed its Global Customer programme for freight forwarders.</p>
      <p>Launched in 2013, PayLoadRewards is a dedicated loyalty programme for air cargo customers, who will continue to earn miles as before with an additional opportunity to start earning bonus miles for general cargo and premium cargo through the online booking portal.</p>
      <p>Similar to the passenger Etihad Guest loyalty programme, cargo customers can now receive exclusive benefits upon attaining Silver, Gold or Platinum Tier Status, with further enhancements to be progressively rolled out.</p>
      <p>The renewed Global Customer programme offers freight forwarders three tiers: Global Account, Global Plus and Global Partner, each holding different support levels.</p>
      <p>Haleema Al Hosani, senior manager global accounts and loyalty at Etihad Cargo says: "Today's unveiling of these commercial schemes is a proud result of the interactive dialogue we have been having with our global customers over the past months, aimed at enhancing our value offering. These programmes have been designed to reward growth, trust and consistency, embedding a renewed customer-driven culture into Etihad Cargo's modus operandi."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>1c3315</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/bollore-logistics-inaugurates-miami-foreign-trade-zone-facility/</url>
    <title>Bollore Logistics inaugurates Miami Foreign Trade Zone facility</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2018-04-05T11:52:10+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Forwarder News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Bollore Logistics</topic>
      <topic>Clement Leclerc</topic>
      <topic>Cyrille Bollore</topic>
      <topic>Florida</topic>
      <topic>Miami</topic>
      <topic>Miami Foreign Trade Zone</topic>
      <topic>Thierry Ehrenbogen</topic>
      <topic>Tony Rodrigues</topic>
      <topic>USA</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Bollore Logistics has inaugurated its Foreign Trade Zone facility in Miami, consolidating freight forwarding and contract logistics services in one location.</p>
      <p>The 200,000 square foot facility, which was inaugurated in the presence of Consul general of France in Miami, Clement Leclerc; Bollore Transport &amp; Logistics chief executive officer (CEO), Cyrille Bollore and Bollore Logistics CEO, Thierry Ehrenbogen consolidates activities that were previously housed at two different locations and the company says this will support operational synergies and cargo turnaround time for customers with time critical logistics requirements.</p>
      <p>The company says that by combining traditional freight forwarding with value added services, the Miami hub has become a multimodal platform meeting needs of its various customers, especially in the cosmetics, aerospace and travel retail industries.</p>
      <p>Bollore Americas CEO, Tony Rodrigues says: "We are extremely proud of our newest logistics centre. Miami is geographically pivotal to regional trade and a strategic location for Bolloré Logistics Americas. With this investment, we aim to play a key role in supporting the supply chain transformation of this industry."</p>
      <p>The secure facility has on-site 24/7 guard coverage, biometric access control, CCTV monitoring and recording, perimeter fencing and fire sprinkler systems engineered to handle specific commodity classifications.</p>
      <p>The warehouse offers state of the art infrastructure with 52 dock doors, 32' clear height, 60' speed bay and a line of material handling equipment that Bollore says can handle the warehouse challenges with reliability, power, productivity, performance and efficiency.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>75ea22</document_id>
    <url>https://aircargoworld.com/allposts/alibaba-to-enter-european-cloud-computing-market-in-mid-2017/</url>
    <title>Alibaba to enter European cloud computing market in mid-2017</title>
    <author>Lewis King</author>
    <published_time>2017-06-15</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>E-Commerce</category>
      <category>Freight Trends</category>
      <category>News</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
    </categories>
    <topics/>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>As it seeks to expand its global reach outside China, Alibaba Cloud announced that it will introduce "MaxCompute," to Europe's US$18.9 billion cloud computing market in the second half of 2017.</p>
      <p>The E.U. cloud market is smaller than, say, its U.S. counterpart, but it is already populated by the likes of Amazon, Salesforce, Microsoft and IBM, setting the stage for competition. Alibaba said it hopes to get a piece of this action by convincing E.U. businesses that it's artificial intelligence (AI) features can, "unlock the immense value of their data, using a highly secure and scalable cloud infrastructure and AI programs," said Wanli Min, an Alibaba Cloud scientist responsible for AI and data-mining.</p>
      <p>The Chinese cloud provider's AI program is already popular in China, where it has been applied to easing traffic congestion, diagnosing disease through medical imaging, and even predicting the winners of reality show contests.</p>
      <p>MaxCompute intends to deliver these same services to the E.U. market, using advanced AI and deep -earning technologies and algorithms for data storage, modeling and analytics.</p>
      <p>Alibaba Cloud opened its first European data center in Germany in late 2016. The company has not revealed what it's E.U. customer base looks like, but said it is in discussions with companies in Europe about using MaxCompute.</p>
      <p>Alibaba corporate headquarters</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>06e1b6</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/sia-cargo-selects-zodiac-herculight-containers/</url>
    <title>SIA Cargo selects Zodiac Herculight S containers</title>
    <author>james.graham@azurainternational.com</author>
    <published_time>2016-10-05T15:48:53+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Airfreight Industry Supplier News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Asia</topic>
      <topic>containers</topic>
      <topic>Singapore</topic>
      <topic>Singapore Airlines Cargo (SIA Cargo)</topic>
      <topic>ULDs</topic>
      <topic>Zodiac Aerospace</topic>
      <topic>Zodiac Herculight S AKE</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Singapore Airlines Cargo (SIA Cargo) has selected Zodiac Aerospace for the supply of more than 2,000 Zodiac Herculight S AKE cargo containers.</p>
      <p>The containers, constructed with a combination of composite and aluminium panels, come in two highly customised configurations to target SIA Cargo's needs in both passenger and cargo operations.</p>
      <p>Zodiac says SIA Cargo evaluated the Herculight S containers comprehensively and one of the carrier's key requirements was the sustainability of the lightweight unit load device to remain functional in operations for many years and explains the Herculight S AKE fits this requirement.</p>
      <p>Zodiac Cabin Equipment vice president of sales, Bart van Berkel says: "This truly is a positive quality and testament to the design philosophy we uphold for all of our products. We strive towards the lightest tare weight possible for our products, leading the market trend towards lightest weight with highest durability.</p>
      <p>"At the same time, we strictly will not compromise the performance potential of our products. We look forward to a successful collaboration with Singapore Airlines Cargo for many years to come."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>738e68</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/technology/dhl-tech-makes-for-a-speedier-safer-warehouse/</url>
    <title>DHL tech makes for a speedier, safer warehouse</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time>2017-05-10T13:35:55+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>technology</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic/>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>DHL Supply Chain is testing new technology that monitors warehouse activity in real-time at three pilot sites in Germany, the Netherlands and Poland. Data is aggregated from sensors on scanners and material handling equipment, and DHL's warehouse management system which is then visualised on 'heat maps' to improve efficiency and employee safety.   The system is being developed in partnership with networking firm Cisco and airline software specialist Conduce. DHL Supply Chain chief information officer and chief operating officer, Markus Voss, explains: "By monitoring operational activities in real-time rather than retrospectively, we can interpret data more meaningfully, and immediately re-engineer processes or warehouse layouts to boost operational efficiency and address potential safety blind spots in a warehouse." DHL says that the pilots have revealed valuable insights on activity peaks, warehouse layouts and processes by displaying concentrations of pickers and material handling equipment.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>5e7691</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/its-a-try-for-tcl-2019/</url>
    <title>It's a try for TCL 2019</title>
    <author>James Graham</author>
    <published_time>2018-11-21T16:45:23+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Airfreight Industry Supplier News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>TCL 2019</topic>
      <topic>Temperature Controlled Logistics</topic>
      <topic>Twickenham</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>The International Air Transport Association (IATA) is among a group of speakers who will be talking about key air cargo issues at a leading UK pharma event in January.</p>
      <p>IATA Cargo specialist manager for Europe Francisco Rizzuto, will be presenting at the annual Temperature Controlled Logistics Conference 2019 conference which takes place at Twickenham Stadium, London on January 28-31.</p>
      <p>The event aims to bring together supply chain, logistics and quality experts from around the globe to experience four days of workshops, case studies, panels, interactive discussion groups and technology showcases.</p>
      <p>Appearing on day one of the main conference, Rizzuto is set to speak about the present global status of pharma cargo community collaboration in air freight and will discuss how best to approach the issue.</p>
      <p>He will also cover how to improve the level of competency, operational and technical preparedness for temperature-sensitive air freight shipments as well as speaking about the IATA CEIV Pharma certification programme and how it can revolutionise distribution strategy.</p>
      <p>The Temperature Controlled Logistics conference, follows a journey from the beginning of the pharmaceutical supply chain, to the very end. With presentations, interactive activities covering planning, transportation, execution, last mile and post-distribution.</p>
      <p>TCL 2019 programme director Katherine Gordon, said: "Our goal is for each and every delegate who attends TCL is to leave understanding what best practice planning and execution looks like at every stage of their cold and ambient supply chain. It will be an unmissable few days for all whose profession revolves in part or wholly around pharma logistics and temperature control, and who wish to remain properly informed and at the top of their game."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>35bfe6</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/technology/video-ups-drives-vehicle-safety-with-virtual-reality-training/</url>
    <title>VIDEO: UPS drives vehicle safety with virtual reality training</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time>2017-08-16T10:57:58+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>technology</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic/>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>UPS will start training student delivery drivers to spot and identify road hazards using Virtual Reality (VR) headsets that vividly simulate the experience of driving on city streets while teaching a more memorable classroom lesson. The US parcels and logistics giant will begin launching VR training in September at its nine UPS Integrad training facilities. Staff training using VR is proving attractive in the freight industry. Cargo handler Hong Kong Air Cargo Terminals Limited (Hactl) has introduced VR training so new staff can gain experience before working in the challenging ramp environment. IT experts at UPS created the VR training modules that users see and hear inside VR headsets like the HTC Vive. Students using the modules must verbally identify potential road hazards such as pedestrians, parked cars and oncoming traffic. The 360-degree view inside the headset is realistic down to the finest details. "Virtual Reality offers a big technological leap in the realm of driver safety training," said Juan Perez, UPS chief information and engineering officer. "VR creates a hyper-realistic streetscape that will dazzle even the youngest of our drivers whose previous exposure to the technology was through video games."  The VR training modules replace the touchscreen devices UPS Integrad facilities currently use to teach lessons on road hazards. For now, the VR training is only for those who drive package delivery trucks. But the company is exploring VR and even Augmented Reality (AR) for training tractor trailer drivers and performing other duties throughout the operation. </p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>69a2c3</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/cargo-airport/brucargo-to-launch-air-cargo-belgium-with-polmans-as-chairman/</url>
    <title>BRUcargo to launch Air Cargo Belgium with Polmans as chairman</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time>2015-12-08T16:29:22+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>cargo-airport</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic/>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>The BRUcargo community in Brussels is launching a new independent organisation that will work to improve the logistics and cargo operations linked to Brussels Airport. The new Air Cargo Belgium organisation, which will be launched in February next year, is the next stage of development of BRUcargo's Strategic Committee. Brussels Airport head of cargo Steven Polmans has been nominated as its chairman. Polmans told Air Cargo News that having a separate legal entity with paying members would make it easier to hirer staff and subsidise projects. He said it had yet to be decided how many staff would be hired and whether they would by full-time or part-time. While Polmans will act as chairman, someone from the local Chamber of Commerce will become vice chairman and the secretary general will be a representative of the airline association. Representatives will be re-elected by members every two years. BRUcargo will continue with its work on developing cargo operations in the Brussels area while ACB will have a much broader scope and wider membership, including suppliers to the air cargo industry Polmans said the new organisation was influenced by the work of Air Cargo Netherlands and that 85% of its members would also be members of the Dutch group. While the new organisation carries Belgium in its name, all work carried by ACB must be to the benefit of Brussels airport. However, Polmans said the organisation could work with other airports on certain topics, such as e-freight, e-air waybill, or pharma facilities, if doing so will improve Brussel's logistics chain for stakeholders. Summarising the ACB in its member newsletter, BRUcargo said: "Early 2016, we will take a next step by forming a new independent organisation taking over these activities and further professionalising them. "The current members of the committee will be the founding members of the new organisation, but other companies and stakeholders will also be able to join. "The new organisation will represent the BRUcargo community on all levels and has a clear goal: strengthen BRUcargo, grow the volumes and drive innovation to the benefit of all stakeholders."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>76c365</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/menzies-joins-cargo-iq-kn-qatar-airways-renew-certificates/</url>
    <title>Menzies joins Cargo iQ, K+N and Qatar Airways renew certificates</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2018-03-14T10:45:20+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Airline News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Ariaen ZImmerman</topic>
      <topic>Cargo iQ</topic>
      <topic>Cargo iQ Air Cargo Intelligence Hub</topic>
      <topic>Guillaume Halleux</topic>
      <topic>Kuehne + Nagel</topic>
      <topic>Max Sauberschwarz</topic>
      <topic>Menzies Aviation</topic>
      <topic>Qatar Airways Cargo</topic>
      <topic>Robert Fordree</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Qatar Airways Cargo and Kuehne + Nagel have received their continuing certification from Cargo iQ's auditor, and Menzies have joined the group as a new member.</p>
      <p>SGS carried out an independent audit for Cargo iQ, with members undertaking a two day on site visit to demonstrate their processes and services are compliant with quality standards for the worldwide air cargo industry, as created and implemented by the Cargo iQ membership.</p>
      <p>Cargo iQ executive director, Ariaen Zimmerman says: "The response of our members and the industry to our new external audit has been overwhelmingly positive. In an industry which can fall into a cycle of being inward-facing, the value of external validation on our processes and procedures is clear.</p>
      <p>"Each and every one of our members has the opportunity to improve their operations through this."</p>
      <p>Kuehne + Nagel received two certifications, one for its forwarding services and for its internal IT platform for Cargo iQ, the Cargo iQ Data Management Platform.</p>
      <p>Global head carrier and gateway air logistics, Max Sauberschwarz says: "Continuous process optimisation is a crucial part of our air freight business strategy. We are delighted to be the first forwarder who has received the new Cargo iQ Phase 2 certificate. This confirms our high standards in airfreight."</p>
      <p>Qatar Airways acting chief officer for cargo, Guillaume Halleux says: "Air cargo is such an interconnected industry that no success is possible without a consistent and coherent collaboration by all parties in the logistics chain.</p>
      <p>"This certification is certainly a booster for us to continue our active participation in the Cargo iQ working group, setting industry standards that bring progressive changes to the air cargo industry."</p>
      <p>Menzies Aviation vice president of cargo development, Robert Fordree says: "We have recently launched our new cargo strategy across our network and joining Cargo iQ is an integral part of our drive for excellence and a standardised approach to our customers' expectations."</p>
      <p>The group has also launched an Air Cargo Intelligence Hub that gives members real-time access to their performance data, enabling them to develop new products and improve processes.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>7c9f54</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/boost-for-smes-as-cargo-iq-unveils-new-shipment-planning-and-control-platform/</url>
    <title>Boost for SMEs as Cargo iQ unveils new shipment planning and control platform</title>
    <author>Alexander Whiteman</author>
    <published_time>2019-03-15T14:46:05+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Cargo iQ</topic>
      <topic>CCS Italy</topic>
      <topic>SMEs</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Small- and medium-sized forwarders can boost the quality of their air freight services following the successful trial of a new control and planning tool.</p>
      <p>Cargo iQ's SME Solution provides forwarders with live-tracking of individual consignments.</p>
      <p>Executive director Ariaen Zimmerman told The Loadstar the system marked the "first time" SMEs could operate shipment control and planning within one system.</p>
      <p>"We aim to give end-to-end visibility. The first step is to promise access for SME forwarders and more steps are down the line," said Mr Zimmerman.</p>
      <p>"It's a transaction-based fee, you don't need to be a member, but if you are of a certain size, it may become more financially beneficial to join Cargo iQ.</p>
      <p>"There are good reasons to become a member, but this offers a fairly straightforward planning and control solution."</p>
      <p>Following registration with an accredited Cargo iQ SME IT service provider, forwarders can use Cargo iQ performance management tools immediately.</p>
      <p>An official launch would be in the "coming months", said the company, after a full evaluation of the trial.</p>
      <p>"We concluded there was real demand in the market and technical solutions available for us to address the lack of SME forwarders in Cargo iQ," said Mr Zimmerman.</p>
      <p>"We have aligned the systems so we can all go forward, and you can apply Cargo iQ quality standards for every shipment."</p>
      <p>Italy-based CCS was a participant in the trial, utilising Riege Software's back-end Cargo Data Management Platform (CDMP) technology.</p>
      <p>A source from CCS told The Loadstar that Cargo iQ had been seen as an "elite club for big forwarders", but with the new system, "everyone was interested".</p>
      <p>Senior consultant at CCS Italy Gianni Mauri said: "Taking part in Cargo iQ's SME Solution trial is a great opportunity. It allowed us to demonstrate how independent freight forwarders can work with air cargo carriers to benefit the overall air cargo industry."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>0b25c5</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/uncategorized/swissports-tanzania-monopoly-ends/</url>
    <title>Swissport's Tanzania monopoly ends</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time>2011-12-14T23:00:00+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>uncategorized</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic/>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>FOUR companies have been awarded licenses to operate at six airports in Tanzania, ending Swissport's role as sole ground handler.</p>
      <p>The move by The Tanzania Civil Aviation Authority (TCAA) would boost competition, reducing charges and fares. The quartet of new companies is Aviation Handling Services, DTP Jet Concept, Mtwara Aviation Services and Taha Fresh Handling.</p>
      <p>"Every ground-handling company will work to their best ability in order to meet the expectations of their customers," TCCA assistant public information officer Anita Jonas said. "Customers will get value for their money, [as] the charges will not be as high and clearance of goods will be much faster due to the fact that more ground-handling companies will be offering the services."</p>
      <p>Swissport Tanzania met the requirements and was licensed to operate at Class I airports in Tanzania for a term of five years effective from 25 May 2008. The license allowed the company to operate at any airport in the country, subject to obtaining a concession from the respective airport operator.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>14c87e</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/mercator-launches-intelligent-cargo-ecosystem/</url>
    <title>Mercator launches Intelligent Cargo Ecosystem</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2017-03-14T14:15:51+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Airfreight Industry Supplier News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Brendan McKittrick</topic>
      <topic>Finnair Cargo</topic>
      <topic>Intelligent Cargo Ecosystem</topic>
      <topic>Janne Tarvainen</topic>
      <topic>Mercator</topic>
      <topic>Warehouse App</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Mercator has launched the Intelligent Cargo Ecosystem, the first open API platform the air cargo management and ground handling, which its says will help carriers revolutionise air cargo management.</p>
      <p>It will be showcasing its Warehouse App, a digital solution enabling air cargo carriers to connect goods, people, data and processes to transform warehousing operations and Mercator says it is the first in a series of breakthrough applications to be rolled out as part of the Intelligent Cargo Ecosystem.</p>
      <p>Mercator says the new open architecture platform enables air cargo carriers to break away from constraints of legacy systems by allowing handlers and operators to make process changes within the system quickly.</p>
      <p>It says the app will let companies introduce new services, for example carriers moving small consumer packages and perishable goods more effectively by having full visibility into the movements of the shipments and optimising air cargo management processes to reduce delays and minimise the risk of disruption.</p>
      <p>Mercator chief technology officer, Brendan McKittrick says: "Mobile technology and open API platforms will revolutionise the industry, allowing carriers to get a real-time digital view of the entire air cargo supply chain. The technology can really transform the industry, providing much greater visibility, versatility, and above all, the ability to simplify complex and challenging processes."</p>
      <p>The app allows warehouse agents to capture all air cargo data through a single mobile interface and achieve full visibility into every stage of warehouse management, from acceptance and relocation, through to breakdown, build-up, delivery and tracking billing data.</p>
      <p>Finnair Cargo is one of the first carriers to deploy the Warehouse App, and vice president head of cargo, Janne Tarvainen says: "We are very pleased to have Mercator as a partner in this significant project. The Warehouse App will be an important tool for years to come. The new mobile and digital system, alongside our investment in a new cargo terminal, will revolutionise Finnair's cargo system for customers and partners."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>ac1dbb</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/bollore-logistics-partners-oro-create-b2b-e-commerce-platform/</url>
    <title>Bollore Logistics partners with Oro Inc. to create B2B e-commerce platform</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2017-11-22T10:23:03+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Forwarder News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Bollore LINK</topic>
      <topic>Bollore Logistics</topic>
      <topic>Frederic Serra</topic>
      <topic>Ludovic Laungani</topic>
      <topic>Oro</topic>
      <topic>OroCommerce</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Bollore Logistics has partnered with Oro Inc. in a global venture offering clients a one-stop B2B e-commerce sales and processing service.</p>
      <p>The international and logistics company says it creates an enhanced means for multichannel retailers to do business with customer companies, simplify and speed up order preparation, handling and delivery procedures orchestrated by Bollore Logistics.</p>
      <p>The service harnesses direct digital sales to consumers by adapting those to the particularities of B2B e-ecommerce – an activity set to reach $6.7 trillion by 2020.</p>
      <p>The OroCommerce platforms – tailored to the specifics of B2B – are augmented with Bollore's LINK collaborative information network.</p>
      <p>LINK provides real-time tracking, inventory, first and last mile status and other updating, using the constant input of maritime, air and road transporters, warehouses, customs and other supply chain companies.</p>
      <p>It is already used by 5,300 customers, 20,000 specific users per month and receives 400,000 views per month.</p>
      <p>Bollore Logistics solutions director, Frederic Serra says: "B2C e-commerce sites have become the ambassadors of retailers' online presence, and we import and adapt those efficiencies to simplify and increase B2B experience and activity."</p>
      <p>"We then go further by integrating our transport and logistics expertise and IT assets into the offer, providing processing service and visibility from order placement and management to final destination delivery."</p>
      <p>Bollore Logistics Asia Pacific regional e-commerce solution, Ludovic Laungani says: "Next step for us is to integrate well-known payment gateways in order to provide a complete, end-to-end offer for B2B."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>6a5962</document_id>
    <url>https://aircargoworld.com/allposts/swissport-international-opens-second-warehouse-at-vie/</url>
    <title>Swissport International opens second warehouse at VIE</title>
    <author>Brianne Ledda</author>
    <published_time>2019-07-01</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Airports</category>
      <category>EMEA</category>
      <category>Facilities</category>
      <category>News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Flughafen Wien AG</topic>
      <topic>Fraport Group</topic>
      <topic>ground handler</topic>
      <topic>Heathrow Cargo Handling Ltd.</topic>
      <topic>swissport</topic>
      <topic>Vienna International Airport (VIE)</topic>
      <topic>warehouse</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>On June 28, Swissport International opened its second air cargo warehouse at Vienna International Airport (VIE).</p>
      <p>The 2,100 square foot building is located directly adjacent to the airfield, allowing for faster transportation of cargo to and from the aircraft, according to Swissport. With the new facility, built by Flughafen Wien AG, the ground handler hosts a total of 7,000 square meters in warehouse space at VIE.</p>
      <p>Swissport said that it entered into a "long-term lease agreement for the facility" with VIE, but did not provide further details. The ground handler did say, however, that it has relocated its cargo documentation to new offices in the facility, in accordance with the agreement.</p>
      <p>Swissport also told Air Cargo World it is planning for a "10to/aqm/p.a. utilization rate" in its facilities at VIE, though it depends on the actual mix of carriers and cargoes.</p>
      <p>"VIE is a growing hub airport and we are closely monitoring the developments around the airport infrastructure, i.e. the planned additional runway," the ground handler added.</p>
      <p>The opening of this second warehouse at VIE continues Swissport's global expansions efforts over the past year, which include the inking of an agreement with Fraport Group and the total acquisition of Heathrow Cargo Handling Ltd.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>d46718</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/three-more-members-join-pharmaaero-air-cargo</url>
    <title>Three more members join Pharma.Aero</title>
    <author>STAT Times</author>
    <published_time>2017-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>AirCargo</topic>
      <topic>Aviation</topic>
      <topic>Logistics</topic>
      <topic>Freight</topic>
      <topic>SupplyChain</topic>
      <topic>Shipping</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Pharma.Aero welcomes an additional three companies into the organisation to foster strong collaboration amongst all the key stakeholders involved in the pharmaceutical supply chain.</p>
      <p>The two joining air cargo stakeholders are Expeditors and Envirotainer. Additionally, the organisation welcomes 7th airport member, Montevideo Free Airport. This brings the total number of companies in Pharma.Aero to eighteen members.</p>
      <p>Nathan De Valck, chairman of Pharma.Aero, said, "The Pharma.Aero membership base is expanding to include all stakeholders in the pharmaceutical supply chain. Our cross-industry collaboration now involves pharmaceutical manufacturers, airports, airlines, logistics service providers and solution providers. This large scope allows us to tackle a broad range of improvement projects in the Pharma.Aero working groups. Together with these air cargo stakeholders, we will develop global pharmaceutical trade lanes, implement best practices and share market knowledge and expertise."</p>
      <p>Pharma.Aero welcomes other IATA CEIV airport communities, shippers, airline carriers, logistics companies and other pharmaceutical stakeholders with like-minded goals to become members.</p>
      <p>Peter Van Domburg, district manager Belgium &amp; Luxembourg, explains, "Close partnerships, consistent global execution, targeted communications, and deep industry expertise allow Expeditors' logistics specialists to successfully navigate through the complexities of the healthcare industry. Pharma.Aero personifies the answers to these needs and why Expeditors believes in the success of this kind of collaboration which helps preserve the integrity of Healthcare products for the patients at the end of the supply chain."</p>
      <p>"MVD Free Airport is confident that joining Pharma.Aero will provide a solid platform for a better understanding of key tendencies and issues present throughout the pharmaceutical supply chain. It hopes to provide the network with strategic insights on the challenges faced throughout emerging markets and the best practices and lessons learnt that will enable the industry itself to raise the bar in terms of quality distribution standards," says Bruno Guella, managing director at MVD Free Airport.</p>
      <p>Anna Levander, CSO at Envirotainer, explains, "At Envirotainer we feel very strongly that bringing the industry together to collectively further best practices based on real experience is the way forward to secure the integrity of Pharmaceutical products."</p>
      <p>Brussels Airport and Miami Airport are the founding members of this initiative in October 2016.</p>
      <p>Photo: Miami Airport. The airport partnered with Brussels Airport to launch the Pharma.aero initiative in October 2016.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>b9437c</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/bh-worldwide-opens-second-singapore-control-tower/</url>
    <title>B&amp;H Worldwide opens second Singapore Control Tower</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2019-01-18T12:29:43+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Airfreight Industry Supplier News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>ALPS Free Trade Zone</topic>
      <topic>B&amp;H Worldwide</topic>
      <topic>B&amp;H Worldwide Control Tower</topic>
      <topic>Changi Airport</topic>
      <topic>Singapore</topic>
      <topic>Stuart Allen</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Aerospace logistics provider B&amp;H Worldwide has established a second Control Tower at its climate-controlled facility in Singapore, at Changi Airport.</p>
      <p>The Control Tower leverages Singapore's position as one of the fastest growing aerospace markets in the world, with connectivity across the Far East and Oceania.</p>
      <p>It is located within the ALPS Free Trade Zone, providing an integrated information hub to enable team members to proactively monitor customer shipments 24/7/365 at the same time as providing updates and full visibility.</p>
      <p>The second Control Tower will utilise the newly designed, next generation FirstTrac computer system to manage shipments.</p>
      <p>Stuart Allen, CEO of B&amp;H Worldwide says: "This new initiative is an exciting start to 2019 and will give customers operating across multiple time-zones even greater confidence in our services.  All our global solutions are under-pinned by cutting edge IT and state of the art facilities and the new Control Tower will enable our highly trained teams to maintain robust operating procedures."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>857ecf</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/bollore-logistics-acquires-danish-forwarder-global-solutions/</url>
    <title>Bollore Logistics acquires Danish forwarder, Global Solutions</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2018-01-30T11:24:41+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Europe News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Bollore Logistics</topic>
      <topic>David Smith</topic>
      <topic>Global Solutions</topic>
      <topic>Henri Le Gouis</topic>
      <topic>Thomas Toubro</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Bollore Logistics has expanded its presence in the Scandinavian market by acquiring a majority stake in Danish freight forwarder, Global Solutions.</p>
      <p>The Danish company, which has offices in Vejle and Copenhagen Airport, started operations in 2006 and offers airfreight, ocean freight and road/distribution/courier services, particularly on the Europe-Asia axis.</p>
      <p>Bollore says the transaction will expand its network in Europe and the company's global end-to-end offering in the Scandinavian market.</p>
      <p>Bollore Logistics chief executive officer for Europe, Henri Le Gouis says: "This new location will enable us to better serve our key account customers in Denmark and more generally in Scandinavia.</p>
      <p>"We will support Danish companies in their international development and logistics projects, particularly in Africa, the continent of the future with strong market opportunities, where we operate as the first integrated logistics network."</p>
      <p>CEO for Northern Europe, David Smith says: "We are also aiming to strengthen our range of solutions and services for the Aid &amp; Relief sector, which is strongly represented in Denmark."</p>
      <p>Global Solutions founder and managing director, Thomas Toubro says he is: "Satisfied and honoured to be now part of the big Bolloré family Group. I am very confident for the future, and believe in our ability to elevate Bolloré Logistics to the rank of the leading transport and logistics operators in Scandinavia."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>d9887b</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/delta-cargo-offers-realtime-bluetooth-tracking-for-container-shipments-air-cargo</url>
    <title>Delta Cargo offers real-time Bluetooth tracking for container shipments</title>
    <author>STAT Times</author>
    <published_time>2018-03-07T12:52:00+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Delta Cargo</topic>
      <topic>Bluetooth tracking</topic>
      <topic>container shipments</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Delta Cargo is the first US passenger airline to recently introduce a new Bluetooth tracking technology, with real-time tracking for unit load devices (ULDs).</p>
      <p>It marks a new era for Delta Cargo and for over 500 million kilograms of cargo, which it carries every year. The technology will replace manual tracking for all shipping containers and introduce ULDs, which will help move cargo shipments, baggage and mail, globally.</p>
      <p>"Our customers expect improved tracking and immediate transparency for ULD shipments, and this best-in-class product will deliver exactly that," said Shawn Cole, vice president – cargo, Delta Cargo.</p>
      <p>"Our innovative tracking technology, in conjunction with our 24/7 cargo control center, offers us the competitive edge to serve our customers," said Cole.</p>
      <p>Real-time ULD tracking information will also allow Delta's cargo control center to more accurately monitor and reroute shipments that are delayed due to irregular operations, like inclement weather.</p>
      <p>The new tracking system will also enable Delta Cargo to produce electronic unit control receipts, which is mandated by the International Air Transport Association (IATA), while ULDs are transferred between parties, thereby making it the first cargo airline to offer a fully automated solution for customer transactions.</p>
      <p>Delta was the first airline to test Bluetooth tracking technology in 2016, and has since deployed readers to 23 locations.</p>
      <p>By the end of 2018, the tracking system will be available on all of Delta's ULDs, with over 1,400 readers tracking customer shipments at more than 200 airports across six continents.</p>
      <p>The airline's current GPS-enabled cargo tracking products, including a recently-announced service for highly time-sensitive shipments called 'Equation Critical', will be available for both narrow body and wide-body aircraft shipments traveling internationally and within the US.</p>
      <p>Delta recently introduced auto check-in for Fly Delta app users, and has started testing its biometric boarding pass at DCA and its redesigned E-Gate experience in Atlanta.</p>
      <p>Over the last few year, Delta Cargo has led the industry on a number of other innovative customer solutions, such as biometric-based self-service bag drop, RFID baggage handling, real-time bag tracking through its Fly Delta mobile app, more efficient and high tech automated screening lanes and a groundbreaking flight deck app that helps its pilots avoid turbulence for a more comfortable flight.</p>
      <p>Delta's partnership with CLEAR offers exclusive rates to the US-based SkyMiles members for a faster way through security lines at more than 20 airports nationwide.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>5057f9</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/jettainer-lufthansa-develop-intelligent-containers/</url>
    <title>Jettainer and Lufthansa to develop "intelligent" containers</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2016-10-20T15:38:51+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Airfreight Industry Supplier News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Carsten Hernig</topic>
      <topic>Jettainer</topic>
      <topic>Lufthansa Industry Solutions</topic>
      <topic>Martin Kraemer</topic>
      <topic>Pieter Huyghens</topic>
      <topic>Ralf Struckmeier</topic>
      <topic>ULD</topic>
      <topic>Unit load device</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Jettainer and Lufthansa Industry Solutions are to cooperate on creating "intelligent" containers to help accelerate maintenance and control procedures in the future.</p>
      <p>The containers will be able to provide information including location, temperature changes, shocks and other external factors independently and provide information about its state.</p>
      <p>The new generation of containers will accelerate maintenance and control procedures, and at the same time the increased level of transparency will make it easier to determine who is responsible for any damage to the ULD. It is hoped companies will take greater care of the units, reducing damage.</p>
      <p>Jettainer managing director, Carsten Hernig says: "The intelligent container will ensure greater transparency within the process chain in future. We're deliberately breaking new ground here in order to make our services for customers even more efficient in future."</p>
      <p>Lufthansa Industry Solutions is to use its experience in tracking technologies in developing the digital containers, with other functions to be gradually added.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>ddbeb4</document_id>
    <url>https://aircargoworld.com/allposts/panalpina-dhl-gf-join-growing-list-of-digital-freight-sales-platforms/</url>
    <title>Panalpina, DHL GF join growing list of digital freight sales platforms</title>
    <author>Chelsea Toczauer, Associate Editor</author>
    <published_time>2019-06-03</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Americas</category>
      <category>Asia Pacific</category>
      <category>EMEA</category>
      <category>Freight Trends</category>
      <category>Logistics</category>
      <category>News</category>
      <category>Perishables</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>DHL</topic>
      <topic>Panalpina</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Two more companies have joined the now not-so-exclusive group of logistics providers offering digital freight sales platforms available in air cargo – today, Panalpina announced it will present its new customer platform at Air Cargo Europe 2019 in Munich this week, while DHL Global Forwarding (DHL GF) launched its own platform last week. While the growing number of these platforms indicates process digitalization is the new norm, how can air cargo stakeholders determine which providers are successful in their pursuit of this trend?</p>
      <p>In a 2017 study, Freightos surveyed freight forwarders on what service differentiation meant to them in the era of digital freight. Freight forwarders said that value-added services and customer service were critical to determining service differentiation among providers. For forwarders this meant easy automation for seamless operations – they did not want to invest in a cloud-based mailroom requiring manual processes. The first steps in automation forwarders are looking for include:</p>
      <p>Providers are clearly taking note of these expectations, as seen in the development of service offerings provided most recently by Panalpina and DHL GF.</p>
      <p>Panalpina's new "customer portal" is designed to provide fully automated and instant quotes, collaborative shipment management and real-time lane risk assessment. According to Panalpina, the collaborative feature of its platform that allows customers and external partners to work in remote teams on the platform is an industry-first. The lane risk assessment feature will also support customers, especially in the pharmaceutical industry, to assess and determine the most reliable shipment planning, even months before a shipment. The company said it is also working to add additional features, such as machine learning for quotation, a chatbot and big data analysis. Panalpina is allowing interested customers to test the portal at the conference before its launch later this year.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, DHL GF's "myDHLi Quote &amp; Book" is designed to provide customers instant quotes for air and ocean shipments, as well as transport insurance. On the platform, customers can compare the rates and lead times of air and ocean freight with end-to-end visibility. Customers can also save quotes – valid for 30 days – and share them via e-mail with selected recipients. With the platform, customers may also request a quote on the platform for special cargo, including dangerous goods, lithium batteries and non-stackable cargo.</p>
      <p>Whether these new platforms, in addition to the many other existing and developing platforms, are successful in meeting freight forwarders' expectations remains to be seen. Regardless, it is likely we will soon see more emerge on the subject over the next year.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>dc0891</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/freight-forwarder/dachser-expands-airfreight-business-in-china/</url>
    <title>Dachser expands airfreight business in China</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time>2017-04-27T10:33:17+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>freight-forwarder</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Dachser</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Logistics firm Dachser has expanded its airfreight station at Shanghai Pudong Airport Bonded Zone. The Germany-headquartered firm said work on its facility in Shanghai to expand it to 6,000 sq m from 3,000 sq m had now been completed. The expansion allows the company to operate with a two airport gateway strategy. This will speed up airfreight processing, the company said. Inbound and outbound cargo for the ten Dachser branches in its north China region will be routed through  Shanghai Pudong Airport and the Beijing International Airport, depending on their geographical proximity, specific requirements of the goods and current market situation. "The north China gateway demonstrates Dachser's high quality process management across continents," said Yves Larquemin, managing director air and sea logistics north China." "Consolidating cargo via the gateway instead of handling it individually at local airports will harmonize processes and extend service capabilities," said David Wang, airfreight gateway manager north China. </p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>68a1dc</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/iata/wsc17-schiphol-gets-grant-for-pharma-alert-system/</url>
    <title>WCS17: Schiphol gets grant for pharma temperature alert system</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time>2017-03-14T13:50:26+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic/>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Amsterdam Airport Schiphol is to develop an early warning system for pharma shippers with the help of a €1m research grant, it was revealed at the IATA World Cargo Symposium on 14 March. The money, from the Netherlands Organisation for Scientific Research and TKI Dinalog, the Dutch Institute for Advanced Logistics, will fund data collection and monitoring of Pharma Gateway Amsterdam (PGA) shipments to identify exceptions such as temperature excursions. The information will then be used to design a model to alert shippers when there has been an issue with their consignment. Schiphol has teamed up with Air France KLM Cargo, Cargonaut, and PGA members for the project, which starts this month and with results expected later this year. The Schiphol Cargo Community and Cargonaut will add performance management and alerting capabilities to the community Cloud; Amsterdam University of Applied Sciences and Delft University of Technology will do the underlying research, contribute to the development, and measure the benefits for shippers and their transport suppliers. Stekelenburg said: "Pharma shippers are asking for more visibility so they can have confidence that their sensitive cargo is being handled safely through the supply chain and find solutions if there are issues such as temperature excursions. "This research will enable us to develop a system capable of stepping up to those challenges." Air France KLM Cargo executive vice-president Marcel de Nooijer added: "We are keen to improve the supply chain in collaboration with other parties in the chain, contributing to overall higher product integrity for pharmaceutical shipments." while Sebastiaan Scholte, chief executive of PGA member company, Jan de Rijk Logistics commented: "We hope that many other air cargo supply chain communities will follow this example and work together, because this is how the whole industry will improve." Speaking at an event to announce the development, Schiphol Airport cargo director Jonas van Stekelenburg said it was down to members of the organisation how they would use the data provided when an alert is triggered. "Not everyone handles a warning in the same way," he said. "This is up to the parties themselves. We have 13 members who are going to develop the system. "There is not going to be a rule that everyone is going to share everything with everyone, but what we want is an improvement in the pharma shipment process, of course. "Shippers want to know if something goes wrong and what the action will be. We hope that in the end everyone will know everything, but at the beginning we will take it slowly and whoever generates the data decides what happens to that data." Scholte added: "If the data is shared amongst all the players in air cargo supply chain then you can take corrective measurements sooner than if it is not shared." Kester Meijer, director of operational integrity, compliance and safety at Air France KLM, added: "When we get the data from the cargo community portal we can immediately take action and see where in the supply chain, when it is under our control, whether we can do anything. "In hindsight you can also do data analysis – what are the routings where you see these excursions – and take action to ensure that it does not re-occur in the future." PGA, formed a year ago with the aim of providing a transparent and qualified process for pharma, includes 13 members representing forwarders, ground handlers, hauliers, and airlines. Its members are expected to be certified to the IATA CEIV Pharma standard, and benefit from cooperative and competitive knowledge sharing.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>22cfe1</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/edi-transactions-shoot-up-with-kales-ezycompliance/</url>
    <title>EDI transactions shoot up with Kale's ezyCompliance</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2019-03-27T15:29:32+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Asia News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Amar More</topic>
      <topic>Anusorn Lovichit</topic>
      <topic>ezyCompliance</topic>
      <topic>Kale Logistics Solutions</topic>
      <topic>Thailand International Freight Forwarders Association</topic>
      <topic>TIFFA EDI Services</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Thailand International Freight Forwarders Association (TIFFA EDI Services) has achieved over 220 times in growth volumes of EDI transactions since implementing Kale Logistics Solutions' PING services on the ezyCompliance platform.</p>
      <p>Several other performance parameters such as saving up to 80% on each ENS/AMS filings and an increase of about eight times in MAWB filings were other significant accomplishments by TIFFA EDI Services.</p>
      <p>The e-freight initiative aims to remove paper documents from the supply chain, developed with regional stakeholders to replace paper air waybills with electronic data interchange message formats.</p>
      <p>Thailand is a key country for air waybill volume, and the focus for TIFFA EDI Services has been to implement e-AWB and later expand the technology adoption to include e-freight compliance.</p>
      <p>Amar More, director of Kale Logistics Solution says: "We are glad that we could provide the necessary technological innovation and support to TIFFA EDI Services for their growth story. PING services has capability to push the global e-AWB adoption globally and we strive to work towards creating digital air freight communities worldwide using such innovations."</p>
      <p>Anusorn Lovichit, managing director of TIFFA EDI Services says: "There has been an increase in the number of customers handled on this platform by eighteen times in between 2014 and 2018. We are confident that this platform will further facilitate trade in addition to Thailand's National Single Window for electronic transactions which is emerging as a key requirement for global trade."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>e3308b</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/iata-wcs2017-e1m-pharma-shipper-early-warning-system-schiphol/</url>
    <title>IATA WCS2017: €1m for pharma shipper early warning system at Schiphol</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2017-03-14T11:12:03+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Airport News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air France KLM Cargo</topic>
      <topic>Amsterdam Airport Schiphol</topic>
      <topic>Amsterdam University of Applied Science</topic>
      <topic>Cargonaut</topic>
      <topic>Delft University of Technology</topic>
      <topic>Jonas van Stekelenburg</topic>
      <topic>Marcel de Nooijer</topic>
      <topic>Netherlands Organisation for Scientific Research</topic>
      <topic>Pharma Gateway Amsterdam</topic>
      <topic>Schiphol Cargo Community</topic>
      <topic>TKI Dinalog</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Amsterdam Airport Schiphol is to invest €1 million ($1.06 million) in developing an early warning system for pharma shippers, starting this month and results expected later this year.</p>
      <p>The money, a subsidy from the Netherlands Organisation for Scientific Research, and TKI Dinalog, to fund data collection and monitoring of Pharma Gateway Amsterdam (PGA) shipments in order to identify exceptions such as temperature incursions.</p>
      <p>Schiphol has teamed up with Air France KLM Cargo, Cargonaut and PGA members for the project, with the Schiphol Cargo Community and Cargonaut adding performance management and alerting capabilities to the community Cloud, Amsterdam University of Applied Sciences and Delft University of Technology doing underlying research, contribute to the development and measure benefits for shippers and their transport suppliers.</p>
      <p>Amsterdam Airport Schiphol cargo director, Jonas van Stekelenburg says: "Pharma shippers are asking for more visibility so they can have confidence that their sensitive cargo is being handled safely through the supply chain and find solutions if there are issues such as temperature incursions."</p>
      <p>Air France KLM Cargo executive vice president, Marcel de Nooijer says pharma is very important for the airline, saying: "We are keen to improve the supply chain in collaboration with other parties in the chain, contributing to overall higher product integrity for pharmaceutical shipments."</p>
      <p>PGA was formed a year ago with the aim of providing a transparent and qualified process, including 13 members representing forwarders, ground handlers, hauliers and airlines, and members are expected to be certified to International Air Transport Association Center of Excellence for Independent Validators Pharma standards.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>058764</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/hactl-introduces-virtual-reality-train-staff/</url>
    <title>Hactl introduces virtual reality to train new staff</title>
    <author>James Muir</author>
    <published_time>2017-08-16T08:55:38+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Asia News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>COSAC-VR</topic>
      <topic>Hactl</topic>
      <topic>Hong Kong</topic>
      <topic>Hong Kong Air Cargo Terminals</topic>
      <topic>Mark Whitehead</topic>
      <topic>Simon Yap</topic>
      <topic>Virtual Reality</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Hong Kong Air Cargo Terminals (Hactl) has introduced a Virtual Reality (VR) training environment, enabling new staff to gain experience before working on the ramp.</p>
      <p>The COSAC-VR provides users with an interactive, fully immersive, 360 degrees, four-dimensional experience, with the first phase covering aircraft cargo compartment operations, and other areas of Hactl operations will be included in future modules.</p>
      <p>COSAC-VR overcomes the limitations of on-the-job-training in preparing new staff for working in ramp handling, the fast pace of work, and the restricted opportunity to practice on real aircraft and ramp equipment.</p>
      <p>The system is not dependent on a high technology, fixed location training suite, but is fully portable and can be quickly set up in any location.</p>
      <p>The VR is expected to speed up the learning process, enable trainees to experience a wider variety of scenarios such as handling odd-sized cargo pallets and special loads, and enhance safety awareness.</p>
      <p>Hactl senior manager for learning and development, Simon Yap says: "In the past, newly-recruited ground service staff had to undergo extensive classroom training before experiencing the real-life aircraft cargo handling environment."</p>
      <p>"COSAC-VR has reduced the reliance on real aircraft availability and suitable weather conditions for training, and trainees meanwhile can undergo work simulations in a totally safe environment."</p>
      <p>Hactl chief executive, Mark Whitehead says young recruits are well versed in VR technology due to using computer games, so VR should help them and turn learning into an enjoyable experience.</p>
      <p>He says: "This is just the beginning: we will add progressively to COSAC-VR's scope, and look at other ways to deploy VR, such as staff induction and internal communication. We are very interested in exploring collaboration with our airline customers on the VR training concept, for our mutual benefit."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>fb272d</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/finnair-cargo-signs-up-to-cargo-one-booking-platform/</url>
    <title>Finnair Cargo signs up to cargo.one booking platform</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time>2019-03-12T05:00:00+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>cargo.one</topic>
      <topic>Finnair</topic>
      <topic>Lufthansa Cargo</topic>
      <topic>WCS19</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Finnair Cargo has become the latest airline to sign up to offer its capacity through booking portal cargo.one.</p>
      <p>The portal will allow the airline's freight forwarder customers to digitally book spot market capacities at live prices and with direct booking confirmation. The deal was announced at IATA's World Cargo Symposium.</p>
      <p>Fredrik Wildtgrube, head of global sales at Finnair Cargo, said: "Digital connectivity is the missing link to guarantee end-to-end speed, quality and continuous improvement in the industry. We are happy to now offer our customers a fully digital first-class booking experience with cargo.one.</p>
      <p>"Making our offers available digitally through cargo.one is a forward-thinking move and will benefit both our customers and Finnair Cargo now and in the long-term."</p>
      <p>Finnair Cargo customers, such as Hellmann Worldwide Logistics which also uses cargo.one, welcome the partnership.</p>
      <p>Jan Kleine-Lasthues, global head of airfreight at Hellmann Worldwide Logistics, said: "We are very pleased to see Finnair Cargo joining the cargo.one platform, underscoring its image as a customer oriented and forward-thinking cargo carrier. We compliment the decision to join the multi-carrier platform in an effort to decrease complexity for customers, rather than to focus on a proprietary channel."</p>
      <p>Moritz Claussen, managing director of cargo.one added: "While some players in the industry still lament about digitalization, Finnair Cargo joins leading cargo carriers in the pursuit to actively drive the industry's digital development, to the benefit of their customers and to further strengthening their position in the market.</p>
      <p>"With the partnership, cargo.one becomes even more attractive for forwarders, adding more destinations in North America and Asia – and a platform no airline should want to be missed on".</p>
      <p>The Finnair Cargo offering is planned to be available on the cargo.one platform starting from May 2019.</p>
      <p>Other companies to sign up to the platform include: Lufthansa Cargo, Leisure Cargo, Dachser and JAS Forwarding.</p>
      <p>Lufthansa Cargo, along with others, has also invested in the platform.</p>
      <p> </p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>0b200c</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/kerry-logistics-turns-to-robots-in-hong-kong/</url>
    <title>Kerry Logistics turns to robots in Hong Kong</title>
    <author>james.graham@azurainternational.com</author>
    <published_time>2015-09-16T10:38:58+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Asia News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics/>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Kerry Logistics has introduced six fully-automated and programmed robotic butlers at its flagship product customisation and consolidation centre (PC3) in Hong Kong.</p>
      <p>The logistics service provider says it has brought in the robots to meet "the ever-growing consumer demands in online shopping".</p>
      <p>According to Kerry Logistics, the robots "speed-to‐market order fulfillment is the key to success in the retail industry. The process of picking products is at the heart of e-commerce operations, where high volumes of small and irregular orders predominate".</p>
      <p>The robotic butlers have been deployed in Kerry Logistics' order fulfilment centre, where sales orders from retailers and e-commerce marketplaces are processed. Real-time orders are transmitted to the robots via Kerry Logistics' proprietary warehouse management system (WMS) .</p>
      <p>Designated shelves are then delivered to the pick station. A simple lighting indicates which items to include in shipments, with every item tracked via barcodes.</p>
      <p>The robotic butlers operate 24 hours a day, and can pick 280 items per hour, Kerry Logistics says, benefiting from a pick rate four times faster than that of traditional methods. This solution, according to the logistics specialist, is ideal for retail brands which sell a wide variety of consumer products.</p>
      <p>Kerry Logistics operates across China and Asia. It has more than 550 offices in 40 countries and territories.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
</corpus>
