<corpus>
  <document>
    <document_id>a894be</document_id>
    <url>http://pharma.aero/images/blog/White%20Paper%20DIGI%201.0%20Certification%20of%20Pharmaceuticals%20Air%20Trade%20Lanes%20through%20Digitisation.pdf?page=8</url>
    <title>DIGI 1.0 : CERTIFICATION OF PHARMACEUTICALSAIR TRADE LANES THROUGH DIGITISATION - Page 8</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time/>
    <categories/>
    <topics/>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Status and location data Presently, shippers have to rely mainly on the forwarders for the status and location of their product. These forwarders in turn get their tracking information mainly from carriers and their respective Cargo Community Systems. However, most shippers do not have direct access to this information.The working party identified common key milestones based on the flight status update (FSU) messages, which are currently being time-stamped by the airlines. These milestones allow one to interpret the location of a shipment at a given time.</p>
      <p>Quality dataTypical examples of quality data are CEIV Pharma Acceptance Checklists and other Quality Analysis (QA) checks. Presently, shippers only get access to these quality data after an excursion or a QA issue and during a CAPA investigation. It is thus hard for them to assess the overall quality of a transportation operation or a specific trade lane.These data could be fed into the data platform at relevant milestones during cargo movement. Ideally, the data platform should also be able to register photos or checklists, such as the IATA Acceptance Checklist.</p>
      <p>Temperature dataShippers often use data loggers that travel with the shipments. However, with passive data loggers, the information on temperature can only be collected after arrival at the destination country. Although the data would indicate any excursions, they do not indicate where they occurred along the supply chain. CEIV certified operators do monitor the temperature of their transport or storage activities, but these data are only shared in case of a CAPA investigation (CAPA: Corrective And Preventive Action).</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>acf99e</document_id>
    <url>https://lufthansa-cargo.com/documents/20184/6653033/2018-007_LHC_Industrienbroschu%E2%95%A0e%CC%82re_Pharma%2BMedizintechnik_engl.pdf/77274ea1-b560-cbfb-0dd2-7423b364c392?t=1564028151000?page=2</url>
    <title>Lufthansa Cargo: Logistics for the  healthcare industry - Page 2</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time/>
    <categories/>
    <topics/>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>An uninterrupted cold chain, continuous documenta-tion, the secure transport of valuable pharmaceuticals: the demands that the healthcare industry place on  logistics are very high – and specific. Just like the quality and diversity of the logistics solutions that we have specially customized to meet the needs of your industry. Regardless of whether you choose Care for dangerous goods, Cool for temperature-sensitive goods such as insulin or Safe1 for particularly valuable items like donor organs – our products allow you to get your life-saving cargo to its destination, on time and intact.Are you interested to see just what customized solu-tions for CT scanners, vaccines, generic drugs, donor organs, blood and plasma, and radioactive isotopes for cancer treatments can look like? Take a look at lufthansa-cargo.com/enablingglobalbusinessto see some of our customers' logistics highlights.</p>
      <p>You can count on your valuable shipments getting to their destination reliably, securely and intact, which we ensure with customized solutions, precise temperature control, the highest security standards and more.•  Special  infrastructure: a state-of-the-art Cool Center, where pharmaceutical shipments, classic perishables and temperature-controlled dangerous goods are stored separately•  Temperature-stable  transport: a temperature- controlled, optimized cold chain thanks to  significantly shorter transport routes and fewer interruptions during transfers, as well as  temperature-controlled compartments on board  most flights•  Cool  service: a range of different cooling contain-ers that can also be made available outside of flight and processing hours• Just in case: a combination of Cool together with Care, our special product for dangerous goods, which complies with the IATA Dangerous Goods Regulations•  Comprehensive  documentation: transparent pro-cesses with continuous shipment monitoring and password-protected shipment tracking in real time• Personal and competent: teams of experts ensure that pharmaceutical and medical technology ship-ments are monitored and handled appropriately</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>3e8eb0</document_id>
    <url>http://www.airlinecargo.com/hazardous-materials</url>
    <title>Hazardous Materials</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time/>
    <categories/>
    <topics/>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Airline Cargo services provides transportation solutions for various commodities of Dangerous Goods transported throughout the world, from radioactive goods to nuclear fuels,  or laboratory samples, to full air charters of explosives and ammunition, cargoes that are forbidden aboard commercial aircraft (such as grenades and rockets).</p>
      <p>ACS  extensive experience within the logistics industry with the goal of providing the best service available, preventing any delay caused by improper packaging or document discrepancy.</p>
      <p>ACS  staff maintains training and certification for IATA regulations, plus the additional training required for the certification and handling of  radioactive materials. ACS international network of cooperating partners includes agents specialized in dangerous goods handling to facilitate in transit and destination services when necessary, such as certification and packing, recertification for transshipments, pre-clearance and special delivery for shipments requiring necessary permissions or exemptions. Extensive experience and expertise ensures the transport of dangerous materials is conducted with the utmost consideration for safety and efficiency to meet our clients demands</p>
      <p>ACS COMMITMENT TO OUR CUSTOMERS NEEDS</p>
      <p>    Coordination for classification, certification, and UN Specified packaging of hazardous materials</p>
      <p>    Inspection of packaging conditions and documentation to identify discrepancy, exception, or damage</p>
      <p>    Maintain sensitive handling during retrieval, and throughout transit, to ensure a timely acceptance and prevent any possible delays or additional expenses due to repackaging</p>
      <p>    Best suited carrier and routing selection, with compliance for state and operator restrictions or variations</p>
      <p>    Separation of hazardous portions of large shipments to ensure total charges are not based on the higher fees associated with dangerous goods, while maintaining the consistent service of a single shipment</p>
      <p>    Coordination of shipments to remote destinations in countries with strict government regulations that may require advanced approval from unilateral authorities for permission to allow over flight, ground transport, or importation of dangerous goods</p>
      <p>Results:</p>
      <p>Utilizing the expertise of ACS staff and cooperation of proven reliable local and international agents, ACS arranges and coordinates all required steps, from advanced preparation through retrieval, classification, packing, shipping, and delivery of all dangerous goods commodities to their destination.</p>
      <p>Airline Cargo Services high Quality and Reliability standards are upheld, with the ultimate goal of exceeding the clients' requirements and expectations.</p>
      <p>Services Utilized:</p>
      <p>Certified dangerous goods packaging and handling agents</p>
      <p>Secure and constant surveillance, exclusive or ltl use ground transport</p>
      <p>All cargo freighter or charter flights or passenger service when allowed by applicable laws</p>
      <p>Proper segregation of incompatible dangerous goods</p>
      <p>Tracking of the goods and constant updates on status of the goods</p>
      <p>Third Party Logistics, with on-site ACS representative when necessary</p>
      <p>Prompt and thorough communication with client and consignee until delivery</p>
      <p>Hard-copy Proof of Delivery and backup documents provided as necessary</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>d614f6</document_id>
    <url>https://www.airbridgecargo.com/en/page/30/hub-in-moscow</url>
    <title>Hub in Moscow</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time/>
    <categories/>
    <topics/>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>ABC's Moscow hub at Sheremetyevo airport features state-of-the-art equipment in each warehouse, allowing for efficient, seamless and safe handling of any type of cargo - from live animals to dangerous substances and beyond.</p>
      <p>Our decision to develop our Moscow hub was an important milestone in the history of the company and a strategic step on our path to become a network carrier. Our hub network model and flight connectivity in Moscow lets our customers access connections within a 48-hour delivery time - including handling.</p>
      <p>Thanks to our hub, we can offer the following benefits</p>
      <p>20,000m² of total warehouse space and 3 GHA warehouses</p>
      <p>Dedicated pharmaceuticals warehouse and zones for cargo with special requirements (dangerous substances, temperature-sensitive shipments, etc.)</p>
      <p>24/7 surveillance</p>
      <p>99.98% safety index</p>
      <p>TAPA certified</p>
      <p>We also offer</p>
      <p>ABC aviation security division at the airport</p>
      <p>Priority SVO: Customs cleared cargo ready for pick-up within 4 hours</p>
      <p>Assistance with customs clearance</p>
      <p>Trucking services to more than 25 destinations in Russia</p>
      <p>24/7 customer service helpdesk assistance in Russian</p>
      <p>Customers with cargo destined for Russia, shipments can be delivered to any of the following warehouses at Sheremetyevo airport</p>
      <p>Moscow Cargo</p>
      <p>Sheremetyevo Cargo</p>
      <p>DHL (GOSNIIGA)</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>320629</document_id>
    <url>https://www.nac.aero/specialized-shipping/</url>
    <title>Specialized Shipping</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time/>
    <categories/>
    <topics/>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Certain items must be prepared following specific criteria for shipment prior to drop off. Please see the instructions below.</p>
      <p>Fish, Game and Hunting Gear Shipments</p>
      <p>When shipping your seafood, meat and gear with Northern Air Cargo, please use the following guidelines:</p>
      <p>All meat, seafood and gear must be picked up within 12 hours from the arrival time into Anchorage. Shipments not picked up during this time will be subject to storage charges of $.75 per 100 lbs. per day.</p>
      <p>All items in the shipment must have names, addresses, phone numbers and be labeled clearly if they are chilled or frozen.</p>
      <p>Please, DO NOT mix meat or seafood with gear.</p>
      <p>Seafood, meat and horns are the shipper's risk.</p>
      <p>During peak seasons, every effort will be made to accommodate your frozen and chilled shipments while awaiting recovery by the consignee in Anchorage.</p>
      <p>Frozen and Chilled space is limited due to high shipping volumes during peak hunting season.</p>
      <p>Please be aware that most of our agents do not have frozen and chilled facilities.</p>
      <p>Prior arrangements must be made by the shipper for meat being released to meat processors (please indicate their name and phone number at the time of shipping).</p>
      <p>Out of state checks will not be accepted.</p>
      <p>We accept Visa, Mastercard and Discover.</p>
      <p>Live Animal Shipments</p>
      <p>The following guidelines must be adhered to when accepting live animals (specifically dogs and cats) for shipment on Northern Air Cargo:</p>
      <p>The shipper must make arrangements in advance with NAC to ensure adequate space exists on the flight to accommodate live animal shipments.</p>
      <p>Animals must not be tendered for shipment more than four hours prior to scheduled departure time of the intended flight.</p>
      <p>The shipper must provide a contact phone number so that NAC may notify them in the event of a flight cancellation or overflight and they can retrieve the animals from NAC, pending the next available flight to the destination. A phone number for the consignee is required on the air waybill.</p>
      <p>All live animal shipments must be prepaid.</p>
      <p>The shipper must guarantee any additional charges in writing, on the air waybill.</p>
      <p>All animals must be healthy and show no signs of illness or abnormal distress. All federal, state or local health regulations must be met with regards to vaccinations and proof of them.</p>
      <p>Animals must be shipped in an approved airline type kennel or other suitable container which meets the standards of an approved container with regard to: ventilation, postural movement (sit up, stand up, turn, lie down), security (animal will not escape the kennel), protection of the animal, prevention of leakage. Non-airline type kennels must be approved at the time of acceptance by a lead supervisor.</p>
      <p>Animals are restricted to one adult animal per kennel or two puppies/kittens. No dog or cat will be accepted for transportation unless older than eight weeks and weaned. Puppies are defined as over eight-weeks-old and less than six-months, not to exceed 20 lbs. Puppies/kittens shipped in the same kennel must be of comparable size and weight.</p>
      <p>Animals not claimed within 4 hours of arrival at destination will be boarded in a suitable kennel. All charges for this service will be the responsibility of the consignee and/or the shipper.</p>
      <p>Animals not claimed within 48 hours of arrival at destination will be returned to the shipper at the shipper's expense (including cost of food and upkeep). Shipper must guarantee all charges, in writing on the air waybill.</p>
      <p>Requests for declared value for live animal shipments must be approved by the Claims Department or a manager.</p>
      <p>Hazardous Materials</p>
      <p>The shipper must declare all hazardous materials, such as propane, white gas, small arms ammunition, bear spray, aerosol cans, etc. All camp stoves, lanterns and tanks must be empty of any fuel. All boat motors and boat motor tanks must be empty of fuel. ATVs should be drained of fuel.</p>
      <p>Please note: Firearms cannot be loaded with ammunition and are required to be in a locked case.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>44dbe7</document_id>
    <url>https://au.kuehne-nagel.com/en_gb/industry-solutions/pharma-healthcare/</url>
    <title>KN PharmaChain -  For when it matters the most.</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time/>
    <categories/>
    <topics/>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>You need a strong partner that you can rely on to manage your logistic complexity on a global level. You need to deliver your pharmaceutical and healthcare products to locations all over the world on a tight schedule.</p>
      <p>And you need your products to arrive in perfect condition and fully compliant to global and local regulations. You can trust us to be that partner.</p>
      <p>We simplify the complexity</p>
      <p>We handle every part of the logistics chain as one single company, regardless of the mode of transportation, storage or compliance level needed. In your daily operations, this translates into dedicated account managers who have full oversight of your entire logistic chain, from supplier to end customer. They stand by your side to plan efficient end-to-end solutions that deliver at the highest level of precision and reliability.</p>
      <p>For you, this means that we consolidate and optimize your logistics operations and simplify the complexity, so that you can focus on what matters the most to you and to your end customers.</p>
      <p>KN PharmaCHain - We understand your specific requirements</p>
      <p>We understand your specific requiremements</p>
      <p>As you bring your portfolio of products to customers and patients across the world, you face a number of varying compliance requirements and delivery-relevant needs. By relying on our advanced Lane Risk Assessment data and our deep industry expertise, we guide you into finding the most efficient and suitable logistic setup for each shipment.</p>
      <p>For you that means that we customize solutions that successfully complete each individual shipment, always placing the integrity of the product first.</p>
      <p>KN PharmaChain - Right level of compliance</p>
      <p>We deliver the right level of compliance</p>
      <p>With KN PharmaChain we can answer to both standard and advanced compliance requirements. Our global network operates at every compliance level with currently 194 GxP certified operations all over the world.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, our team of highly trained experts can stand by 24/7/365 to monitor and support your shipments through digital applications and thorough supervision.</p>
      <p>For you this means that you can be confident that your products will arrive at their destination with the required compliance level, proven by the right documentation.</p>
      <p>KN PharmaChain spokesman Jon Chapman</p>
      <p>"For six years, we have committed ourselves to develop, adapt and test KN PharmaChain to assure the integrity of your products throughout their journey."</p>
      <p>Jon Chapman</p>
      <p>Head of Operations for KN PharmaChain</p>
      <p>KN PharmaChain - We operate globally</p>
      <p>We operate with precision, globally.</p>
      <p>Our KN PharmaChain network is fully operated by us and continuously audited and expanded. Our global standardized processes are relentlessly tried, tested and developed. And our experts keep building their expertise to ensure and advance KN PharmaChain.</p>
      <p>For you, this means that you can trust us to take the responsibility for the full logistical needs of all the products in your portfolio.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>d56727</document_id>
    <url>http://www.cathaypacificcargo.com/Default.aspx?tabid=138</url>
    <title>Pharma LIFT</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time/>
    <categories/>
    <topics/>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>There are many reasons to ship high value pharmaceutical products across Asia or around the world. We understand the potential costs in lives and dollars if they don't arrive in perfect condition. Pharma LIFT is a comprehensive range of specialised and professional air cargo services for temperature sensitive shipments designed to meet your needs.</p>
      <p>Why Choose Cathay?</p>
      <p>Embrace a Pharma LIFT culture</p>
      <p>Precious cargo such as pharmaceuticals needs special care. We provide this with specialised services, tailor-made solutions and dedicated support for Pharma LIFT.</p>
      <p>Product Features</p>
      <p>Service Description</p>
      <p>Embrace a Pharma LIFT culture</p>
      <p>Pharmaceuticals save lives. We handle each shipment with special care</p>
      <p>Active container – supported by Envirotainer and CSafe</p>
      <p>Provides reliable cold chain solutions for your temperature sensitive cargo</p>
      <p>Thermal Dolly</p>
      <p>Temperature controlled dolly, protecting shipment from extreme heat on tarmac at Hong Kong International Airport</p>
      <p>24/7</p>
      <p>Support from the Hong Kong Pharma LIFT team</p>
      <p>Multiple CCP</p>
      <p>Multiple Critical Control Points(CCP) at each shipping point</p>
      <p>Automatic communication system</p>
      <p>Automatic pre-alert system when an active container temperature reading reaches a specific threshold for preventive action</p>
      <p>Online temperature tracking</p>
      <p>Online temperature tracking for Active Pharma and Heat and Cooling Pharma at your fingertips</p>
      <p>Approved wireless sensor devices</p>
      <p>• 7Solutions GD100, GL200, GL300W, and EMN Probe</p>
      <p>• CAL/AMP SC1102</p>
      <p>• Cartasen</p>
      <p>• Controlant CO 10.01</p>
      <p>• Hanhaa ParceLive</p>
      <p>• iCHIME</p>
      <p>• ILC2000</p>
      <p>• Intelyt iTAG</p>
      <p>• Kirsen A-Type device</p>
      <p>• LogTag TRIX-8</p>
      <p>• LogTag USRIC-8 &amp; USRIC-16</p>
      <p>• Q-tag CLm doc</p>
      <p>• RoamBee: 2G-3G Bee</p>
      <p>• Sendum PT300, PT300D</p>
      <p>• SenseAware</p>
      <p>• Sensitech TempTale Ultra</p>
      <p>• Sentry 400 FlightSafe</p>
      <p>• Sentry 500 FlightSafe</p>
      <p>• Tempsen iTAG3 Pro</p>
      <p>• Tempsen Tempod SP</p>
      <p>• TempTale4 USB &amp; USB Dry Ice</p>
      <p>Priority handling on tarmac</p>
      <p>Speedy ground logistics avoiding prolonged exposure to unsuitable ambient temperatures</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>a4c95c</document_id>
    <url>https://www.airbridgecargo.com/files/flipbook/pharma_brochure19_EN_05Aug19_online.pdf?page=2</url>
    <title>AirBridgeCargo abc pharma - Page 2</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time/>
    <categories/>
    <topics/>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>At  AirBridgeCargo,  we  understand  your  mission  to  help  people  live  longer,  happier  and  healthier  lives.  We  are  experts  when  it  comes  to  transporting  temperature-sensitive  pharmaceuticals  and  life-saving  medical  equipment  across  the  globe.  From  vaccines,  laboratory equipment, MRI machines to blood samples and beyond. AirBridgeCargo is your partner with an in-depth knowledge of the healthcare and pharma-ceutical industry. When a cool chain has to span across continents, you can count on our cargo experts and modern freighter fleet to make it happen. Always. Worldwide.Logistic solutions based on your needs• Dedicated, highly skilled staff trained in handling healthcare products• Boeing 747-8 and 747-400 with three compartments enabling different temperaturesettings from 4°C to 29°C• Full compliance with IATA TCR and CEIV Pharma• Exact temperature monitoring from acceptance to delivery• Special packaging solutions and thermal blankets for palletized shipments• Customer service support, online track &amp; trace option for all shipments• High-tech hub at Moscow Sheremetyevo International Airport with effective connec-tions to deliver cargo worldwide• Tailor-made logistics solutions based on your individual requirements• QEP Envirotainer accredited network of ABC stations• Adoption of the latest digital technologies (Sky Fresh for data collecting,temperature data loggers to monitor ambient environment, etc)• Sophisticated, cohesive and forward-thinking approach based on peer learning and networking through industry-related initiatives - Pharma Aero, Pharma Gateway Amsterdam (PGA) and othersAirBridgeCargo  operates  one  of  the  youngest  freighter  fleets  in  the  air  cargo  industry,  consisting of state-of-the-art Boeing aircraft.Our freighter fleet offers pharma customers multiple benefits• Three independently selectable temperature zones• Selectable target temperature range from 4°C to 29°C for each cargo compartment• Independent temperature control between main deck, FWD lower deck and AFT lower deck• Fast temperature pull down times after takeoff• 'GoGreen' strategy – low levels of CO2 emissions• State-of-the-art widebody aircraft in the air cargo industry• Most  suitable  positions  for  termperature-sensitive  cargo  transportation  based  on  temperature mapping of both aircraft typesOur Moscow hub that redefines what's possibleAirBridgeCargo's  Moscow  hub  at  Sheremetyevo  airport  features  brand  new  equipment  in  each warehouse, allowing for an efficient and seamless handling of healthcare goods. Thanks to our hub, we can offer the following benefits• 70,300m2 of total warehouse space at 2 GHA`s warehouses• Warehouse with dedicated storage area for pharmaceutical products• Enhanced security measures with 24/7 surveillance• First automated cargo handling system in Russia with 3D cargo handling on several levels• 99,98% safety index, TAPA certified</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>f6260c</document_id>
    <url>https://www.airbridgecargo.com/files/flipbook/pharma_brochure19_EN_05Aug19_online.pdf?page=5</url>
    <title>AirBridgeCargo abc pharma - Page 5</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time/>
    <categories/>
    <topics/>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>AirBridgeCargo is  the  leading  all-cargo  carrier  in  Russia  that  operates  among  the  top  ten  international cargo airlines worldwide.Quality focus• IATA and IOSA certified, full compliance with all international/internal safety guidelines and quality standards (Cargo iQ)• Member of Cool Chain Association• IATA CEIV (pharma) and QEP certified stations • Qualified and certified team of logistics practitioners for transportation of general and special cargoes• 24/7/365 Control Tower (CT) operation to monitor and manage transportation of special cargo consignmentsSpecial attentionfor special cargoCONTROL TOWERAirBridgeCargo Airlines has established a new 24/7/365 Control Tower (CT) operation to monitor consignments of special cargoes and to proactively respond to service disruptions to ensure it consistently meets customers' delivery deadlines. Managed by a team of fully trained supply chain specialists and based in Moscow, HQ the Control Tower provides:• real-time, round-the-clock monitoring of all cargo movements throughout the entire transportation process across ABC's network• checkup of ABC's fleet technical condition (temperature control system, cargo handling system readiness)• schedule alignment and control for priority delivery of special cargo• communication with ABC specialists from different departments and customers in case of deviations for prompt response• cargo status updates and reports • CT personnel availability 24/7 via e-mail, skype or direct phone lineAchievements and advantages• More than 15 years of consecutive growth• Over 30 airfreight destinations with effective connectivity options through hub in Moscow and 48 hour delivery time• 1,300 cargo professionals worldwide• Customized logistics solutions for transportation of general and special cargo• State-of-the-art Boeing 747 fleet• Logistics solutions, complemented by the extensive network of ABC interline  partners and trucking companies worldwide</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>942781</document_id>
    <url>https://csafeglobal.com/why-csafe/</url>
    <title>Why CSafe</title>
    <author/>
    <published_time/>
    <categories/>
    <topics/>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Temperature assured. Life enhanced. Safeguarding life's most vital temperatures</p>
      <p>There's no room for error in life-science cold chain logistics, and stable, precise temperature control is critical in maintaining the quality of vital, life-enhancing products during storage and transport. No company knows this better, or does it better, than CSafe—the true partner in cold chain packaging offering you the most reliable protection against temperature excursions.</p>
      <p>Delivering best-in-class packaging solutions for life-enhancing products</p>
      <p>CSafe is the industry's only provider of a full line of both active and passive cold chain packaging solutions, designed to ensure the integrity of the world's most advanced temperature-sensitive products. Our comprehensive portfolio of temperature-control solutions can accommodate any customer need and is backed by unparalleled customer service, rapid-response technical support, rigorous system testing and validation, and an industry-leading preventive maintenance program (PMR).</p>
      <p>That's why more customers trust CSafe as an indispensable cold chain partner for all of their temperature-management needs—and why you should too. It's our commitment to you that, no matter where you ship your precious, life-enhancing products, they will be kept safe and stable with CSafe's best-in-class cold chain packaging solutions.</p>
      <p>ThermoCor® VIP insulation: the core of cold chain packaging innovation</p>
      <p>The superior performance of CSafe's range of active and passive packaging solutions is driven by the unmatched insulating efficiency of our proprietary ThermoCor® Vacuum-Insulated Panels (VIP). Backed by nearly 4 decades of research, innovation, and manufacturing, ThermoCor® VIP boasts highly efficient insulating properties that translate into longer hold times, reduced power and stored energy consumption, and superior temperature control, even in the most extreme ambient environments.</p>
      <p>ThermoCor® VIP achieves nearly 10 times greater thermal protection than other commonly used insulation materials</p>
      <p>ThermoCor® achieves far superior thermal efficiency compared to commonly used packaging insulation</p>
      <p>* R-value is a measure of resistance to heat flow through a given thickness of material. Materials with a higher R-value possess greater thermal resistance and, therefore, superior insulating properties.</p>
      <p>ThermoCor® remains the least conductive insulation material in the packaging industry</p>
      <p>* W/mK, also referred to as "K value," is a measure of thermal conductivity, or the rate of heat transfer in a homogeneous material. Materials with a lower K value transfer less heat and provide superior insulating properties.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
</corpus>
