<corpus>
  <document>
    <document_id>287830</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/working-from-home-can-be-tricky-for-freight-firms-with-onsite-only-tech/</url>
    <title>'Working from home' can be tricky for freight firms with 'onsite-only' tech</title>
    <author>Sam Whelan</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:28:13+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Cogoport</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Digital freight forwarder</topic>
      <topic>Flexport</topic>
      <topic>freight forwarders</topic>
      <topic>FreightBro</topic>
      <topic>Kontainers</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Forwarders and carriers are being stretched to the limit by lockdowns and quarantines sweeping the globe, forcing large-scale remote working and reduced resources.</p>
      <p>And Flemming Frost, president of digital freight marketplace Cogoport, believes remote working will “hurt more” than many realise – “Even among the big players,” he told The Loadstar.</p>
      <p>“I spoke with a top 10 carrier and it is down on resources across many locations, as such staff are flat-out to just keep the daily business together.”</p>
      <p>While investment into freight-tech and digitalisation has been a hot industry topic in recent years, many logistics firms are likely ill-prepared to operate efficiently under “work from home” conditions.</p>
      <p>“The lack of tech and automation means many processes are ‘band-aided’ by ‘human APIs’, and when the humans are either away from work or ill-equipped to work from alternative locations, that will hurt,” explained Mr Frost.</p>
      <p>“A check with a small forwarder gave me the same impression – half the staff are at the office and the rest can only work at half-capacity due to an inability to access all the required material and systems from outside the office.”</p>
      <p>According to Mark Yong, MD for Asia Pacific at multimodal digital supply chain platform Blume Global, many freight companies still rely on legacy systems which can only be operated onsite, due to network security.</p>
      <p>“Medium-size companies are probably suffering the most, as they don’t have adequate tools,” he noted.</p>
      <p>Seko Logistics announced remote working at its global headquarters in Chicago this week. Group commercial director Keith Gaskin said the industry needed to embrace digital transformation at a quicker pace.</p>
      <p>“That includes the archaic bill of lading process,” he said, “especially in times like this when a piece of paper is often still needed to exchange hands [which] is crazy.</p>
      <p>“There are obviously alternatives, but from some regions, L/Cs still stipulate multiple copies of the bills need to be presented. Hard to do if an office is in lockdown or the post office/courier services are unable to work.”</p>
      <p>Flexport, meanwhile, is looking to collaborate, according to CEO Ryan Petersen, who explained: “If you work at a customs brokerage or freight forwarder that can’t maintain operations because of your IT set up, please reach out.</p>
      <p>“This is a crucial time for us to all help each other to keep supply chains moving, especially as there may be life-saving goods in some of these shipments.”</p>
      <p>However, one customs broker said: “We are fully equipped to work remotely with zero service interruptions. Most brokers are.”</p>
      <p>Perhaps sensing a need for greater digital capabilities among forwarders, freight-tech companies Kontainers and FreightBro both announced this week that new users could temporarily access their respective products free of charge.</p>
      <p>Similarly, Australian firm A2B Solution Group, a service partner of the Cargowise One platform, said it had developed an “essential workflow package that will allow your staff to work from home within 24 hours of engagement”.</p>
      <p>“Best of all,” A2B added, “the implementation package comes with a company specific guide and a free roll of toilet paper.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>44bd0b</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/services/charter-company/ceva-logistics-operates-charters-to-maintain-asia-us-supply-chain/</url>
    <title>CEVA Logistics operates charters to maintain Asia-US supply chain</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T10:27:08+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>services</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>CEVA Logistics</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>CEVA Logistics has contracted 86 freighter flights to help maintain the global supply chain as the coronavirus outbreak continues.</p>
      <p>The company is using the aircraft on a charter basis to deliver parts and supplies to its customers in the automotive, aerospace, computer and hi-tech electronics sectors.</p>
      <p>The majority of flights served routes between Asia (Hong Kong, Shanghai, Bangkok and Singapore) and the US (Dallas, Rockford, Rickenbacker). Other charters served European cities, such as Amsterdam and Brussels.</p>
      <p>CEVA has already operated more than 58 flights – to transport more than 7,700 tonnes or airfreight – to provide urgent stock replenishment for those which could not otherwise be supplied.</p>
      <p>Over the next few weeks, it will operate 28 more charter flights.</p>
      <p>Guillaume Col, CEVA Logistics’ chief operating officer, commented: “Working extremely closely with our customers, we have been able to deliver a robust charter programme to adapt to these difficult circumstances.</p>
      <p>“Acting in close collaboration with the rest of the CMA CGM Group, we are striving to offer fast and accessible alternatives to our clients throughout the world in order to help keep the global economy moving.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>236fd3</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/factories-switch-production-to-boost-medical-supplies-to-fight-covid-19/</url>
    <title>Factories switch production to boost medical supplies to fight Covid-19</title>
    <author>Alex Lennane</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:29:00+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Flexport</topic>
      <topic>Humanitarian logistics</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Growing numbers of companies are changing tack, shelving production of normal wares to make hand sanitiser and other medical products.</p>
      <p>Some forwarders, meanwhile, are offering to ship them.</p>
      <p>French luxury group LMVH has switched its luxury perfumes for sanitiser, while small gin distilleries across the UK and Ireland and France’s Pernod Ricard have also stepped in as alcohol supplies in Europe dwindle.</p>
      <p>Flow Water Technologies has offered to supply the Cyprus government with disinfectant free of charge, after it ramped up production of disinfectant compound sodium hypochlorite. It is now capable of making five cubic metres of high-concentrate a day, the equivalent of 60 cubic metres of sanitiser.</p>
      <p>“We have taken the joint decision to put aside our immediate commercial objectives and help assist with the national fight against Covid-19 infection escalation,” said chief executive Mark Hadfield.</p>
      <p>“Cyprus imports chemicals, but it will soon run out. As Flow Water Technologies BWMS solution holds a Cyprus biocide licence for the emergency services, the moral obligation was clear.”</p>
      <p>But it’s not just manufacturers looking to help the fight against coronavirus.</p>
      <p>Flexport.org is to export thousands of coronavirus test kits from Asian suppliers to the US west coast, but added that it had “limited resources to pay for all of these and other urgently needed supplies for the healthcare system”, and called for donations.</p>
      <p>It said: “It’s time to punch back, join humanity’s counterattack by making a tax-deductible donation. 100% of your money will go toward buying and shipping critical products for the world’s healthcare systems in this time of need.”</p>
      <p>Another forwarder, on LinkedIn, commented: “I proudly work for a rival company, but I absolutely applaud these efforts as we all need to work together, especially in the logistics/supply chain community.”</p>
      <p>You can help: click here.</p>
      <p>If you know of any businesses providing humanitarian or charitable services, please let us know and we will help promote it.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>f54ca1</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/record-shipment-for-wfs-new-paris-pharma-centre/</url>
    <title>Record shipment for WFS’ new Paris Pharma Centre</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T15:17:24+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Latest News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>Paris Charles de Gaulle Airport</topic>
      <topic>pharma centre</topic>
      <topic>WFS Pharma Centre</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Worldwide Flight Services’ new Pharma Centre at Paris Charles de Gaulle Airport has handled its biggest single shipment so far – 34 temperature-controlled containers for customers AirBridgeCargo Airlines and Kuehne + Nagel.</p>
      <p>The outbound shipment, which was destined for Beijing, spent 24-48 hours at the Pharma Centre where it was maintained within 2-8 degrees Celsius, before being sent to China on a Boeing 747 freighter.</p>
      <p>AirBridgeCargo has been a regular customer of WFS’ IATA CEIV certified Pharma Centre since the €10 million facility opened in the second half of 2019. To confirm compliance with its own requirements, Kuehne + Nagel also conducted its own audit of the Centre before commencing shipments.</p>
      <p>WFS’ Pharma Centre is the only dedicated facility at Paris CDG, the second largest air cargo gateway in Europe. The centre offers temperature-controlled warehousing and handling services as well as a transport fleet specifically adapted to guarantee the integrity of pharmaceutical shipments. Already, some 30 airlines and freight forwarders are using the Pharma Centre regularly to support their strict pharma product requirements, and WFS expects the operation to process over 8,000 tonnes of healthcare and life science products in 2020.</p>
      <p>Hugo Rodrigues, vice president of cargo in France at WFS, has commented that: “Our decision to invest in this state-of-the-art facility to support our airline and freight forwarder customers, as well as the pharmaceutical industry, has already been validated by the strong demand we are seeing from so many different organisations. This particular shipment for AirBridgeCargo and Kuehne + Nagel was the biggest so far and helped to demonstrate the capabilities of both the facility and our team. With the need for pharma products all over the globe likely to soar in 2020, we will deliver the capacity and quality of service our customers need to ensure the integrity and efficiency of their pharma supply chains.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>b0f91e</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/freight-forwarder/ups-achieves-ceiv-pharma-in-singapore/</url>
    <title>UPS achieves CEIV pharma in Singapore</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T12:20:02+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>freight-forwarder</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>UPS</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>The UPS freight forwarding operation at Changi Airport has received IATA CEIV Pharma certification for pharmaceutical logistics — a first for UPS in Asia Pacific.</p>
      <p>IATA’s CEIV Pharma certification is an industry certification developed by IATA, regulators and aviation industry stakeholders.</p>
      <p>The certification requires companies to meet or exceed many existing pharmaceutical standards and guidelines such as IATA Temperature Control Regulations, European Union Good Distribution Practices, World Health Organisation Annex 5 Good Distribution Practices for Pharmaceutical Products and United States Pharmacopeia Standards.</p>
      <p>“Pharmaceuticals are time and temperature-sensitive, requiring an extra amount of care throughout the transportation process. These are not typical packages, and at times life-saving deliveries as well. This certification is an affirmation of the high standards of handling and transportation that UPS’s customers in the healthcare and life sciences sector have come to rely on for their high-value shipments,” said Lim Bee Koong, director, healthcare strategy, UPS Asia Pacific.</p>
      <p>As a biomedical sciences hub for the Asia Pacific region, Singapore is home to eight of the top 10 pharmaceutical companies globally, manufacturing four of the top 10 drugs by global revenue.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>f6c93b</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/keeping-cargo-flowing-will-save-lives-and-may-avoid-airline-bankruptcies/</url>
    <title>Keeping cargo flowing 'will save lives' – and may avoid airline bankruptcies</title>
    <author>Alex Lennane</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T14:26:55+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>airlines</topic>
      <topic>bankruptcy</topic>
      <topic>Bankruptcy Blues</topic>
      <topic>CAPA</topic>
      <topic>ERA</topic>
      <topic>IATA</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Most of the world’s airlines could be bankrupt in just 10 weeks, according to analysis by Capa.</p>
      <p>The analyst, however, noted this was a “catastrophe” that could be avoided, with coordinated government and industry action.</p>
      <p>And as if on cue, IATA stepped up to call on governments to facilitate freighter and freight-only flights.</p>
      <p>In a rare show of concern for cargo, IATA director general Alexandre de Juniac urged governments to “take urgent measures to ensure vital supply lines remain open, efficient and effective”.</p>
      <p>IATA outlined five ways in which they could support the industry: exclude air cargo operations from any Covid-19-related travel restrictions; ensure that standardised measures are in place so that air cargo can continue to move around the world with minimal disruption; exempt air cargo crew members who do not interact with the public from 14-day quarantine requirements; support temporary traffic rights for cargo operations where restrictions may apply; remove economic impediments, such as overfly charges, parking fees and slot restrictions.</p>
      <p>Arguing that air freight was one way to fight Covid-19, Mr de Juniac added: “Air cargo carriers are working closely with governments and health organisations around the world to safeguard public health while also keeping the global economy moving. Today, as we fight a global health war, governments must take urgent action to facilitate air cargo. Keeping cargo flowing will save lives.”</p>
      <p>The European Regions Airlines Association (ERA) also waded in.</p>
      <p>“Legislation, directives and guidance aimed at air passenger operations and the protection of air passengers on commercial flights, does not specifically exempt cargo flights and cargo flight crews.</p>
      <p>“At this moment, some states require that when a cargo flight returns to a country following minimal ground time as part of the turnaround process in a high-risk area, even if the crew do not leave the aircraft, effectively never leaving the territory of the aircraft registration and never entering the country in which they landed, they will be subject to 14 days of mandatory isolation. If this is to continue, airlines will quickly run out of flight crew to continue operations.”</p>
      <p>Atlas Air’s crew have already said they were worried about getting to work, a commute which tends to involve catching passenger flights.</p>
      <p>Capa explained that some airlines may already be technically bankrupt – or “at least substantially in breach of debt covenants”, while cash reserves, it said, “are running down quickly”.</p>
      <p>It added: “Demand is drying up in ways that are completely unprecedented. Normality is not yet on the horizon.”</p>
      <p>Capa said governments were sending mixed messages and there was “little instinct to act cooperatively”.</p>
      <p>“Each nation is adopting the solution that appears best suited to it, right or wrong, without consideration of its neighbours or trading partners,” it noted, adding that President Trump’s unilateral overnight travel ban was a case in point.</p>
      <p>“The fear is that, as a collapsed airline system is reconstituted, similar national self-interest will prevail. That’s important because the aviation industry is about much more than airline health. It is crucial to global communications and trade.”</p>
      <p>Capa blames foreign ownership rules, unionisation and cabotage rules for what is now a “fragmented and largely unviable airline industry”.</p>
      <p>“As things stand, the likely tepid response to the airline crisis will equally be fragmented and nationally based. It will consist mostly of bailing out selected national airlines.</p>
      <p>“If that is the default position, emerging from the crisis will be like entering a brutal battlefield, littered with casualties.” And it said, this could be a unique time to re-write the rules.</p>
      <p>You can read the full article here – it’s well worth it.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>544d4e</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/freighter-operator/air-partner-expects-charter-market-surge/</url>
    <title>Air Partner expects charter market surge</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-16T17:36:59+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Partner</topic>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Charter broker Air Partner has urged companies to book cargo transport early to keep supply chains moving in light of the coronavirus.</p>
      <p>The company said that it has reported a spike in demand while capacity is in short supply as passenger airlines have axed services.</p>
      <p>Air Partner chief executive Mark Briffa said: “We’re seeing a spike in airfreight service requests as many commercial flights are being grounded and at a time when Chinese industrial production is restarting after a month-long shutdown. There is still immediate charter availability, but we foresee that could change in the coming weeks.”</p>
      <p>The broker said that is has access to any freight aircraft between North America and Europe or between North America and China, or South East Asia, “at a moment’s notice”.</p>
      <p>“If availability does decrease, prices will surge,” it warned. “As such, to reduce risk and guarantee availability, Air Partner recommends companies secure aircraft charter solutions as soon as they are needed.”</p>
      <p>It warned that freight rates from China have already begun to increase as demand increases.</p>
      <p>Figures from the latest TAC Index show airfreight prices from Shanghai to North America increased by 32.3% from a week earlier to $4.02 per kg, while prices from the Chinese city to Europe jumped by 15.8% compared with the prior seven days to $2.71 per kg.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, prices from Hong Kong to North America increased by 11.5% week on week to $3.59 per kg and there was a 3.2% increase to $2.58 per kg on services to Europe.</p>
      <p>On the capacity side, Air Partner warned that the US travel ban for Europeans would cause an immediate negative impact on availability and significant increase in pricing for cargo capacity to Europe for at least 30 days.</p>
      <p>For China, it said available cargo capacity from China is down 39% versus last year and flight cancellations on routes to China have removed close to 5,000 tons per day of capacity, with belly capacity down by 85% and maindeck capacity down by 12%.</p>
      <p>It added that more than 40 airlines have temporarily suspended operations to and from China to-date and this is likely to continue to rise with no estimated date to recommence commercial airline operations.</p>
      <p>“With China beginning to slowly ramp up production again, it will take some time for scheduled freight operators to readjust their capacities to normal schedule,” the broker said. </p>
      <p>“During the coronavirus outbreak, Air Partner has seen a large increase in urgent freight requests from companies seeking to transport a number of different commodities between North America, Asia and Europe.” </p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>1420b2</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/ad-hoc-slot-allocation-at-amsterdam-airport-schiphol-eased-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>Ad hoc slot allocation at Amsterdam Airport Schiphol eased</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T11:44:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Amsterdam Airport Schiphol’s (AMS) slot procedure has changed after Airport Coordination Netherlands (ACNL) temporarily lifted the Local Rule 2 (LR2) due to the global COVID-19 outbreak.</p>
      <p>The purpose of LR2 at AMS is to provide sufficient ad hoc capacity for full freighter airlines, but ACNL said in the current “exceptional circumstance” caused by the COVID-19 outbreak, LR2 works “counter-productively”.</p>
      <p>Under LR2, the number of slots available for reallocation is limited, but the temporary lifting of the rule frees up freight operations.</p>
      <p>“In these difficult times, it is important that we work together to ensure that the supply chain keeps moving,” said Bart Pouwels, Head of Cargo, Amsterdam Airport Schiphol.</p>
      <p>“The lifting of LR2 will enable us to operate temporarily more ad hoc full-freighter flights at AMS, which is much needed to offset the current decline in belly capacity.”</p>
      <p>Effective immediately, ACNL will not use LR2 for ad-hoc slots to be allocated up to and including 6th June 2020.</p>
      <p>In addition, slots which have been handed back to the slot coordinator by passenger carriers who are not using them, are to be offered to full freighter operators first on an ad hoc basis until 6th June 2020.</p>
      <p>ACNL said that due to the proposed temporary 80/20 waiver, which required airlines to use 80% of their slots or risk losing them, it expects a large number of slots to be handed back.</p>
      <p>With this decision ACNL is aiming to provide sufficient slots in line with the purpose of LR2 and so that the necessary freight capacity is maintained in the general interest for goods transported to/from the Netherlands.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>225a30</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/sita-uld-care-propose-blockchain-use-to-digitally-track-and-record-change-in-uld-journey-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>SITA, ULD Care propose blockchain use to digitally track and record change in ULD journey</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T14:12:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>SITA and trade association ULD Care hope to bring new efficiency to the air cargo industry by exploring the use of blockchain to digitally track and record change of custody of airline cargo containers or Unit Load Devices (ULDs) across their journey.</p>
      <p>By eliminating inefficiency, embedding always-on tracking of ULDs and abandoning redundant paper systems, the use of blockchain is expected to save the industry $400m a year in improved efficiency, fewer losses and prevention of damage. The proposed platform also offers a wide range of authentication and trust-based benefits, reducing the risk of tampering, cybercrime, trade-based money laundering, fraud, and illicit trade.</p>
      <p>Bob Rogers, vice president and treasurer, ULD Care, said, “Air cargo represents only 1 percent of all global trade in terms of volume but accounts for 35 percent of the total trade value and the inefficiency is significant. A container traveling from Shanghai to Long Beach could take up to 30 days to finish its journey, but the true travel time on sea or road is only around 15 days, with the remaining time spent on back-office and paperwork. The use of blockchain could revolutionize that process.”</p>
      <p>Today more than 800 million ULDs are in use by airlines yet the system used to track these ULDs has only been partial digitalized and relies on incomplete data sharing and record keeping.</p>
      <p>The proposed blockchain system improves efficiency by making use of all data points across the air cargo journey and provides a platform that aggregates and processes the ULD data in a trusted and secure way. The PoC will extend and upgrade the current ULD interlining platform to include non-airline third parties such as ground handlers via open APIs and a new modern interface. The results will transform the industry by lifting the veil on a myriad of previously unknown factors like damage reports. Knowing the location of all ULD’s (and therefore cargo) at all times means companies can accurately track where loss or damage occurs and recover the costs without dispute.</p>
      <p>For any given shipment there can be up to 12 custodian companies monitoring and tracking the cargo, with many relying on paper documents making the process cumbersome and undermined by trust and transparency issues. Blockchain presents a near-perfect solution to address these industry pain points with huge time and cost-saving potential.</p>
      <p>Matthys Serfontein, president of Air Travel Solutions for SITA said: “We are looking at blockchain very closely and we’re excited to test the potential of the technology to transform the air cargo industry. Beyond cargo and across the air transport industry we see huge potential for blockchain to address common challenges. The biggest obstacles standing in the way of a seamless passenger journey and truly efficient air travel, are the siloed processes across the many stakeholders, including airlines, airports, ground handlers and control authorities. They act as significant speed bumps at every step of the way.”</p>
      <p>This project forms part of SITA’s Global Blockchain Alliance which is leading exploration into blockchain’s potential for the air transport industry. SITA’s role, as the air transport community’s IT provider, is to provide governance for the global alliance, support the working groups, deliver all required blockchain technology components and ensure proper alignment and validation with regulators and international standardization bodies.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>91d1fb</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/cargoguide-launches-new-online-rate-management-platform-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>Cargoguide launches new online rate management platform</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T15:50:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Cargoguide has officially unveiled its new online rate management platform, as part of its mission to simplify rate management and boost global freight forwarding.</p>
      <p>The new platform is a feature-rich search engine for the freight forwarding sector and enables forwarders to meet the key challenges they face in their day-to-day sales operations by increasing transparency and efficiency.</p>
      <p>It builds on the success of its predecessor Cargo Office. The new Cargoguide enables forwarders to compare accurate air freight rates including surcharges, create better rate calculations by including detailed shipment information in the search, create and send custom quotes quickly and easily from within the system and track and manage sales opportunities.</p>
      <p>Cargoguide already works with more than 1,500 forwarders in over 84 countries. Compared to traditional paper-based and scattered digital spreadsheets, Cargoguide allows users to save an average of two hours per day. In addition, as a cloud-based solution, it has no installation time. It can be used to work remotely and provides up-to-date rates and flight schedules. Allowing for simplified rate management, enhanced productivity and ultimately increasing margins.</p>
      <p>Bas van der Putten, growth manager, Cargoguide said, “We believe the freight forwarding process should be transparent, neutral and conducted within a fair market. Cargoguide is the next step in helping make that a reality.</p>
      <p>“This is an exciting time for us and for digital technology in the wider freight forwarding sector. It is however a challenging time for many freight forwarders and carriers, as they look to meet the demands of modern customers while remaining competitive.”</p>
      <p>“That's where Cargoguide can add real value. We understand that forwarders and carriers need a platform that connects them through rates and that is continuously innovating and growing with them. The transparent rate calculations and accuracy of Cargoguide's data is unique and truly sets us apart from other platforms.”</p>
      <p>Jorre Cobelens, founder and managing director, Cargoguide International, added, “We've established great partnerships over the years, working with the Carriers, GSAs and forwarders as their independent partner. Having created a standard for comparable freight rates since 2003, the platform allows carriers to market their capacity and forwarders to easily compare freight rates.</p>
      <p>“Our mantra is ‘Dare to Improve', continuing to innovate and boost global freight forwarding. With our dedicated teams and niche software, we strive to maintain the highest reliability standards. This is an exciting time for us as we enhance our service.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
</corpus>
