<corpus>
  <document>
    <document_id>3a1ec5</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/zim-a-strong-operational-and-financial-performance-in-a-difficult-2019/</url>
    <title>Zim – 'a strong operational and financial performance' in a difficult 2019</title>
    <author>Gavin van Marle</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T14:52:58+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>2M</topic>
      <topic>Asia-Mediterranean</topic>
      <topic>Asia-US Gulf</topic>
      <topic>Asia-US west coast</topic>
      <topic>The Purse Strings</topic>
      <topic>Zim</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Despite a marginal decline in volumes, Israeli container carrier Zim has reported significant improvement in financial results last year.</p>
      <p>In 2019, it earned revenue of $3.3bn, compared with $3.25bn in 2018, a 1.6% increase, which came on the back of a 3.7% increase in the average freight rate to $1,009 per teu compared with $973 per teu in 2018.</p>
      <p>Total volumes were 2.8m teu compared with 2.9m teu in 2018.</p>
      <p>Its adjusted ebitda was $385.9m, compared with $150.7m in 2018, and on this it posted a net loss of $13m compared with a net loss of $119.9m in 2018.</p>
      <p>Eli Glickman, Zim president and chief executive, said: “2019 has been a challenging year for the industry which had to cope with the escalation of the US-China trade war, while simultaneously getting itself ready for the IMO 2020 new regulation enforcement.</p>
      <p>“Despite those difficult market conditions, we delivered a strong operational and financial performance with better ebit margin contribution than most of our peers. We also accelerated the deleveraging of our balance sheet,” he said.</p>
      <p>Its 2019 operating cash flow was $370.6m, compared with $225m in 2018, as the carrier expanded its vessel sharing agreement with the 2M partners Maersk and MSC to three additional trades: Asia-East Mediterranean; Asia-American Pacific Northwest; and Asia-US Gulf.</p>
      <p>“This clearly indicates that our strategy proves to be fruitful and effective and we intend to continue the path we initiated,” Mr Glickmann added.</p>
      <p>“We continue to develop and implement lead innovative solutions, and we remain agile and ready to respond fast to new challenges. I’m convinced that these values will enable us to overcome the current coronavirus crisis, which we all hope will be contained soon.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>e7feed</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/qatar-cargo-freighter-services-unaffected-despite-bellyhold-cuts/</url>
    <title>Qatar Cargo freighter services unaffected despite bellyhold cuts</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T11:15:11+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Qatar Airways</topic>
      <topic>Qatar Airways Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Qatar Airways Cargo announced that its cargo operations — specifically, freighter flights — will remain unaffected following the Qatar government’s recent instructions which state that with immediate effect, “entry to the State of Qatar is allowed for Qatari nationals only”.</p>
      <p>Qatari nationals travelling back to their country will be allowed to enter, but will then have to be quarantined for 14 days as a precaution against the coronavirus.</p>
      <p>Due to low passenger demand caused by the virus Qatar Airways has reduced its passenger flights to select countries, which in turn has reduced bellyhold capacity on these routes.</p>
      <p>However, the carrier explained: “We are working to rebook any cargo on the affected belly-hold flights to alternative flights and would like to assure you that we are doing as much as we can to reduce the impact to your business”.</p>
      <p>The carrier also added that its freighter aircraft services currently remain unaffected.</p>
      <p>“We thank you all for your understanding during these challenging times that we all are going through and appreciate your cooperation, trust and support. Customer-centricity continues to remain at the core of all our operations,” Qatar Airways Cargo said.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, Scoot, Korean Airways and Cathay Pacific are operating passenger aircraft for cargo-only operations to serve the growing need for freight to be moved between China and the rest of the world as factories increase productivity following the extended Chinese New Year break.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>544d4e</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/freighter-operator/air-partner-expects-charter-market-surge/</url>
    <title>Air Partner expects charter market surge</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-16T17:36:59+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Partner</topic>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Charter broker Air Partner has urged companies to book cargo transport early to keep supply chains moving in light of the coronavirus.</p>
      <p>The company said that it has reported a spike in demand while capacity is in short supply as passenger airlines have axed services.</p>
      <p>Air Partner chief executive Mark Briffa said: “We’re seeing a spike in airfreight service requests as many commercial flights are being grounded and at a time when Chinese industrial production is restarting after a month-long shutdown. There is still immediate charter availability, but we foresee that could change in the coming weeks.”</p>
      <p>The broker said that is has access to any freight aircraft between North America and Europe or between North America and China, or South East Asia, “at a moment’s notice”.</p>
      <p>“If availability does decrease, prices will surge,” it warned. “As such, to reduce risk and guarantee availability, Air Partner recommends companies secure aircraft charter solutions as soon as they are needed.”</p>
      <p>It warned that freight rates from China have already begun to increase as demand increases.</p>
      <p>Figures from the latest TAC Index show airfreight prices from Shanghai to North America increased by 32.3% from a week earlier to $4.02 per kg, while prices from the Chinese city to Europe jumped by 15.8% compared with the prior seven days to $2.71 per kg.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, prices from Hong Kong to North America increased by 11.5% week on week to $3.59 per kg and there was a 3.2% increase to $2.58 per kg on services to Europe.</p>
      <p>On the capacity side, Air Partner warned that the US travel ban for Europeans would cause an immediate negative impact on availability and significant increase in pricing for cargo capacity to Europe for at least 30 days.</p>
      <p>For China, it said available cargo capacity from China is down 39% versus last year and flight cancellations on routes to China have removed close to 5,000 tons per day of capacity, with belly capacity down by 85% and maindeck capacity down by 12%.</p>
      <p>It added that more than 40 airlines have temporarily suspended operations to and from China to-date and this is likely to continue to rise with no estimated date to recommence commercial airline operations.</p>
      <p>“With China beginning to slowly ramp up production again, it will take some time for scheduled freight operators to readjust their capacities to normal schedule,” the broker said. </p>
      <p>“During the coronavirus outbreak, Air Partner has seen a large increase in urgent freight requests from companies seeking to transport a number of different commodities between North America, Asia and Europe.” </p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>44bd0b</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/services/charter-company/ceva-logistics-operates-charters-to-maintain-asia-us-supply-chain/</url>
    <title>CEVA Logistics operates charters to maintain Asia-US supply chain</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T10:27:08+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>services</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>CEVA Logistics</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>CEVA Logistics has contracted 86 freighter flights to help maintain the global supply chain as the coronavirus outbreak continues.</p>
      <p>The company is using the aircraft on a charter basis to deliver parts and supplies to its customers in the automotive, aerospace, computer and hi-tech electronics sectors.</p>
      <p>The majority of flights served routes between Asia (Hong Kong, Shanghai, Bangkok and Singapore) and the US (Dallas, Rockford, Rickenbacker). Other charters served European cities, such as Amsterdam and Brussels.</p>
      <p>CEVA has already operated more than 58 flights – to transport more than 7,700 tonnes or airfreight – to provide urgent stock replenishment for those which could not otherwise be supplied.</p>
      <p>Over the next few weeks, it will operate 28 more charter flights.</p>
      <p>Guillaume Col, CEVA Logistics’ chief operating officer, commented: “Working extremely closely with our customers, we have been able to deliver a robust charter programme to adapt to these difficult circumstances.</p>
      <p>“Acting in close collaboration with the rest of the CMA CGM Group, we are striving to offer fast and accessible alternatives to our clients throughout the world in order to help keep the global economy moving.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>07bf59</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/disciplined-capacity-management-by-carriers-keeps-freight-rates-in-line/</url>
    <title>Disciplined capacity management by carriers keeps freight rates in line</title>
    <author>Gavin van Marle</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T14:55:25+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Asia-Mediterranean</topic>
      <topic>Asia-North Europe</topic>
      <topic>Asia-US east coast</topic>
      <topic>FBX</topic>
      <topic>Freightos</topic>
      <topic>Rates: the eternal tango</topic>
      <topic>SCFI</topic>
      <topic>Transpacific Trade</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Continued discipline over capacity management by container lines managed to keep freight rates from tumbling this week as increased levels of factory production in China began to be offset by coronavirus crisis that has gripped Europe and North America.</p>
      <p>Last week’s double-digit gain on the transpacific headhaul route from China to the US west coast on the SCFI was reversed this week, with its Shanghai-USWC rate dipping 3.8% to $1,549 per feu.</p>
      <p>Similarly, the Shanghai-US east coast freight rate fell 4.4% to finish the week at $2,785 per feu, as US demand for imports appeared to be declining dramatically, reportedly leading the east coast gateway of Miami to temporarily suspend port operations due to lack of cargo.</p>
      <p>However, there has been a divergence between indices this week, as the Freightos Baltic Index (FBX) has shown a 12% increase in China-USWC prices to $1,477 per feu and a 7% increase on China-US east coast rates to $2,730 per feu.</p>
      <p>“I assume this is a matter of the market stabilising as demand for shipping from China increases (driving prices up), and fewer sailings are blanked (driving prices down),” Freightos chief marketing officer Eytan Buchman told The Loadstar today.</p>
      <p>“We’re continuing to see prices rise and I anticipate this will continue as companies continue to replenish inventories; this week alone (since Monday), the FBX daily increased 8% for shipping from China to the US west coast,” he added.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, Asia-Europe trades also recorded a slight decline as carriers managed capacity in expectation of a steep drop in demand for goods from Asia.</p>
      <p>The SCFI’s Shanghai-North Europe leg fell by 3.6% to $797 per teu, and 1.2% to Mediterranean ports, to end the week at $892 per teu.</p>
      <p>Martin Holst-Mikkelsen, EMEA head of ocean freight for Flexport, explained: “Rates have remained relatively stable in the past four weeks, with only a marginal rate erosion – carriers recognise that there is a limited amount of spot cargo available in the market to shift around and have acted with discipline.</p>
      <p>“Activity has resumed in China, and demand has picked up very well in the past few weeks and will continue in the week to come. But we expect the resumption of demand to be short lived. The impact of Covid-19, and lockdown in an increasing number of countries across Europe, presents us all with unprecedented uncertainty and a set of challenges we have not previously faced.</p>
      <p>“We can expect the recent developments to lead to declining consumer demand across Europe, especially for non-essential goods. Carriers are informing us they have observed this trend during the past few days through an increasing number of cancellations from their large BCO customers, affecting bookings in the month to come.</p>
      <p>“We expect a decline in demand will force carriers to increase the number of blank sailings going into April, in an attempt to address supply/demand imbalance and reduce the risk of significant rate erosion,” he continued.</p>
      <p>In an illuminating blog on LinkedIn this week, SeaIntelligence Consulting partner Lars Jensen warned that the decline in demand in Europe and elsewhere could be unprecedented.</p>
      <p>“Consumers will reduce their spending. Not only are many shops closed, but many consumers will also fear for their jobs and hence scale back on consumption of non-essentials.</p>
      <p>“Likewise, businesses have very little clarity over the immediate future and will halt the ordering of additional goods beyond what they are absolutely certain they can sell.</p>
      <p>“These effects will have a strong impact – and are the exact same effects which impacted the industry during the financial crisis. How strong remains to be seen, but the effect in China was a 20% decline in retail sales in January and February,” he wrote.</p>
      <p>However, he also warned that once the worse effects of the outbreak were over, the outlook for Asia-Europe container supply chains could change rapidly.</p>
      <p>“Once we are past the pandemic and countries revert to normal, we should expect a surge of cargo. Even if the economy remains subdued, businesses might have to re-stock some of their inventories, which itself has a strong impact on container demand.</p>
      <p>“Hence, during this rebound phase, we should expect a shortage of shipping capacity and rising freight rates,” he said.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>29fa14</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/fedex-corp-withdraws-earnings-guidance-for-the-first-time-in-50-year-history-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>FedEx Corp withdraws earnings guidance for the first time in 50-year history</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T13:55:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>FedEx Corp. said it would continue to reduce its delivery capacity, as the coronavirus pandemic disrupts global trade patterns and economic activity. While reporting its consolidated results for the third quarter ended February 29, FedEx Corp revealed that operating results declined due to weaker global economic conditions including the impact of the coronavirus. Operating results also took a hit on account of higher self-insurance accruals, an unfavourable variable incentive compensation comparison, increased FedEx Ground costs from expanded service offerings, the loss of business from a large customer, a continuing mix shift to lower-yielding services and a more competitive pricing environment.</p>
      <p>These factors were partially offset by the benefits from volume growth at FedEx Ground, an additional operating weekday, increased yields at FedEx Freight and the shifting of Cyber Week into December. The delivery giant withdrew its earnings guidance for the first time in its 50-year history.</p>
      <p>“The COVID-19 pandemic is having a significant impact around the world,” said Frederick W. Smith, FedEx Corp. chairman and chief executive officer.  “We continue to deliver for our customers and are ready to support increased demand for our international express export services due to the significant reductions in intercontinental air capacity.  While the global economic impact from recent social-distancing mandates is uncertain, we remain well positioned to assist our customers as they work to manage their supply chains and inventories.  We will continue to support efforts to combat the pandemic.”</p>
      <p>Last year’s net income included tax benefits of $90 million ($0.34 per diluted share) from the recognition of certain loss carry forwards.  This was partially offset by a tax expense of $50 million ($0.19 per diluted share) related to new lower rates in the Netherlands applied to deferred tax balances.</p>
      <p>“We are suspending our fiscal 2020 earnings forecast for our consolidated and segment results due to the uncertainty caused by the coronavirus pandemic,” said Alan B. Graf, Jr., FedEx Corp. executive vice president and chief financial officer.  “To mitigate these near-term headwinds and position the company for future earnings growth, we are attacking costs throughout the company by managing capacity, retiring our oldest and least-efficient aircraft, integrating TNT Express, and lowering our residential delivery costs by having FedEx Ground deliver FedEx SmartPost and certain day-definite FedEx Express packages.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>454689</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/uk-and-ireland-increase-truckers-working-hours-to-keep-supply-chains-moving/</url>
    <title>UK and Ireland increase truckers' working hours to keep supply chains moving</title>
    <author>Alex Lennane</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:31:43+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Land</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>driver rules</topic>
      <topic>driver shortage</topic>
      <topic>EU</topic>
      <topic>Ireland</topic>
      <topic>UK</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Driver hours restrictions across the UK and Ireland have been relaxed, allowing an extra hour of work before taking a break.</p>
      <p>The new rules in the UK stipulate that drivers may now drive for up to 5.5 hours before a 45-minute break, and the daily driving period has been increased to 11 hours, once a week. Daily rest periods have been cut to nine hours.</p>
      <p>The new rules have been designed to bring greater flexibility and allow drivers to complete journeys without a break, and/or return to a depot rather than parking overnight.</p>
      <p>Ireland’s minister for transport, tourism and sport Shane Ross explained: “We have granted a temporary relaxation of the EU driving and resting time rules due to the Covid-19 public health crisis, recognising the importance of the haulage industry to the economy, and in response to requests from the industry itself.</p>
      <p>“Critically, we are striking a balance between driver welfare, operator flexibility, road safety and minimising disruption to supply chains.</p>
      <p>“I have also requested that these arrangements be kept under continual review. I want to thank our hauliers for their support and hard work in this difficult time. With their help we will keep our chains of supply for food and essential goods moving.”</p>
      <p>It is as yet unclear whether other EU member states are taking similar action, but relaxation of the rules seems inevitable, as media report long truck queues at borders in Europe.</p>
      <p>As borders close, drivers were waiting up to 18 hours at several. The worst, according to Business Insider, was on the A4 between Germany and Poland, where a 60km traffic jam had formed.</p>
      <p>Thousands of trucks were also stuck on the Lithuanian and Polish border after Poland ordered a coronavirus test for every driver. And while Hungary temporarily opened its borders on Tuesday night, by the morning there was a new 27km queue on the Austrian side.</p>
      <p>You can see the UK’s new rules here, and Ireland’s here.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>491f93</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/policy/tiaca/tiaca-wants-air-cargo-exempt-from-covid-19-travel-bans/</url>
    <title>TIACA wants air cargo exempt from Covid-19 travel bans</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T10:47:32+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>policy</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Tiaca</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>The International Air Cargo Association (TIACA) has called on governments to exempt air cargo from any bans because of the vital role it will play in the fight to stop the spread of the coronavirus.</p>
      <p>TIACA said that the air cargo industry has a decisive role to play in the fight against COVID-19 and the industry’s voice must be fully heard by regulators and governments.</p>
      <p>This is why TIACA has joined the ICAO Technical group on joint actions related to COVID-19.</p>
      <p>“The goal is clear: to draw attention both to the fundamental role that the air cargo industry plays and to the need to protect its continued existence and vitality,” the organisation said.</p>
      <p>“In the current major crisis, airfreight is essential for the transport of food, basic necessities and health-related products – in other words, everything necessary for people to survive. The global economy also needs airfreight to continue to supply businesses and factories.”</p>
      <p>TIACA said that airlines are facing multiple financial issues are emerging: Leasing payments for aircraft; salaries, energy supplies, and payments to service providers and equipment providers; taxation; and difficulties arising from uncoordinated travel bans, restrictions imposed on crew movements, airport slots and route changes, etc.</p>
      <p>“TIACA sees its role in the ICAO Technical Group as using ICAO’s mechanism to reach out to governments and remind them that air cargo is a significant contributor to the global economy and international trade and that it plays a very important role in preventing and battling the disastrous effect of coronavirus,” said Vladimir Zubkov, TIACA secretary general.</p>
      <p>“We support IATA’s appeal to have air cargo recognized as vital in the fight against COVID-19 and for action to be taken – in particular, removing all travel restrictions on air cargo operations and taking all necessary measures to allow air cargo to continue to circulate around the world,” said Steven Polmans, TIACA chairman.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>fd2018</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/china-airfreight-rates-continue-to-surge/</url>
    <title>China airfreight rates continue to surge</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T09:50:34+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Freight Investor Services</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Airfreight rates out of China have rapidly increased over the last week, but thoughts are now turning to the impact of lower consumer demand in Europe and the US.</p>
      <p>The latest TAC Index figures show that average airfreight rates on services from Shanghai to the US last week increased by 29.7% on the prior week to reach $4.71 per kg. On services from Shanghai to Europe there was a 17.7% week on week increase to $3.19 per kg.</p>
      <p>From Hong Kong to the US there was a 10.4% week on week increase to $3.70 per kg and from Hong Kong to Europe prices were up 10.8% to $2.86 per kg.</p>
      <p>The price increases come as factories in China continue to ramp up production following the extended New Year break and passenger airlines have slashed capacity as result of lower demand.</p>
      <p>It is estimated that flight cancellations have removed more than 5,100 tons of capacity from China per day on average.</p>
      <p>Peter Stallion of air cargo derivatives broker said that freighter operators looked set to benefit from the lack of bellyhold capacity.</p>
      <p>However, he warned that with Europe and the US now introducing social distancing measures, consumer demand could weaken.</p>
      <p>“The dramatic shift in price generated by a severe lack of belly freight capacity, lifting pent up cargo-throughput that was previously bottle-necked in Asia, will be a welcome reprieve from the pain freighter operators endured in 2019.”</p>
      <p>He added: “Even with events such as the 2015 US west coast port strikes in recent memory, COVID-19 has now become an exceptionally disruptive event for supply chains globally.</p>
      <p>“Upstream problems have now become downstream problems, as imports from Asia will now hit slack consumer demand in Europe and North America.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>236e23</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/tiaca-calls-for-recognition-of-air-cargo-in-the-fight-against-covid-19/</url>
    <title>TIACA calls for recognition of air cargo in the fight against COVID-19</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T15:25:49+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Association News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>ICAO</topic>
      <topic>TIACA</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>TIACA has joined the “ICAO Technical group on joint actions related to COVID-19,” along with other bodies including WHO, IATA, ACI and GEA. TIACA aims at highlighting the important role that the air cargo industry plays in this unprecedented crisis and stresses that the industry’s voice must be heard by regulators and governments.</p>
      <p>In the current major crisis, airfreight is essential for the transport of food, basic necessities and health-related products. The global economy also needs air freight to continue to supply businesses and factories. TIACA has described that in the current situation multiple financial issues have emerged. This includes, leasing payments for expensive aircraft, salaries, energy supplies, and payments to service providers and equipment providers, taxation, as well as difficulties arising from uncoordinated travel bans, restrictions imposed on crew movements, airport slots and route changes, and so on.</p>
      <p>“TIACA sees its role in the ICAO Technical Group as using ICAO’s mechanism to reach out to governments and remind them that air cargo is a significant contributor to the global economy and international trade, and that it plays a very important role in preventing and battling the disastrous effect of coronavirus,” Vladimir Zubkov, TIACA secretary general, has commented.</p>
      <p>TIACA has also urged governments to exempt the movement of cargo from any bans. “We support IATA’s appeal to have air cargo recognized as vital in the fight against COVID-19 and for action to be taken – in particular, removing all travel restrictions on air cargo operations and taking all necessary measures to allow air cargo to continue to circulate around the world,” said Steven Polmans, chairman of TIACA.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
</corpus>
