<corpus>
  <document>
    <document_id>07bf59</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/disciplined-capacity-management-by-carriers-keeps-freight-rates-in-line/</url>
    <title>Disciplined capacity management by carriers keeps freight rates in line</title>
    <author>Gavin van Marle</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T14:55:25+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Asia-Mediterranean</topic>
      <topic>Asia-North Europe</topic>
      <topic>Asia-US east coast</topic>
      <topic>FBX</topic>
      <topic>Freightos</topic>
      <topic>Rates: the eternal tango</topic>
      <topic>SCFI</topic>
      <topic>Transpacific Trade</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Continued discipline over capacity management by container lines managed to keep freight rates from tumbling this week as increased levels of factory production in China began to be offset by coronavirus crisis that has gripped Europe and North America.</p>
      <p>Last week's double-digit gain on the transpacific headhaul route from China to the US west coast on the SCFI was reversed this week, with its Shanghai-USWC rate dipping 3.8% to $1,549 per feu.</p>
      <p>Similarly, the Shanghai-US east coast freight rate fell 4.4% to finish the week at $2,785 per feu, as US demand for imports appeared to be declining dramatically, reportedly leading the east coast gateway of Miami to temporarily suspend port operations due to lack of cargo.</p>
      <p>However, there has been a divergence between indices this week, as the Freightos Baltic Index (FBX) has shown a 12% increase in China-USWC prices to $1,477 per feu and a 7% increase on China-US east coast rates to $2,730 per feu.</p>
      <p>"I assume this is a matter of the market stabilising as demand for shipping from China increases (driving prices up), and fewer sailings are blanked (driving prices down)," Freightos chief marketing officer Eytan Buchman told The Loadstar today.</p>
      <p>"We're continuing to see prices rise and I anticipate this will continue as companies continue to replenish inventories; this week alone (since Monday), the FBX daily increased 8% for shipping from China to the US west coast," he added.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, Asia-Europe trades also recorded a slight decline as carriers managed capacity in expectation of a steep drop in demand for goods from Asia.</p>
      <p>The SCFI's Shanghai-North Europe leg fell by 3.6% to $797 per teu, and 1.2% to Mediterranean ports, to end the week at $892 per teu.</p>
      <p>Martin Holst-Mikkelsen, EMEA head of ocean freight for Flexport, explained: "Rates have remained relatively stable in the past four weeks, with only a marginal rate erosion – carriers recognise that there is a limited amount of spot cargo available in the market to shift around and have acted with discipline.</p>
      <p>"Activity has resumed in China, and demand has picked up very well in the past few weeks and will continue in the week to come. But we expect the resumption of demand to be short lived. The impact of Covid-19, and lockdown in an increasing number of countries across Europe, presents us all with unprecedented uncertainty and a set of challenges we have not previously faced.</p>
      <p>"We can expect the recent developments to lead to declining consumer demand across Europe, especially for non-essential goods. Carriers are informing us they have observed this trend during the past few days through an increasing number of cancellations from their large BCO customers, affecting bookings in the month to come.</p>
      <p>"We expect a decline in demand will force carriers to increase the number of blank sailings going into April, in an attempt to address supply/demand imbalance and reduce the risk of significant rate erosion," he continued.</p>
      <p>In an illuminating blog on LinkedIn this week, SeaIntelligence Consulting partner Lars Jensen warned that the decline in demand in Europe and elsewhere could be unprecedented.</p>
      <p>"Consumers will reduce their spending. Not only are many shops closed, but many consumers will also fear for their jobs and hence scale back on consumption of non-essentials.</p>
      <p>"Likewise, businesses have very little clarity over the immediate future and will halt the ordering of additional goods beyond what they are absolutely certain they can sell.</p>
      <p>"These effects will have a strong impact – and are the exact same effects which impacted the industry during the financial crisis. How strong remains to be seen, but the effect in China was a 20% decline in retail sales in January and February," he wrote.</p>
      <p>However, he also warned that once the worse effects of the outbreak were over, the outlook for Asia-Europe container supply chains could change rapidly.</p>
      <p>"Once we are past the pandemic and countries revert to normal, we should expect a surge of cargo. Even if the economy remains subdued, businesses might have to re-stock some of their inventories, which itself has a strong impact on container demand.</p>
      <p>"Hence, during this rebound phase, we should expect a shortage of shipping capacity and rising freight rates," he said.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>23fb98</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/forwarder-group-fiata-backs-iatas-cargo-push/</url>
    <title>Forwarder group FIATA backs IATA's cargo push</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T11:56:56+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>FIATA</topic>
      <topic>IATA</topic>
      <topic>Tiaca</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Freight forwarder association FIATA has backed IATA's efforts to ensure that airfreight is not affected by measures put in place to stop the spread of coronavirus.</p>
      <p>Earlier this week, IATA urged governments to take the following actions:</p>
      <p>In response, the forwarder group said: "Government's do not appear to clearly understand that short term decisions will exacerbate the immediate and short-term ability of economies to meet the challenge of COVID-19 containment and then the economic rebuild.</p>
      <p>"As to those two critical needs, air cargo is vital in delivering emergency relief, medical technical infrastructure componentry and keeping global supply chains functioning with 'just in time' intervention.</p>
      <p>"Such delivery has been traditionally through dedicated cargo aircraft and high utilisation of capacity in passenger aircraft (bellyhold).</p>
      <p>"With passenger aircraft now denied cross border access such belly hold capacity has significantly declined, rates have become exorbitant and suppliers, through their international freight forwarder partners, now seeking to move goods through other compromised logistic chains.</p>
      <p>"As international airfreight is instrumental in transporting perishable, short shelf life goods and medical supplies it is time for all governments to address decisions that are counterproductive to the fight of COVID-19."</p>
      <p>Yesterday, TIACA also came out in support of the IATA initiative.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>b826bf</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/iag-offers-pax-aircraft-for-cargo-charter/</url>
    <title>IAG offers PAX aircraft for cargo charter</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T09:56:58+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>IAG</topic>
      <topic>IAG Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>IAG is offering its passenger to freight forwarders for cargo operations in response to the coronavirus.</p>
      <p>In a short note to customers, IAG Cargo chief commercial officer John Cheetham said: "To support your freight and to help get it where it needs to be, we are now opening up the opportunity for freight forwarders to charter our aircraft where needed.</p>
      <p>"As a business we are looking to move quickly to find working solutions for our customers. If you are interested and you need more information on charter capacity, please do get in touch with your local sales representative."</p>
      <p>This comes as passenger operations have been cut, resulting in cargo capacity reductions.</p>
      <p>Earlier this week, IAG chief executive Willie Walsh said that governments "need to appreciate" that there is a strong cargo demand, and passenger aircraft carry a large proportion of global airfreight.</p>
      <p>"Our intention is to try and keep as much of our capacity available for critical supplies that need to be shipped around the world," he said.</p>
      <p>"We may operate some of our passenger aircraft just for belly-hold cargo to ensure we keep critical supplies moving."</p>
      <p>IAG is set to ground dozens of aircraft over April and May, equivalent to a 75% cut in capacity, in response to falling demand and restrictions imposed on travel.</p>
      <p>In the US, Delta Air Lines has also offered its aircraft up for cargo charter.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, Scoot is operating its passenger aircraft on behalf of sister company SIA Cargo and Cathay Pacific and Korea Air have confirmed that their aircraft are being used to carry cargo.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>5d79b4</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/schiphol-sees-168-drop-in-cargo-tonnage-in-mar-2020-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>Schiphol sees 16.8% drop in cargo tonnage in Mar 2020</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-15T19:18:00+05:30</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Cargo flights at Schiphol Airport rose by 3.2 percent during the month compared to the same period last year, to reach a total of 1,338. There was a significant increase in the number of dedicated cargo aircraft at Schiphol (+25 percent) in the last week of March. Even though cargo is generally carried in a dedicated cargo aircraft, there are also combinations of passenger planes with cargo in the hold. This was unable to compensate for the decrease in cargo in the hold of passenger aircraft over the entire month of March and the tonnage transported decreased by 16.8 percent, despite the upward trend in the number of cargo aircraft during the last week.</p>
      <p>"We are seeing increases in the transport of certain items that are usually transported by sea, like surgical face masks, protective eyewear and disposable gloves. Those items are currently being sent as air freight too because of the faster delivery times," said Maaike van der Windt, head of aviation marketing at cargo and customer experience, Schiphol.</p>
      <p>The number of flights to and from Schiphol in March fell by 36.8 percent to a total of 25,155. The number of travellers arriving, departing or transferring at Amsterdam Airport Schiphol decreased by 56.1 percent to 2.5 million. The figures for March are entirely dominated by the impact of coronavirus. The corona virus' impact is seen as the main reason for the reduction in figures.</p>
      <p>There was a decrease by 51 percent to 0.8 million in the number of intercontinental passengers at Amsterdam Airport Schiphol. The decrease in passenger volume to South America was the least pronounced (-34 percent), while the most pronounced decrease occurred for Asia (-63.1 percent). Africa (-40 percent), the Middle East (-49 percent) and North America (-55 percent) also saw major drops in passenger volumes. Passenger volumes within Europe also fell by 58.4 percent, with Italy showing the largest drop (-84.3 percent). In total, there were destinations in 50 countries for which passenger volumes decreased by more than 50 percent. Destinations in 30 countries decreased by more than 25 percent but less than 50 percent, and the figures decreased even less or even rose slightly in only 11 countries.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>0da11f</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/sectors/pharma-logistics/wfs-handles-largest-single-shipment-at-paris-pharma-centre/</url>
    <title>WFS handles largest single shipment at Paris pharma centre</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T11:12:32+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>sectors</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>WFS</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Worldwide Flight Services' (WFS) has handled 34 temperature-controlled containers at its new pharma centre at Paris Charles de Gaulle Airport (CDG) – its largest single shipment since it opened the €10 m facility late last year.</p>
      <p>The containers, which were handled on behalf of WFS' customers AirBridgeCargo Airlines and Kuehne + Nagel, spent 24 to 48 hours at the pharma centre ahead of their delivery to China on an AirBridgeCargo Boeing 747 freighter.</p>
      <p>Hugo Rodrigues, vice president of cargo France, at WFS, explained: "This particular shipment for AirBridgeCargo and Kuehne + Nagel was the biggest so far and helped to demonstrate the capabilities of both the facility and our team.</p>
      <p>"Our decision to invest in this state-of-the-art facility to support our airline and freight forwarder customers, as well as the pharmaceutical industry, has already been validated by the strong demand we are seeing from so many different organisations.</p>
      <p>"With the need for pharma products all over the globe likely to soar in 2020, we will deliver the capacity and quality of service our customers need to ensure the integrity and efficiency of their pharma supply chains."</p>
      <p>WFS' pharma centre is the only dedicated facility of its kind at Paris CDG, the second largest airfreight hub in Europe.</p>
      <p>Features of the pharma centre include: a team of 30 experts onsite, temperature-controlled warehousing and handling services and a transport fleet that is suitable for moving pharmaceutical cargo.</p>
      <p>Currently, around 30 airlines and freight forwarding companies regularly use WFS' pharma centre to support their cold chain shipments.</p>
      <p>WFS estimates that this year it will handle 8,000 tonnes of healthcare and life sciences products at its pharma centre.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>cb2ecc</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/freight-forwarder/new-online-rate-platform-from-cargoguide/</url>
    <title>New online rate platform from Cargoguide</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T09:27:51+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>freight-forwarder</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Cargoguide</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Cargoguide has officially unveiled its new online rate management platform as part of efforts to simplify rate management.</p>
      <p>The new platform is a search engine for the freight forwarding sector and enables companies to meet the "key challenges they face in their day-to-day sales operations by increasing transparency and efficiency".</p>
      <p>It enables users to compare airfreight rates, including surcharges; improve rate calculations by allowing the inclusion of detailed shipment information, create and send custom quotes, track and manage sales opportunities.</p>
      <p>It builds on predecessor Cargo Office, the first independently managed global rate solution with a pre-filled air rate database. Cargoguide already works with more than 1,500 forwarders in over 84 countries. </p>
      <p>As a cloud-based solution, it has no installation time and it can be used to work remotely and provides up-to-date rates and flight schedules.</p>
      <p>Bas van der Putten, growth manager, Cargoguide, said: "We believe the freight forwarding process should be transparent, neutral and conducted within a fair market. Cargoguide is the next step in helping make that a reality.</p>
      <p>"This is an exciting time for us and for digital technology in the wider freight forwarding sector. It is however a challenging time for many freight forwarders and carriers, as they look to meet the demands of modern customers while remaining competitive."</p>
      <p>"We understand that forwarders and carriers need a platform that connects them through rates and that is continuously innovating and growing with them. The transparent rate calculations and accuracy of Cargoguide's data is unique and truly sets us apart from other platforms."</p>
      <p>Jorre Cobelens, founder and managing director, Cargoguide International, added: "We've established great partnerships over the years, working with the Carriers, GSAs and forwarders as their independent partner.</p>
      <p>"Having created a standard for comparable freight rates since 2003, the platform allows carriers to market their capacity and forwarders to easily compare freight rates.</p>
      <p>"We look forward to working with our customers to meet the challenges within the freight forwarding market – together."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>3cb96d</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/freight-forwarder/hong-kong-logistics-groups-ask-for-rent-relief/</url>
    <title>Hong Kong logistics groups ask for rent relief</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-14T10:59:32+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>freight-forwarder</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Ten Hong Kong freight and logistics organisations have issued an appeal to landlords to provide the industry with rental relief in light of the enormous negative impact of the Covid-19 outbreak on the industry.</p>
      <p>The organisations argue that the freight and logistics industry is being hit hard by the ongoing Covid-19 pandemic, with the global supply chain severely interrupted.</p>
      <p>They say that 95% of the shipments are cancelled, put on hold or disrupted, and that operators are facing unprecedented threats, tremendous risk of payment defaults and liquidity difficulties.</p>
      <p>"Without timely relief from landlords' high rental costs at this critical moment, it is estimated that a substantial number of SMEs and micro companies operating within the industry will close down or go bankrupt, forcing tens of thousands of workers out of jobs," the groups said.</p>
      <p>"With trading and logistics operations forming one of the four pillars of Hong Kong industry, and cargo throughput topping the list worldwide, the sector occupies substantial office and warehouse space in the city.</p>
      <p>"Leasing of these office premises and warehouse space accounts for the largest proportion of costs in the freight logistics industry. The huge pressure of rental commitments is a deciding factor in determining the survival of a considerable percentage of operators."</p>
      <p>The ten freight and logistics bodies have appealed for the support of landlords in the form of temporary rental relief to help the industry weather the current tumultuous economic environment.</p>
      <p>"The key role of freight logistics operators is to ensure the supply of food, necessities and other goods for Hong Kong citizens and communities affected by Covid-19.</p>
      <p>"It is vital to the future of the industry and to the wider economy, including leasing and rental businesses, to work together to ensure survival in order to be able to maintain the delivery of shipments to users and consumers. Immediate, temporary rental relief is vital, and would go a long way towards tiding the industry over the current crisis."</p>
      <p>Ten freight &amp; logistics bodies (in alphabetical order) are: Federation of Hong Kong Industries Group 21 – Transport &amp; Logistics Services Council (TLSC); Guangdong and Hong Kong Feeder Association (GHKFAL); Hong Kong Association of Aircargo Truckers (HAAT); Hong Kong Association of Freight Forwarding and Logistics (HAFFA); Hong Kong Logistics Association (HKLA); Hong Kong Logistics Management Staff Association (HKLMSA); Hong Kong Sea Transport and Logistics Association (HKSTLA); The Chamber of Hong Kong Logistics Industry (CHKLI); The Chartered Institute of Logistics and Transport in Hong Kong (CILTHK) and The Institute of Purchasing &amp; Supply of Hong Kong (IPSHK).</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>d2f49e</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/people/fta-hires-senior-transport-advisor-to-bolster-covid-19-logistics-support/</url>
    <title>FTA hires senior transport advisor to bolster Covid-19 logistics support</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-14T12:35:23+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>people</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>FTA</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>FTA has appointed a new senior transport advisor, Becky Martin, within its Member Advice Centre (MAC) to assist the team in supporting logistics businesses during the Covid-19 outbreak.</p>
      <p>Martin has 12 years' experience working in transport, distribution and retail, and previously held advisory roles at John Lewis Partnership and Marks &amp; Spencer.</p>
      <p>FTA's MAC provides expert advice and answers members' questions on legal, technical and operational matters, on topics including Covid-19 and Brexit.</p>
      <p>On her new role, Martin commented: "I am so excited to be joining FTA; the MAC team are well-known in the industry for their unrivalled knowledge of the legal, technical and operational matters pertaining to logistics and I'm delighted to be joining such a knowledgeable group of advisers.</p>
      <p>"Working together, we will be able to help our members through the challenges of Covid-19, along with many other issues."</p>
      <p>Robert Saunders, manager of MAC at FTA, added: "With so many conditions changing in the market on a daily basis at the moment, it is unsurprising that we are experiencing record numbers of calls to support members during the Covid-19 outbreak.</p>
      <p>"With Martin's in-depth understanding of transport and logistics – in addition to her exceptional customer service skills – we are thrilled to have her join the team to help us assist businesses through the challenging times ahead, from Covid-19, Brexit and beyond."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>622bdf</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/sectors/pharma-logistics/csafe-parcel-containers-used-to-boost-kimera-labs-research/</url>
    <title>CSafe Parcel containers used to boost Kimera Labs research</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-14T10:19:09+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>sectors</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>CSafe</topic>
      <topic>CSafe Global</topic>
      <topic>Pharma</topic>
      <topic>Pharma Logistics</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Temperature-controlled container manufacturer CSafe Global is providing its passive Parcel shipping containers to Kimera Labs to boost the research centre's studies.</p>
      <p>CSafe's Parcel containers will allow Kimera Labs — a biotechnology laboratory that produces mesenchymal stem cell-derived (MSC) exosome products for scientific and clinical research — to ship its products anywhere in the world to further ongoing medical research.</p>
      <p>With its Parcel containers, which offer protection, simplicity and efficiency by design, CSafe has been able to not only provide a solution that will protect Kimera Labs' products during longer transports, but also allows them to ship products five days a week instead of four.</p>
      <p>Duncan Ross, founder and chief executive of Kimera Labs, commented: "Over the past several months, we've received orders for our products from locations where overnight delivery is simply not an option.</p>
      <p>"The containers we had on hand were not able to maintain the needed temperature long enough to ensure product integrity upon delivery. We had to find a solution that would meet our standards for quality and accommodate long-term growth."</p>
      <p>Emilio Frattaruolo, CSafe's vice president of innovation, passive systems, added: "The superior VIP insulation in our Parcel solutions provides extended hold times for 120+ hour shipment durations.</p>
      <p>"Combined with the fact that CSafe Parcels are qualified to ISTA 7D worst case challenge testing, the team at Kimera Labs can rest assured that their products will arrive in optimal condition".</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>287830</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/working-from-home-can-be-tricky-for-freight-firms-with-onsite-only-tech/</url>
    <title>'Working from home' can be tricky for freight firms with 'onsite-only' tech</title>
    <author>Sam Whelan</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:28:13+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Cogoport</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Digital freight forwarder</topic>
      <topic>Flexport</topic>
      <topic>freight forwarders</topic>
      <topic>FreightBro</topic>
      <topic>Kontainers</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Forwarders and carriers are being stretched to the limit by lockdowns and quarantines sweeping the globe, forcing large-scale remote working and reduced resources.</p>
      <p>And Flemming Frost, president of digital freight marketplace Cogoport, believes remote working will "hurt more" than many realise – "Even among the big players," he told The Loadstar.</p>
      <p>"I spoke with a top 10 carrier and it is down on resources across many locations, as such staff are flat-out to just keep the daily business together."</p>
      <p>While investment into freight-tech and digitalisation has been a hot industry topic in recent years, many logistics firms are likely ill-prepared to operate efficiently under "work from home" conditions.</p>
      <p>"The lack of tech and automation means many processes are 'band-aided' by 'human APIs', and when the humans are either away from work or ill-equipped to work from alternative locations, that will hurt," explained Mr Frost.</p>
      <p>"A check with a small forwarder gave me the same impression – half the staff are at the office and the rest can only work at half-capacity due to an inability to access all the required material and systems from outside the office."</p>
      <p>According to Mark Yong, MD for Asia Pacific at multimodal digital supply chain platform Blume Global, many freight companies still rely on legacy systems which can only be operated onsite, due to network security.</p>
      <p>"Medium-size companies are probably suffering the most, as they don't have adequate tools," he noted.</p>
      <p>Seko Logistics announced remote working at its global headquarters in Chicago this week. Group commercial director Keith Gaskin said the industry needed to embrace digital transformation at a quicker pace.</p>
      <p>"That includes the archaic bill of lading process," he said, "especially in times like this when a piece of paper is often still needed to exchange hands [which] is crazy.</p>
      <p>"There are obviously alternatives, but from some regions, L/Cs still stipulate multiple copies of the bills need to be presented. Hard to do if an office is in lockdown or the post office/courier services are unable to work."</p>
      <p>Flexport, meanwhile, is looking to collaborate, according to CEO Ryan Petersen, who explained: "If you work at a customs brokerage or freight forwarder that can't maintain operations because of your IT set up, please reach out.</p>
      <p>"This is a crucial time for us to all help each other to keep supply chains moving, especially as there may be life-saving goods in some of these shipments."</p>
      <p>However, one customs broker said: "We are fully equipped to work remotely with zero service interruptions. Most brokers are."</p>
      <p>Perhaps sensing a need for greater digital capabilities among forwarders, freight-tech companies Kontainers and FreightBro both announced this week that new users could temporarily access their respective products free of charge.</p>
      <p>Similarly, Australian firm A2B Solution Group, a service partner of the Cargowise One platform, said it had developed an "essential workflow package that will allow your staff to work from home within 24 hours of engagement".</p>
      <p>"Best of all," A2B added, "the implementation package comes with a company specific guide and a free roll of toilet paper."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
</corpus>
