<corpus>
  <document>
    <document_id>6c9108</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/geodis-launches-air-charter-and-rail-services-for-urgent-shipments-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>Geodis launches air charter and rail services for urgent shipments</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-23T11:50:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Geodis is offering a number of air charter services to assist customers with urgent shipments during the ongoing Covid-19 crisis. In addition, rail alternatives are being offered to/from China.</p>
      <p>With disruptions in ocean freight and restrictions in air cargo with established carriers cancelling scheduled flights, Geodis is providing alternative means to move customers’ cargoes between China and Europe as well as on Transatlantic routes.</p>
      <p>The first of the air charter services departed from Frankfurt (Germany) on a one-way to Shanghai on February 12. In order to facilitate the resurgence in westbound freight out of China, the company did another round trip service on Feb 21 departing from Liege (Belgium) to Shanghai Pudong International.  As of February 28, weekly round trip flights were established from Frankfurt, with Shanghai departures each Tuesday.  This schedule will remain in place throughout the month of March when consideration of a further extension will be made and is being complemented by flights from Hong Kong to Europe.</p>
      <p>Geodis has continued with its newly introduced direct, dedicated service from Hong Kong to Guadalajara, Mexico, through March.  The next flight departed Hong Kong on March 22.</p>
      <p>Geodis’ rail solutions from major cities in China are also on track. Two options are scheduled from Xi’an and Chongqing to the German destinations of Hamburg and Duisburg.  The standard services have an 18 day transit time and from Xi’an to Hamburg an express, 12-day solution is provided.  Return routings are also available.</p>
      <p>Following the decision by US authorities to close its borders to visitors from Europe and to prepare for the consequent sharp decrease in commercial cargo capacity, Geodis established a return air charter program linking Amsterdam and Chicago on a four flights a week schedule. The first flight from Amsterdam will be on the 21st March.</p>
      <p>Onno Boots, CEO for Asia Pacific region, Geodis shared “We are positively building on our capabilities as a key supply chain partner to our customers by responding to their needs for an undisrupted supply chain through strengthening our capabilities in air freight, with the inclusion of these new services. We hope our prompt response with these quick solutions will continue to assure our global customers that GEODIS is committed to ensuring we deliver the quality of service they have come to rely upon from us”.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>799f10</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/oman-air-suspends-turkish-flights/</url>
    <title>Oman Air suspends Turkish flights</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-23T12:35:34+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Airline News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>air cargo</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Covid-19</topic>
      <topic>Oman Air Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Oman Air will suspend all flight operations between Muscat and Istanbul, Turkey between March 25 and March 31. The suspension comes in reaction to new travel restrictions aimed at limiting the spread of Covid-19. The move will especially affect belly cargo travelling between the two countries.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>ed3c16</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/jack-ma-foundation-alibaba-foundation-fly-medical-supplies-to-us-africa-spain-slovenia-and-france-in-fight-against-covid-19-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>Jack Ma Foundation, Alibaba Foundation fly medical supplies to US, Africa, Spain, Slovenia and France in fight against Covid-19</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T13:59:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>In its ongoing efforts to contain the spread of Covid-19 and provide aid to afflicted communities across the globe, the Jack Ma Foundation and Alibaba Foundation have committed to sending medical supplies, including masks and test kits, to the US, Africa, Spain, Slovenia and France.</p>
      <p>On his personal Twitter page, Alibaba Group founder Jack Ma stressed the importance of staying one step ahead as the effects of the coronavirus pandemic continue to ripple across the globe.</p>
      <p>The foundations sent 500,000 test kits and one million masks to the US and were received by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, in Spain, with the support of King Felipe VI and the Spanish Ministry of Health, Consumer Affairs and Social Welfare, the foundations were able to deliver an initial batch of 500,000 masks from Shanghai to Zaragoza Airport. Additional supplies are due to arrive in Spain over the next few days.</p>
      <p>On March 18, another cargo plane carrying medical masks departed from Hangzhou and arrived at Liege Airport. A portion of these donated supplies will go to frontline medical staff in Belgium. Also on the chartered flight were masks for Slovenia and France. According to the foundations, Slovenia’s Department of Defense and France’s Ministère des Affaires sociales et de la Santé provided crucial support in the delivery of these supplies.</p>
      <p>Another day, another flight! One more plane carrying 1.5 million masks has landed in Liege Airport, Belgium. These supplies will be delivered to France, Slovenia and Belgium. More supplies will be delivered to Liege! COVID-19 is still spreading. We need to be faster! pic.twitter.com/Msd7KYAdUd— Jack Ma Foundation (@foundation_ma) March 18, 2020</p>
      <p>The foundations have also committed to donating 100,000 medical masks, 20,000 test kits and 1,000 protective suits to each of the 54 nations on the African continent. The medical supplies donated by the Jack Ma Foundation and Alibaba Foundation will be delivered to Addis Ababa, the capital of Ethiopia, where Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed Ali has agreed to take the lead in overseeing their distribution to other African countries. The foundations also announced plans to provide online training materials to help medical institutions in Africa cope with coronavirus cases.</p>
      <p>Earlier this month, the Jack Ma Foundation and Alibaba Foundation jointly donated surgical masks to Japan and South Korea. The foundations have also sent test kits and masks to European countries, including Italy and Belgium.</p>
      <p>The foundations have also provided funding to establishments such as the Peter Doherty Institute for Infection and Immunity in Australia and Columbia University in the US to support research into coronavirus vaccines and treatment.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>981038</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/postponed-smart-airports-conference-exhibition/</url>
    <title>Postponed: SMART Airports Conference &amp; Exhibition</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T15:09:36+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Coronavirus</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>air cargo</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>San Antonio</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>In light of the current situation, San Antonio International Airport has taken the decision to postpone the upcoming SMART Airports Conference &amp; Exhibition, that was due to take place in San Antonio, Texas in April.</p>
      <p>Following this it has been announced that the event will be rescheduled and take place Monday 2 to Wednesday 4 November 2020. By November, Jesus H. Saenz, director or airports at San Antonio Airport System (SAAS), notes: “we will be celebrating as we will have concluded our SAAS development plan, charting the path forward for the next 20+ of growth.” Finding the silver lining in the situation, Saenz also adds, “November is a great time to visit our beautiful and vibrant city!”</p>
      <p>“The 2020 SMART Airports and Regions Conference will provide you with a unique opportunity to learn from a host of specialised presenters on innovative strategies in airport design, construction and development, commercial development, real estate and non-aeronautical revenue, customer service excellence and community engagement. We’re looking forward to sharing our vision with you and sharing some of our world-famous warm and welcoming San Antonio hospitality,” said Saenz.</p>
      <p>The November conference is expected to attract over 500 airport industry leader, represent over 50 countries and host over 90 airport/industry expert speakers.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>82a52d</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/heidi-capozzi-to-leave-boeing-as-livingston-steps-up/</url>
    <title>Heidi Capozzi to leave Boeing as Livingston steps up</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T15:38:26+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Boeing News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>Boeing</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Boeing has announced that Heidi Capozzi, senior vice president of human resources will leave the company in early April to pursue another opportunity.Capozzi joined Boeing in 2009 and since 2016 has led the company’s leadership and learning, talent planning, employee and labour relations, total rewards, and diversity and inclusion initiatives.</p>
      <p>“For more than a decade, Heidi has demonstrated a deep commitment to engaging and inspiring our people, strengthening our culture and supporting our business,” said Boeing president and CEO David Calhoun. “During this time, she also built a world-class Human Resources team and helped elevate Boeing as an employer of choice, globally. We owe Heidi sincere gratitude for all she has accomplished, and we wish her well as she pursues a new opportunity.”</p>
      <p>Following an orderly transition, Wendy Livingston, currently vice president of corporate human resources, will replace Capozzi on an interim basis until a permanent successor is named.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>23fb98</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/forwarder-group-fiata-backs-iatas-cargo-push/</url>
    <title>Forwarder group FIATA backs IATA’s cargo push</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T11:56:56+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>FIATA</topic>
      <topic>IATA</topic>
      <topic>Tiaca</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Freight forwarder association FIATA has backed IATA’s efforts to ensure that airfreight is not affected by measures put in place to stop the spread of coronavirus.</p>
      <p>Earlier this week, IATA urged governments to take the following actions:</p>
      <p>In response, the forwarder group said: “Government’s do not appear to clearly understand that short term decisions will exacerbate the immediate and short-term ability of economies to meet the challenge of COVID-19 containment and then the economic rebuild.</p>
      <p>“As to those two critical needs, air cargo is vital in delivering emergency relief, medical technical infrastructure componentry and keeping global supply chains functioning with ‘just in time’ intervention.</p>
      <p>“Such delivery has been traditionally through dedicated cargo aircraft and high utilisation of capacity in passenger aircraft (bellyhold).</p>
      <p>“With passenger aircraft now denied cross border access such belly hold capacity has significantly declined, rates have become exorbitant and suppliers, through their international freight forwarder partners, now seeking to move goods through other compromised logistic chains.</p>
      <p>“As international airfreight is instrumental in transporting perishable, short shelf life goods and medical supplies it is time for all governments to address decisions that are counterproductive to the fight of COVID-19.”</p>
      <p>Yesterday, TIACA also came out in support of the IATA initiative.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>cb2ecc</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/freight-forwarder/new-online-rate-platform-from-cargoguide/</url>
    <title>New online rate platform from Cargoguide</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T09:27:51+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>freight-forwarder</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Cargoguide</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Cargoguide has officially unveiled its new online rate management platform as part of efforts to simplify rate management.</p>
      <p>The new platform is a search engine for the freight forwarding sector and enables companies to meet the “key challenges they face in their day-to-day sales operations by increasing transparency and efficiency”.</p>
      <p>It enables users to compare airfreight rates, including surcharges; improve rate calculations by allowing the inclusion of detailed shipment information, create and send custom quotes, track and manage sales opportunities.</p>
      <p>It builds on predecessor Cargo Office, the first independently managed global rate solution with a pre-filled air rate database. Cargoguide already works with more than 1,500 forwarders in over 84 countries. </p>
      <p>As a cloud-based solution, it has no installation time and it can be used to work remotely and provides up-to-date rates and flight schedules.</p>
      <p>Bas van der Putten, growth manager, Cargoguide, said: “We believe the freight forwarding process should be transparent, neutral and conducted within a fair market. Cargoguide is the next step in helping make that a reality.</p>
      <p>“This is an exciting time for us and for digital technology in the wider freight forwarding sector. It is however a challenging time for many freight forwarders and carriers, as they look to meet the demands of modern customers while remaining competitive.”</p>
      <p>“We understand that forwarders and carriers need a platform that connects them through rates and that is continuously innovating and growing with them. The transparent rate calculations and accuracy of Cargoguide’s data is unique and truly sets us apart from other platforms.”</p>
      <p>Jorre Cobelens, founder and managing director, Cargoguide International, added: “We’ve established great partnerships over the years, working with the Carriers, GSAs and forwarders as their independent partner.</p>
      <p>“Having created a standard for comparable freight rates since 2003, the platform allows carriers to market their capacity and forwarders to easily compare freight rates.</p>
      <p>“We look forward to working with our customers to meet the challenges within the freight forwarding market – together.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>8f94e6</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/saudi-arabia-to-keep-running-all-its-airports-for-cargo-reception-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>Saudi Arabia to keep running all its airports for cargo reception</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-23T18:02:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>The Saudi General Authority of Civil Aviation (GACA), in cooperation with the concerned authorities, announced that all of the Kingdom’s airports will continue to work as usual in the reception of air freight cargo around the clock.</p>
      <p>The measures taken by GACA include requiring all relevant authorities and air freight companies operating in the Kingdom's airports to comply with health and safety requirements and precautionary measures to combat the novel coronavirus (Covid-19).</p>
      <p>All the concerned departments have taken all the necessary precautions to sterilise and disinfect all the air cargo stations at the Kingdom's airports. Furthermore, medical checkpoints have been established in all stations for staff and visitors alike.  This in addition to providing the working teams with all means of protection and prevention measures to ensure the flow of goods and services to all the Kingdom’s cities in safe and secure manner.</p>
      <p>GACA has called on all air cargo companies operating in the Kingdom's airports to implement the precautionary and preventive measures implemented at the Kingdom’s airports. This in addition of adhering to a strict health guidelines followed in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia to prevent the emergence of Covid-19.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>105119</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/wfs-milan-team-handles-critical-medical-supplies-for-hospitals-in-italy-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>WFS’ Milan team handles critical medical supplies for hospitals in Italy</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-23T15:44:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Worldwide Flight Services’ (WFS) team at Milan’s Malpensa Airport are supporting the urgent medical effort to saves the lives of coronavirus victims in Italy by expediting the handling of time-sensitive materials destined for hospitals and medical centres.</p>
      <p>This included handling cargo onboard special China Eastern Airways charter flights from Shanghai to Milan carrying 20 tonnes of medical equipment and supplies as well as a team of doctors to help deal with the crisis, which has already claimed the lives of over 3,400 people in Italy.</p>
      <p>The WFS team ensured the medical cargo was immediately processed and cleared so it could be despatched to hospitals in Milan, Venice, Padoa and Siena. WFS expects to handle more charters into Italy in the coming days and weeks as it continues to give its full support to the relief effort taking place across the country.</p>
      <p>Organised by the Chinese Government, the flights also repatriated 187 Chinese citizens from Italy to Wenzhu in southern Zhejiang Province.</p>
      <p>Massimiliano Introini, managing director of WFS in Italy, said, “Cargo handling specialists at airports around the world are playing a vital role in helping governments and the healthcare sector deal with the urgent medical response to the outbreak of Covid-19. In Milan, we were able to ensure that by 20.00hrs on the day medical supplies had arrives, they were delivered to Protezione Civile, Italy’s emergency agency, to be distributed to various hospitals. We are ready to support more such flights to ensure life-saving equipment reaches patients as quickly as possible. This is one of the ultimate examples of the important role the airline and cargo handling industries play at times of national and international crisis. We must ensure these vital supply lines remain open.”</p>
      <p>“I also want to knowledge the commitment of our team for ensuring this particular project was completed so efficiently and for all their hard work and support during such a difficult time for the Italian population. The health and wellbeing of our staff, alongside the safety and security of our operations, remains our highest priority and we will continue to take the necessary measures to protect all the people involved in this essential work,” he added.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>d2341e</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/cargo-schedules-up-in-the-air-but-carriers-find-ways-to-keep-goods-flying/</url>
    <title>Cargo schedules up in the air, but carriers find ways to keep goods flying</title>
    <author>Alex Lennane</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T14:56:51+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>American Airlines Cargo</topic>
      <topic>Cathay Pacific</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Emirates SkyCargo</topic>
      <topic>Geodis</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Emirates SkyCargo has announced that, owing to “extraordinary” times, along with significantly reducing UK capacity, it has cancelled all contract/modified rate sheets from next Wednesday, 25 March.</p>
      <p>The carrier is to serve the UK with five passenger flights a day and a freighter twice weekly, it said. It will operate two flights into Heathrow, and one flight a day each into Birmingham, Manchester and Glasgow. But the schedule is open to review.</p>
      <p>The carrier is suspending all services from Newcastle, Gatwick, Stansted and Edinburgh until 30 June.</p>
      <p>It said bookings would be on a first-come-first-served basis, but that foodstuffs and pharma would be prioritised.</p>
      <p>All air waybills after 26 March will be priced at “UK standard tariff levels (per product code) or above, until further notice,” it said, and added that the new schedule would likely be in place until the end of June.</p>
      <p>One UK forwarder told The Loadstar: “All contract rates are out of the window – which is basically in line with all other carriers in every territory globally now. It’s pay to play.</p>
      <p>“These flight cancellations will have a huge impact – that’s a cancellation of 105 flights a week, with average bellyhold of 15 tonnes, between the 777s and A380s they operate.”</p>
      <p>Demand is still there, he added.</p>
      <p>“Goods are still moving on export and import, although slowing on inbound for retailers and manufacturing. If consumers aren’t consuming, then there is no point stacking the shelves, unless it is food or toilet paper.”</p>
      <p>He pointed to car manufacturers like BMW, Honda, Toyota, Nissan and Ford, shutting plants across Europe and North America, which would no longer need components.</p>
      <p>Getting the capacity and demand balance right is not going to be easy, he said, but increasing numbers of US and European airlines are putting on passenger flights for cargo.</p>
      <p>American Airlines has announced a series of cargo-only flights from Dallas to Frankfurt, starting today, with a 777-300, for two round-trips over four days. It marks AA’s first scheduled cargo-only flight since 1984, when it retired the last of its freighters.</p>
      <p>It said the flights would be carrying medical supplies, mail, telecoms equipment and e-commerce.</p>
      <p>AA is still carrying cargo domestically, said Rick Elieson, president of cargo. “We have a critical role to play in keeping essential goods moving during this unprecedented time, and we are proud to do our part and find ways to continue to serve our customers and our communities,” .</p>
      <p>“Challenging times call for creative solutions, and a team of people across the airline has been working nonstop to arrange cargo-only flight options for our customers.”</p>
      <p>Cathay Pacific announced this morning it was cutting 96% of its passenger capacity for April and May.</p>
      <p>It will operate three flights a week to 12 destinations: London, Los Angeles, Vancouver, Tokyo, Taipei, Delhi, Bangkok, Jakarta, Manila, Ho Chi Minh City, Singapore and Sydney. Cathay Dragon is still operating to Beijing, Shanghai and Kuala Lumpur and it too will operate passenger aircraft for freight.</p>
      <p>“While our freighter network remains intact, we are also ramping up our cargo capacity by mounting charter services and operating certain suspended passenger services purely for airfreight to meet cargo customer demand,” said chief commercial officer Ronald Lam.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, Geodis has announced it had launched several air services, and rail alternatives to/from China.</p>
      <p>It has weekly round-trips from Frankfurt to Shanghai, as well as flights out of Hong Kong to Europe, and Hong Kong to Guadalajara. And it is offering a four-flights-a-week schedule linking Amsterdam and Chicago.</p>
      <p>It also is offering rail services from Xi’an and Chongqing to Hamburg and Duisberg.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
</corpus>
