<corpus>
  <document>
    <document_id>796d44</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/airlines-continue-fight-against-covid-19/</url>
    <title>LIVE UPDATES: Air cargo continues fight against Covid-19</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-16T14:55:57+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Antonov Airlines</topic>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Emirates SkyCargo</topic>
      <topic>Etihad</topic>
      <topic>Etihad Cargo</topic>
      <topic>MASKargo</topic>
      <topic>Oman Air</topic>
      <topic>Oman Air Cargo</topic>
      <topic>WFS</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>A roundup of air cargo companies' efforts to meet the challenges presented by Covid-19.</p>
      <p>—————  April 16, 3:45pm BST —————————————–</p>
      <p>Atlas Air Worldwide subsidiary, Atlas Air, has donated air transport to New York University (NYU) Langone Health for the movement of essential medical equipment.</p>
      <p>On April 9, a flight was operated from Shanghai to New York City, and on April 13 another flight was operated from Shanghai to Chicago.</p>
      <p>The Atlas Air-operated Boeing 747-400 freighters were filled with medical gowns, face shields and masks necessary to safeguard frontline responders dealing with the coronavirus pandemic.</p>
      <p>Robert Grossman, managing director and chief executive of NYU Langone Health and dean of NYU Grossman School of Medicine, commented: "The Covid-19 pandemic has greatly impacted the accessibility of PPE for healthcare workers at NYU Langone Health, and across the world.</p>
      <p>"We extend our heartfelt thanks to Atlas Air for their extraordinary generosity, and for their efforts to ensure that our community is well-equipped in our ongoing battle against COVID-19."</p>
      <p>Atlas Air Worldwide's headquarters is located in the New York area and is served by NYU Langone.</p>
      <p>—————  April 16, 2:10pm BST —————————————–</p>
      <p>In its latest service updates, Emirates SkyCargo said that it operates flights to 51 destinations globally, out of which 19 cities are served by the Emirates SkyCargo Boeing 777 freighter aircraft and 38 destinations are served by dedicated cargo flights on Emirates' Boeing 777 passenger aircraft offering up to 50 tonnes belly capacity. (For a full list of destination and schedules, visit the Emirates SkyCargo website).</p>
      <p>London Heathrow airport is served by both Boeing 777-300ER "passenger freighters" and Boeing 777 freighters and is currently receiving four "passenger freighter" and two full freighter flights per week, as well as ad hoc charter flights.</p>
      <p>Last week, Emirates moved 125 tonnes of urgent foodstuffs to Dubai. Also in the last week, Emirates have moved over 75 tonnes of pharmaceuticals and medicines from the UK to the United Arab Emirates, China, Pakistan, Australia and Japan.</p>
      <p>Flights have also been transporting electronic and e-commerce goods from the UK. On imports, Emirates SkyCargo flights have been transporting essential supplies including fruit and vegetables and on April 14, a special charter flight flew in 100 tons of hand sanitisers and other commodities into London Heathrow. </p>
      <p>During the week ending 4 April 2020, Emirates SkyCargo had operated more than 160 flights on its freighter aircraft and close to 90 flights on its passenger aircraft. The following week, the air cargo carrier had operated close to 160 flights on its passenger aircraft.</p>
      <p>Since the start of April, the carrier has executed more than 30 charter flights connecting over 20 global destinations. The main commodities transported on the charter flights are medical supplies including face masks, protective covers, sanitisers, equipment for hospitals in addition to pharmaceuticals, raw materials and spare parts.</p>
      <p>—————  April 16, 09:28am BST —————————————–</p>
      <p>Etihad has provided an update on its cargo operations. The airline said it is using 22 Boeing 787 Dreamliners and 777-300ER passenger aircraft, with five more ready for service, to complement its operational fleet of five 777-200F freighters. These aircraft are providing scheduled, special passenger and belly-hold cargo services to several destinations worldwide.</p>
      <p>Since March 25, approximately 500 special passenger, freighter and cargo flights have been operated by the airline. These include passenger and belly-hold freight flights to Amsterdam, Bogota, Brussels, Dublin, Frankfurt, Jakarta, London Heathrow, Manila, Melbourne, Paris Charles de Gaulle, Seoul Incheon, Singapore, Tokyo Narita, Washington DC and Zurich, with other destinations planned.</p>
      <p>Etihad Cargo is now operating up to 100 turnaround flights per week to 32 destinations on five continents. In addition to normal scheduled cargo services, special freighter and humanitarian flights have been flown to Addis Ababa, Amsterdam, Beijing, Bogota, Bucharest, Copenhagen, Chennai, Cochin, Dublin, Frankfurt, Jeddah, Johannesburg, Karachi, Khartoum, Kiev, Milan, Paris, Rome, Shanghai, Tbilisi, Wuhan, and Zagreb. More special flights will be introduced in the coming weeks. </p>
      <p>—————  April 15, 07:00pm BST —————————————–</p>
      <p>Worldwide Flight Services (WFS) has launched a new emergency response cargo handling operation at Liege Airport following a request from the airport to help increase its capacity to accept more freighter flights carrying urgent medical equipment.</p>
      <p>In response to the airport's request, WFS opened the new station in just 72 hours by transferring experienced handling staff from its Brussels operations, as well as transferring equipment such as forklifts, pallets and a truck dock, from WFS stations in Belgium and the Netherlands.</p>
      <p>WFS' new emergency cargo handling station at Liege is located in a new airside warehouse space.</p>
      <p>As one of Europe's premier freighter hubs, Liege is acting as a central hub in the region for medical equipment and supplies arriving from China and other parts of the world.</p>
      <p>WFS expects to handle up to 14 freighter flights per week during this emergency response phase of operations, which is currently expected to continue until the end of May. WFS will also provide handling services for outbound cargo shipments from Liege.</p>
      <p>Craig Smyth, chief executive of WFS, commented: "I am extremely proud of everyone involved in this project and of the WFS team globally who are making such a vital contribution to the speed and efficiency of medical supply chains at a time when the world needs these more than ever before."</p>
      <p>Bert Selis, VP Commercial Cargo &amp; Logistics at Liege Airport, added: "Liege Airport has played a vital role in the provisioning of personal protection equipment (PPE) since the outbreak of covid-19 in Europe.</p>
      <p>"Additional aircraft movements and the huge growth in the volume of humanitarian goods led us to make this request to WFS for an immediate response to the market needs. This could only be done with the kind cooperation of AirBridgeCargo that has allowed their facility to be temporary used for this operation.</p>
      <p>"We are grateful to WFS for accepting this challenge, which means we are now able to welcome cargo carried onboard ad-hoc charters and short term freighter operations in the temporary facility made available to them."</p>
      <p> </p>
      <p>—————  April 15, 13:08am BST —————————————–</p>
      <p>Oman Air has completed 27 flights to eight different countries to return citizens home and supply the nation with food, commodities, medicine and medical equipment.</p>
      <p>The airline said it had flown several cargo-only flights to China to collect medical supplies, along with a number of flights to India to bring food and commodities to Oman. </p>
      <p>Those flights will continue on an as-needed basis and Oman Air is prepared to conduct cargo-only flights to other destinations if the need arises.</p>
      <p>—————  April 15, 11:00am BST —————————————–</p>
      <p>On April 14, an Antonov Airlines AN-225 Mriya aircraft transported 100 tonnes medical supplies from Tianjin China Airport in China to Warsaw in Poland.</p>
      <p>The aircraft flew to Warsaw, via Almaty Airport in Kazakhstan, carrying tests for laboratory analysis, medical masks and other protective equipment, with a total load of about 1000 cubed metres.</p>
      <p>This flight, chartered by UK-based Chapman Freeborn, was the first that utilised an AN-225 that had had maintenance and modernisation performed by Antonov Company specialists.</p>
      <p>The AN-225 Mriya had been fitted with a new Ukrainian engine remote control system, new Ukrainian liquid-crystal devices for the monitoring of the engines' work, and new energy-saving modern LED lighting equipment.</p>
      <p>Since the end of March, Antonov Airlines has carried more than 1,400 tons of cargo from China to different countries in Europe, Americas and the Middle East.</p>
      <p>Vitaliy Shost, Antonov Airlines first deputy director, commented: "Planning and performing charter flights in the current difficult quarantine conditions imposed by many countries when there are restrictions applied for landing and crew rest permits, requires selfless dedication and commitment on the part of all airline staff.</p>
      <p>"I would like to thank everyone who takes part in the setting up and arrangement of humanitarian flights from China and in particular those who were directly involved in the performance of the AN-225 flight to Warsaw.</p>
      <p>"We extend our exceptional gratitude to our customer Chapman Freeborn and partners for their cooperation and the opportunity to jointly carry out such an important and necessary mission together."</p>
      <p>—————  April 15, 12:00pm BST —————————————–</p>
      <p>MASKargo operated a flight from Shanghai in China to Malaysia yesterday, filled with almost 40 tonnes of medical equipment including masks and goggles.</p>
      <p>Ibrahim Mohamed Salleh, MASkargo Chief Executive Officer, explained: "Recognising the gravity and impact of the Covid-19 pandemic countrywide, we are more committed to ensuring that all medical equipment is being delivered as needed.</p>
      <p>"To accommodate the unusually high airfreight demand, we are innovating by using our passenger aircraft to carrying just cargo (P2C). To date, we have carried out 94 P2C flights since March 22 and more than 250 flights are being planned up to May 31.</p>
      <p>"Our freighters have also been very busy fulfilling charter requests on top of the scheduled flights, hitting a very high utilization rate. We have completed four charters this month and have several more planned, made up of mostly medical equipment for frontline healthcare workers".</p>
      <p> </p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>84d1d0</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/despite-cyber-attack-msc-says-cargo-is-still-flowing-seamlessly/</url>
    <title>Despite 'cyber attack', MSC says cargo is still flowing seamlessly</title>
    <author>Gavin van Marle</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-14T13:52:11+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>cyber attack</topic>
      <topic>Kuehne + Nagel</topic>
      <topic>MSC</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>MSC's e-commerce capabilities continue to be hampered by what appeared to be a cyber attack last week.</p>
      <p>Yesterday, the world's second largest carrier said the "network outage" that began on Thursday evening was limited to its headquarters in Geneva and its online operations, while its global office network was unaffected.</p>
      <p>"MSC operates different IT systems to separate headquarters from the agencies network to ensure that in case of an issue they cannot affect each other. In this case, the issue is limited to one of our data centres in Geneva, effecting solely some internal data processes, MSC.com, MyMSC and direct EDI, for a few customers.</p>
      <p>"Our agencies worldwide continue to work as usual; all MSC departments, terminals and depots are serving customers regularly and cargo is flowing without interruptions.</p>
      <p>"We are in continuous dialogue with our business partners and we have their full support," it said.</p>
      <p>This was confirmed in a LinkedIn post by Kuehne + Nagel's head of sea freight Otto Schact, who said his team had been in contact "within minutes" of the outage and said the way MSC and KN teams developed a response was "proof of a strong and true partnership".</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, MSC reminded shippers and forwarders that they could continue to make bookings on platforms such as INTTRA.</p>
      <p>"All bookings are managed securely and efficiently, and the issue affecting Geneva headquarters poses no threat to parties doing business with MSC. Customers can continue to place bookings via email or phone as well.</p>
      <p>"Also, we can confirm the safety of our communication system as MSC adopts all necessary security protocols when it comes to exchanging EDI files and emails," it said.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>b44c30</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/spicejet-ramps-up-cargo-operation-following-coronavirus-outbreak/</url>
    <title>SpiceJet ramps up cargo operation following coronavirus outbreak</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-14T14:26:32+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>SpiceJet</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>On April 7, India-based SpiceJet operated the country's first cargo-only passenger aircraft flight carrying vital medical supplies in the cabin. Since then, the airline has regularly used its Boeing 737 aircraft for cargo-only flights.</p>
      <p>SpiceJet has also recently operated special cargo flights to Abu Dhabi, Kuwait and other countries, to export local fresh fruits and vegetables and maintain supply chains.</p>
      <p>On April 9, SpiceXpress — SpiceJet's dedicated cargo arm — operated a freighter flight on the Chennai-Singapore-Chennai route carrying critical medical equipment and other Covid-19 related medical supplies.</p>
      <p>On April 10, a second freighter flight was operated from Singapore to Bengaluru, also carrying medical supplies.</p>
      <p>The April 9 and 10 flights marked the first time that SpiceXpress had operated freighter services between India and Singapore as part of Covid-19 relief efforts.</p>
      <p>Ajay Singh, chairman and managing director of SpiceJet, commented: "SpiceJet is putting its freighter and passenger aircraft to maximum use to carry medical and other vital supplies in these difficult times."</p>
      <p>SpiceJet has said it will continue to offer "unwavering support during these difficult times to ensure an uninterrupted supply chain across domestic and international markets".</p>
      <p>"Our employees are motivated and eager to contribute to serve the country while keeping health and safety as a paramount," it added.</p>
      <p> </p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>be81ce</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/latam-cargo-brazil-to-transport-240-tonnes-of-critical-supplies-across-brazil-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>LATAM Cargo Brazil to transport 240 tonnes of critical supplies across Brazil</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-16T16:17:00+05:30</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>LATAM Cargo Brazil continues to intensify its operations in order to transport health-oriented products during the fight against the Covid-19 pandemic. The carrier is now strengthening the transportation of such articles to different regions in Brazil, focusing on cities like Recife, Salvador, Fortaleza, Belem, Manaus, Porto Alegre and Brasilia.</p>
      <p>Approximately 240 tonnes will be transported in total, including pharmaceutical cargo and other personal protection equipment. A total of 20 cargo-only Boeing 767 flights will take place, in addition to the existing daily flights in other routes.</p>
      <p>This action, developed by LATAM Cargo Brazil in the country's north and northeast regions, comes in addition to the association with Amigos do Bem NGO. More than two tonnes of medicines, thermometers and sheets have already been transported to various hospitals within the northeastern area.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>1f8bca</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/finnair-the-latest-to-convert-cabins-for-cargo/</url>
    <title>Finnair the latest carrier to convert cabins for cargo</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-15T13:20:20+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Finnair</topic>
      <topic>Finnair Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Finnair is the latest airline to reveal that it is making changes to cabins to handle more cargo.</p>
      <p>The Helsinki-based airline said that this week it will fly more than 10 return flights on its A350 aircraft to Tokyo Narita, Seoul, Osaka, Shanghai and Guangzhou to carry cargo.</p>
      <p>The flights, which are arranged both as charter as well as Finnair's own commercial operations, will carry supplies to both Finland and Estonia, including coronavirus samples from private healthcare provider Mehiläinen and critical supplies from other companies and organisations, as well as normal cargo, such as fresh fish.</p>
      <p>This week, to increase cargo capacity, the cabins of two A350s will be converted for cargo use, the airline said. Previously, Finnair has only carried cargo in the hold.</p>
      <p>Air Cargo News has requested extra details on the work that will be carried out on the cabins.</p>
      <p>Mikko Tainio, managing director of Finnair Cargo, said: "We are working tirelessly on our cargo operations during these exceptional times.</p>
      <p>"Cargo traffic is crucial at the moment, and I am glad that we have been able to implement a new business model and quickly create a new freight network. I want to thank the entire Finnair team for their incredibly hard work."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>ed3c16</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/jack-ma-foundation-alibaba-foundation-fly-medical-supplies-to-us-africa-spain-slovenia-and-france-in-fight-against-covid-19-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>Jack Ma Foundation, Alibaba Foundation fly medical supplies to US, Africa, Spain, Slovenia and France in fight against Covid-19</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T13:59:00+05:30</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>In its ongoing efforts to contain the spread of Covid-19 and provide aid to afflicted communities across the globe, the Jack Ma Foundation and Alibaba Foundation have committed to sending medical supplies, including masks and test kits, to the US, Africa, Spain, Slovenia and France.</p>
      <p>On his personal Twitter page, Alibaba Group founder Jack Ma stressed the importance of staying one step ahead as the effects of the coronavirus pandemic continue to ripple across the globe.</p>
      <p>The foundations sent 500,000 test kits and one million masks to the US and were received by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, in Spain, with the support of King Felipe VI and the Spanish Ministry of Health, Consumer Affairs and Social Welfare, the foundations were able to deliver an initial batch of 500,000 masks from Shanghai to Zaragoza Airport. Additional supplies are due to arrive in Spain over the next few days.</p>
      <p>On March 18, another cargo plane carrying medical masks departed from Hangzhou and arrived at Liege Airport. A portion of these donated supplies will go to frontline medical staff in Belgium. Also on the chartered flight were masks for Slovenia and France. According to the foundations, Slovenia's Department of Defense and France's Ministère des Affaires sociales et de la Santé provided crucial support in the delivery of these supplies.</p>
      <p>Another day, another flight! One more plane carrying 1.5 million masks has landed in Liege Airport, Belgium. These supplies will be delivered to France, Slovenia and Belgium. More supplies will be delivered to Liege! COVID-19 is still spreading. We need to be faster! pic.twitter.com/Msd7KYAdUd— Jack Ma Foundation (@foundation_ma) March 18, 2020</p>
      <p>The foundations have also committed to donating 100,000 medical masks, 20,000 test kits and 1,000 protective suits to each of the 54 nations on the African continent. The medical supplies donated by the Jack Ma Foundation and Alibaba Foundation will be delivered to Addis Ababa, the capital of Ethiopia, where Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed Ali has agreed to take the lead in overseeing their distribution to other African countries. The foundations also announced plans to provide online training materials to help medical institutions in Africa cope with coronavirus cases.</p>
      <p>Earlier this month, the Jack Ma Foundation and Alibaba Foundation jointly donated surgical masks to Japan and South Korea. The foundations have also sent test kits and masks to European countries, including Italy and Belgium.</p>
      <p>The foundations have also provided funding to establishments such as the Peter Doherty Institute for Infection and Immunity in Australia and Columbia University in the US to support research into coronavirus vaccines and treatment.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>da44b0</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/global-retailers-cancelling-orders-threatens-bangladesh-garment-industry/</url>
    <title>Global retailers cancelling orders threatens Bangladesh garment industry</title>
    <author>Bangladesh correspondent</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:27:27+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Bangladesh</topic>
      <topic>Chittagong</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>garments</topic>
      <topic>Talking shop: the retail business</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Major retailers are cancelling or postponing orders, putting Bangladesh's garment industry, the country's top foreign currency earner and employer, in jeopardy.</p>
      <p>The value of order cancellations up to yesterday reached $124m – but the industry expects more to follow.</p>
      <p>The top buyers so far forced to cancel or withhold orders include C&amp;A, Zara, Pull and Bear, Baby Shop, Blackberrys, Inditex and Primark.</p>
      <p>Apparel manufacturers say that just after Covid-19 hit China, they faced a shortage of raw materials, which disrupted their production.</p>
      <p>Prices of locally available raw materials went up significantly, but the problem had eased to some extent as shipments from China began to resume.</p>
      <p>But now, as the virus spreads all over the world, the US and EU main markets for Bangladeshi apparel are severely affected, and the demand for ready-made garments has dropped, following the lockdown of many areas and clothing stores closing.</p>
      <p>"Every day we are hearing messages from buyers, either for cancellations or withheld [orders]," former president of Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) Siddiqur Rahman told The Loadstar.</p>
      <p>"My three factories faced order cancellations for 1.5 million garment items," said Mr Rahman, who is also chairman of Bando Design, whose factory supplies clothes for H&amp;M, belk, Matalan, C&amp;A, Walmart, Indian Terrain, Westside, Mango and Zara.</p>
      <p>The company will have a staff meeting today to assess the immediate impact of Coronavirus on the business, he said. "It's an uncertain situation. No one knows how far it will go."</p>
      <p>Chairman of Evince Group Anwar-ul Alam Chowdhury said manufacturers were receiving cancellations every hour or more. His factory supplies retailers such as Celio, Tesco, Sears, Carrefour, Debenhams, Lee, DeFacto, Wrangler, kmart, F&amp;F and Bexleys.</p>
      <p>"One retailer asked to halt production in factories up to June. It wanted a 30% discount on ready goods and said it will renegotiate a price for suspended orders," he said.</p>
      <p>"A factory owner told me yesterday he sent 10 million pieces garments to Chittagong port, but the buyer is now asking him to take them back to the factory," he added.</p>
      <p>Mr Chowdhury, also a former president of BGMEA, said one of the largest buyers, Inditex, had asked another factory owner to postpone cutting cloth for another 10 million pieces.</p>
      <p>"One of my customers in France said its offices were closed, do not ship the goods, we will let you know. And the order sheets for delivering goods in May and June are yet to come," he said.</p>
      <p>Many retailers had closed their stores worldwide for weeks and months, he added. "What will they do with goods after taking delivery?"</p>
      <p>He said his government needed to come up with a financial package for the garment makers to save the sector.</p>
      <p>"A crisis fund can be formed to support the industry."</p>
      <p>Imports and exports of goods through Chittagong port have plummeted since coronavirus hit the globe. In February, imports fell by 17% compared with January. Export earnings also saw a massive nosedive, and the trend may continue through the year.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>07bf59</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/disciplined-capacity-management-by-carriers-keeps-freight-rates-in-line/</url>
    <title>Disciplined capacity management by carriers keeps freight rates in line</title>
    <author>Gavin van Marle</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T14:55:25+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Asia-Mediterranean</topic>
      <topic>Asia-North Europe</topic>
      <topic>Asia-US east coast</topic>
      <topic>FBX</topic>
      <topic>Freightos</topic>
      <topic>Rates: the eternal tango</topic>
      <topic>SCFI</topic>
      <topic>Transpacific Trade</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Continued discipline over capacity management by container lines managed to keep freight rates from tumbling this week as increased levels of factory production in China began to be offset by coronavirus crisis that has gripped Europe and North America.</p>
      <p>Last week's double-digit gain on the transpacific headhaul route from China to the US west coast on the SCFI was reversed this week, with its Shanghai-USWC rate dipping 3.8% to $1,549 per feu.</p>
      <p>Similarly, the Shanghai-US east coast freight rate fell 4.4% to finish the week at $2,785 per feu, as US demand for imports appeared to be declining dramatically, reportedly leading the east coast gateway of Miami to temporarily suspend port operations due to lack of cargo.</p>
      <p>However, there has been a divergence between indices this week, as the Freightos Baltic Index (FBX) has shown a 12% increase in China-USWC prices to $1,477 per feu and a 7% increase on China-US east coast rates to $2,730 per feu.</p>
      <p>"I assume this is a matter of the market stabilising as demand for shipping from China increases (driving prices up), and fewer sailings are blanked (driving prices down)," Freightos chief marketing officer Eytan Buchman told The Loadstar today.</p>
      <p>"We're continuing to see prices rise and I anticipate this will continue as companies continue to replenish inventories; this week alone (since Monday), the FBX daily increased 8% for shipping from China to the US west coast," he added.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, Asia-Europe trades also recorded a slight decline as carriers managed capacity in expectation of a steep drop in demand for goods from Asia.</p>
      <p>The SCFI's Shanghai-North Europe leg fell by 3.6% to $797 per teu, and 1.2% to Mediterranean ports, to end the week at $892 per teu.</p>
      <p>Martin Holst-Mikkelsen, EMEA head of ocean freight for Flexport, explained: "Rates have remained relatively stable in the past four weeks, with only a marginal rate erosion – carriers recognise that there is a limited amount of spot cargo available in the market to shift around and have acted with discipline.</p>
      <p>"Activity has resumed in China, and demand has picked up very well in the past few weeks and will continue in the week to come. But we expect the resumption of demand to be short lived. The impact of Covid-19, and lockdown in an increasing number of countries across Europe, presents us all with unprecedented uncertainty and a set of challenges we have not previously faced.</p>
      <p>"We can expect the recent developments to lead to declining consumer demand across Europe, especially for non-essential goods. Carriers are informing us they have observed this trend during the past few days through an increasing number of cancellations from their large BCO customers, affecting bookings in the month to come.</p>
      <p>"We expect a decline in demand will force carriers to increase the number of blank sailings going into April, in an attempt to address supply/demand imbalance and reduce the risk of significant rate erosion," he continued.</p>
      <p>In an illuminating blog on LinkedIn this week, SeaIntelligence Consulting partner Lars Jensen warned that the decline in demand in Europe and elsewhere could be unprecedented.</p>
      <p>"Consumers will reduce their spending. Not only are many shops closed, but many consumers will also fear for their jobs and hence scale back on consumption of non-essentials.</p>
      <p>"Likewise, businesses have very little clarity over the immediate future and will halt the ordering of additional goods beyond what they are absolutely certain they can sell.</p>
      <p>"These effects will have a strong impact – and are the exact same effects which impacted the industry during the financial crisis. How strong remains to be seen, but the effect in China was a 20% decline in retail sales in January and February," he wrote.</p>
      <p>However, he also warned that once the worse effects of the outbreak were over, the outlook for Asia-Europe container supply chains could change rapidly.</p>
      <p>"Once we are past the pandemic and countries revert to normal, we should expect a surge of cargo. Even if the economy remains subdued, businesses might have to re-stock some of their inventories, which itself has a strong impact on container demand.</p>
      <p>"Hence, during this rebound phase, we should expect a shortage of shipping capacity and rising freight rates," he said.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>355328</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/maersk-bins-its-2020-financial-guidance-due-to-impact-of-pandemic/</url>
    <title>Maersk bins its 2020 financial guidance, due to impact of pandemic</title>
    <author>Mike Wackett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T14:54:20+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>IMO low-sulphur regulations</topic>
      <topic>Maersk</topic>
      <topic>The Purse Strings</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Despite its expectations of delivering a better first-quarter result than last year, Maersk said today it was suspending its guidance on full-year earnings as a result of the coronavirus outbreaks around the world.</p>
      <p>It said the global pandemic was severely impacting global transport and supply chains, "leading to material uncertainties and lack of visibility".</p>
      <p>It added that while its global operations were "running as normal", it had decided to suspend its 2020 guidance of an ebitda of around $5.5bn, "pending more clarity on the market development and financial implications".</p>
      <p>In a trading update, Maersk said that, based on its preliminary figures, it expected a first-quarter ebitda, before restructuring and integration costs, of around $1.24bn, which was "negatively impacted by weak volume development", but mitigated by strong implementation of IMO 2020 fuel price recovery.</p>
      <p>"We have executed well on our IMO 2020 strategy for how to manage the extra cost involved with the IMO mandated switch to low-sulphur fuel oil from 1 January," said chief executive Soren Skou.</p>
      <p>"We consequently expect to deliver a Q1 20 which is better than Q1 19, despite declining volumes across our businesses, driven by the Covid-19 pandemic."</p>
      <p>Maersk said guidance for its 2020 volume growth for liner business was "expected to be in line with, or slightly lower than, market growth".</p>
      <p>Maersk will publish its first-quarter results on 13 May.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>9f9955</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/quarantine-and-supply-chain-disruption-spreads-around-the-world/</url>
    <title>Quarantine and supply chain disruption spreads around the world</title>
    <author>Sam Whelan</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T14:56:07+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Land</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>ASEAN</topic>
      <topic>bill of lading</topic>
      <topic>Cogoport</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Europe</topic>
      <topic>US trucking</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Supply chain disruption outside China continues to spread, alongside the number of quarantines taking place around the world.</p>
      <p>In South-east Asia, Vietnam will seal its border with Cambodia tonight, according to Geodis.</p>
      <p>"No citizens of either country [will be] allowed to cross," Geodis said. "From a supply chain standpoint, this stops the entire cross-border trucking between both countries."</p>
      <p>Elsewhere in the region, Manila is in complete lockdown, although cargo is still moving, and the whole of Malaysia began a two-week lockdown on Wednesday. Malaysian citizens are barred from travelling overseas and foreign arrivals are not permitted.</p>
      <p>Similarly, India will suspend all scheduled international flights for one week, from 22 March.</p>
      <p>In Europe, Geodis warned operations could be impacted as its staff "transitioned to remote working".</p>
      <p>It said: "CCL (Cargo Container Lines) original bill of lading, import and export shipments may not be handled as promptly as expected in most of our European branches. We recommend you use express CCL or ask your suppliers at origin to telex-release the documents through the Geodis offices at origin."</p>
      <p>The issue of sending and receiving bill of lading documents via courier – still a common practice – could be another bottleneck for ocean freight during the crisis. One forwarder told The Loadstar: "Express companies are rejecting packages from China to Europe.</p>
      <p>"Those collected by them will be returned, as many EU incoming terminals are closed and capacity is cut by airlines as well. But we don't know yet if this includes documents."</p>
      <p>In the US, the port of Houston was forced to temporarily close two container terminals on Wednesday night, after a worker was diagnosed with coronavirus, while truckers across the country are having to deal with new restrictions aimed at "flattening the curve" of the virus.</p>
      <p>According The Wall Street Journal, shippers and receivers are asking to switch to electronic methods for documenting pick-ups and deliveries, and some are refusing to allow drivers to enter their building if they have travelled to virus "hot zones".</p>
      <p>According to Flemming Frost, president of Cogoport, challenges for forwarders and carriers alike will be a lack of both cargo and staff.</p>
      <p>"There will be issues with resources in the ports to handle the volumes," he told The Loadstar. "Crane and gantry drivers will be down in numbers, as will the trucks to take cargo to/from the port. The back offices will struggle to keep up and deliver on the timeline.</p>
      <p>"Fewer trucks may be available as drivers self-quarantine or follow employer or government direction to do so," Mr Frost added, and warned of financial catastrophe on the horizon for many in the industry.</p>
      <p>"Ultimately, shippers will not get quotes timely, and may lose the little business they can generate, adding to their bankruptcy risk.</p>
      <p>"Many in Europe have a dream that this is a three-to-four-week event – they may be disappointed when this drags on towards summer," said Mr Frost.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
</corpus>
