<corpus>
  <document>
    <document_id>5250f6</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/dispatches-from-the-front-lhr-serves-as-vital-airbridge-for-the-uk-amid-covid-crisis/</url>
    <title>Dispatches from the front: LHR serves as vital airbridge for the UK amid COVID crisis</title>
    <author>James Graham</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-14T08:42:17+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Airport News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>COVID-18</topic>
      <topic>LHR</topic>
      <topic>London Heathrow Airport</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>London Heathrow CEO John Holland-Kaye has spoken about how the gateway is supporting the wider UK's efforts to combat the Covid-19 crisis. He said:  "Heathrow continues to serve the nation by keeping vital supply lines open, and helping people get home. Now is the time to agree a common international standard for healthcare screening in airports so that when this crisis recedes, people can travel with confidence and we can get the British economy moving again."</p>
      <p>Highlights of the airport's activities include:</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>00eddc</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/freight-forwarder/damco-moves-into-new-heathrow-facility/</url>
    <title>DAMCO moves into new Heathrow facility</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T09:06:14+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>freight-forwarder</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Damco</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Freight forwarder DAMCO has moved into a new 36,000 sq ft warehouse at London's Heathrow Airport as part of ongoing investment in its airfreight offering.</p>
      <p>The company has moved its airfreight operations into offices at the North Feltham Trading Estate, within three miles of Heathrow's cargo terminal, to support a growing customer base of leading UK retailers.</p>
      <p>The bonded facility's environmental credentials include a Building Research Establishment Environmental Assessment Method (BREEAM) rating of Excellent and a Grade A Energy Performance Certificate (EPC).</p>
      <p>"We are working with our clients closely to help reduce their CO2 footprint," said Anthony Akerman, managing director, UK and Ireland, DAMCO.</p>
      <p>"Their focus on a triple bottom line to satisfy the goals of finance, environment, and ethical and social drivers to create sustainability means we need to remain creative in our approach.</p>
      <p>"By utilising our new facility, we will help to reduce CO2 on air shipments by consolidating clients' cargo at origin in order to book on direct flights rather than use transhipment hubs.  </p>
      <p>"This  allows us to kill volumes on the shipments, providing similar non-direct pricing for cargo that actually flies on a direct flight, reducing the CO2 footprint."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>3355ed</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/freighter-operator/sf-express-continues-transpacific-expansion-with-la-freighter-flight/</url>
    <title>SF Express continues transpacific expansion with LA freighter flight</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-16T16:03:51+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>SF Airlines</topic>
      <topic>SF Express</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Chinese express firm SF Express has expanded its transpacific operation with the addition of a Los Angeles to Hangzhou service.</p>
      <p>The company said that it would utilise an 87-tonne capacity B747-400 for the three-times-per week route, which it will operate alongside its existing New York-Hangzhou operation.</p>
      <p>The US outbound service will focus on general freight for automotive, spare parts, heavy machinery, chemicals, electronic products, and fresh food. SF Express also offers a last-mile delivery network in China, providing additional convenience to international shippers.</p>
      <p>SF Express has expanded its network over recent years and now offers services to Southeast Asia, central Asia and Europe.</p>
      <p>Since February 2020, it has successfully launched/resumed 13 international airfreight routes, among them Wuxi to Chongqing, Hahn to Wuxi, Shenzhen to Chennai, Nanning to Ho Chi Minh, Shenzhen to Delhi, Shenzhen to Singapore and Shenzhen to Osaka.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>f5e7d6</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/siginon-aviation-ramps-up-operations-in-jkia/</url>
    <title>Siginon Aviation ramps up operations in JKIA</title>
    <author>James Graham</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-17T09:08:42+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Africa News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Jomo Kenyatta International Airport (JKIA)</topic>
      <topic>Kenya</topic>
      <topic>Nairobi</topic>
      <topic>Siginon Aviation</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Siginon Aviation, a ground handler based in Jomo Kenyatta International Airport (JKIA), Nairobi and Eldoret International Airport in Kenya, is to revamp its ramp handling services with a multi-million-dollar investment on new ramp equipment.</p>
      <p>The ramp equipment comprises of 20-tonne main deck high loaders, 7-tonne lower deck high loaders, pallet transporters, ground power units, pushback, passenger super steps, tow tractors and conveyor belts. Jared Oswago, the acting general manager adds: "Our goal is to provide our customers with a ramp service that provides, safe, secure and excellent turnaround services. Our assurance to our customers is to continuously set high service standards and sustainable growth."</p>
      <p>Siginon Aviation, which is IATA Safety Audit for Ground Operators (ISAGO) certified, is currently serving contracts with various regional and international freighters.</p>
      <p>"The new ramp equipment has led to an enhancement on the operations team with engagement of an additional job roles created to effectively match the tasks and ensure effective service delivery," he said.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>44bd0b</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/services/charter-company/ceva-logistics-operates-charters-to-maintain-asia-us-supply-chain/</url>
    <title>CEVA Logistics operates charters to maintain Asia-US supply chain</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T10:27:08+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>services</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>CEVA Logistics</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>CEVA Logistics has contracted 86 freighter flights to help maintain the global supply chain as the coronavirus outbreak continues.</p>
      <p>The company is using the aircraft on a charter basis to deliver parts and supplies to its customers in the automotive, aerospace, computer and hi-tech electronics sectors.</p>
      <p>The majority of flights served routes between Asia (Hong Kong, Shanghai, Bangkok and Singapore) and the US (Dallas, Rockford, Rickenbacker). Other charters served European cities, such as Amsterdam and Brussels.</p>
      <p>CEVA has already operated more than 58 flights – to transport more than 7,700 tonnes or airfreight – to provide urgent stock replenishment for those which could not otherwise be supplied.</p>
      <p>Over the next few weeks, it will operate 28 more charter flights.</p>
      <p>Guillaume Col, CEVA Logistics' chief operating officer, commented: "Working extremely closely with our customers, we have been able to deliver a robust charter programme to adapt to these difficult circumstances.</p>
      <p>"Acting in close collaboration with the rest of the CMA CGM Group, we are striving to offer fast and accessible alternatives to our clients throughout the world in order to help keep the global economy moving."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>233ff8</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/american-airlines-cargo-updates-cancellation-policy-to-maximise-capacity/</url>
    <title>American Airlines Cargo updates cancellation policy to maximise capacity</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-16T09:01:17+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>American Airlines</topic>
      <topic>American Airlines Cargo</topic>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>American Airlines Cargo has updated its cancellation and fair booking policy to mitigate unused space on its flights during this challenging, capacity-limited period, caused by the coronavirus outbreak.</p>
      <p>Effective from May 1, the new fair booking policy will allow customers to cancel up to 48 hours prior to the flight's scheduled departure or ship the amount in the original booking, without being charged.</p>
      <p>Customers with shipments over 100 kg will be responsible for paying a fee starting at $50 for late cancellation, late reduction in chargeable weight or failure to show.</p>
      <p>American Airlines Cargo president, Rick Elieson, commented: "As big as our network is, we now have a very limited number of daily flights around the world and we have a responsibility to protect that capacity.</p>
      <p>"This is space that could be used to hold life-saving medicines or critical freight, so we must do everything we can to avoid wasted cargo capacity and have as positive an impact on the world at a time when people are counting on us so heavily.</p>
      <p>"This policy allows us to be more efficient with limited inventory and better meet the needs of our customers."</p>
      <p>American recently launched its new end-to-end management system in late 2019, which introduced an online booking platform and made it easier for customers to digitally review options and secure bookings.</p>
      <p>Full details on the new policy can be viewed here.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>539887</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/klm-and-philips-establish-special-cargo-air-bridge-between-amsterdam-and-china/</url>
    <title>KLM and Philips establish special cargo air bridge between Amsterdam and China</title>
    <author>James Graham</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-13T09:43:47+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Airline News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>KLM</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>The loss of around 90% of flights between Europe and Asia has resulted in a major shortage of cargo capacity. Meanwhile, the corona crisis has prompted an enormous need for the rapid transportation of medical equipment and other supplies between the United States, Europe and China. KLM Royal Dutch Airlines has now joined hands with Royal Philips and the Dutch government to create a special cargo air bridge between the Netherlands and China. In addition to these parties, many others are seeking additional capacity. The air bridge to Asia will be launched today. To maintain this vital cargo air bridge for the coming six to eight weeks, KLM will specially redeploy Boeing 747 Combi equipment for the service between the Netherlands and China. This air bridge will ensure continuous availability of special cargo capacity, with two weekly flights to Beijing and three weekly flights to Shanghai. This will ensure around 250 tonnes of extra cargo capacity each way per week. The flights will supplement the current "skeleton schedule" that took effect on 29 March, with two weekly flights to Beijing and two weekly flights to Shanghai, operated with Boeing 787s and 777s. The KLM/Martinair Full Freighters will continue to be deployed on North Atlantic routes, which Philips will use as an air bridge between Amsterdam and distribution points in the United States. The full freighters will also continue to operate on South Atlantic routes and to destinations in Africa. In view of the 90% decline in flights and anticipated future capacity, KLM previously decided in early March that it would phase out its remaining Boeing 747s in April 2020, instead of in the summer of 2021. For the benefit of this air bridge, however, KLM will now redeploy two Boeing 747 Combi aircraft to be used specifically on these two routes during the designated period. "I believe it is incredibly important that KLM can be of service to broader Dutch society in this time of crisis, by way of our flexibility, creativity and cooperation with partners. This is perfectly exemplified by the initiative from Philips to join hands with KLM in seeking a solution for freeing up cargo capacity between Europe and China for essential medical supplies. I am very proud that the professional and dedicated staff of both companies have managed to realise this initiative at such short notice," said KLM president &amp; CEO Pieter Elbers "Philips and KLM have been key partners for more than 100 years. I am very pleased that we have now joined hands once more, in this time of need, to create this important air bridge with China. In combination with the existing air bridge to the United States, we can now more rapidly transport essential medical equipment and supplies between the United States, Europe and China, thereby ensuring that healthcare professionals can be more rapidly assisted in their battle against the coronavirus," added CEO Philips Frans van Houten</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>555ee4</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/united-expands-cargoonly-flights-to-new-global-destinations-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>United expands cargo-only flights to new global destinations</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-17T12:25:00+05:30</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>To meet the overwhelming demand for medical relief supplies, United began operating cargo-only flights on March 19. Since we began using Boeing 777 and 787 aircraft from United's passenger fleet for this purpose, we have operated over 400 flights carrying more than 6 million kilos of cargo.</p>
      <p>"With the global community in need, we are doing everything we can to keep supply chains moving worldwide and support the battle against Covid-19," said United Cargo President Jan Krems. "We're proud to play an active role in connecting vital medical supplies like test kits and personal protective equipment with healthcare professionals around the world."</p>
      <p>United is now operating more than 150 cargo-only flights per week between six of our US hubs and 13 cities worldwide: CTU, HKG, PEK, PVG, SYD and TPE in the Asia Pacific; AMS, BRU, DUB, FRA and LHR in Europe; SJU in the Caribbean and TLV in the Middle East. The carrier is looking to add new cities soon and will continue to expand our cargo-only flights program.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>30a4b4</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/sea-air-services-disrupted-and-rates-soar-as-airlines-suspend-more-flights/</url>
    <title>Sea-air services disrupted and rates soar as airlines suspend more flights</title>
    <author>Alex Lennane</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T14:42:14+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Aeromar</topic>
      <topic>Arise surcharges</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Dubai</topic>
      <topic>SAT Albatros</topic>
      <topic>Sea-air</topic>
      <topic>Singapore</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Sea-air shipments via Dubai and Singapore to Europe and the US have either been suspended or seen prices soar.</p>
      <p>Aeromar, which specialises in sea freight to Dubai and onward travel by air, said it had suspended its services with immediate effect, although all cargo currently on route would continue.</p>
      <p>It said it had been forced to make this decision as airlines began cancelling flights from Dubai.</p>
      <p>"We can fix rates three weeks in advance, but if during the sea voyage, flights get cancelled, it's pretty difficult to go back and ask a customer for more money to use one of the few carriers left," said MD Nick Coverdale.</p>
      <p>"And with air cargo rates still not that expensive from Hong Kong and South-east Asia, for example, the sea-air service doesn't look that attractive, especially with the uncertainties. The only option is to put the goods back on ship going to Europe, but that's not realistic.</p>
      <p>"Shippers deserve better."</p>
      <p>He said the company would review the situation over the weekend.</p>
      <p>SAT Albatros, another Dubai-based sea-air outfit, has suspended all rate agreements and added a $1 per kg surcharge on all live shipments.</p>
      <p>It has also suspended sea-air traffic via Singapore and Dubai into the US and its service from Singapore to Europe, the US and South Africa. Only its Dubai-Europe service is available.</p>
      <p>The company told customers: "We are monitoring the situation carefully and will keep you updated. All cargo that is on the way to transit hubs on all routes for uplifting, we will individually advise revised costing and routing amendment.</p>
      <p>"In Dubai, the situation has also changed overnight. Many flights have been taken out and rate levels are moving upwards heavily. All airfreight agreements have been cancelled with immediate effect.</p>
      <p>"It will also affect the shipments we have on hand; shipments that are on the sea or even arrived in Dubai."</p>
      <p>"In order to ensure live shipments are uplifted, we've implemented a short-term emergency surcharge of $1 per kg effective immediately. All existing rate agreements are temporarily suspended. Applicable rates are now to be confirmed on booking."</p>
      <p>However, one UK-based forwarder said it was still operating sea-air services via Dubai, and that "rates are still a fraction of air freight from Far East/China currently".</p>
      <p>He added that Singapore still had passenger carriers operating and that rates there "had not fluctuated much", although reduced flights by the major Chinese carriers would add some pressure.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>4c5682</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/business/airfreight-rates/baltic-exchange-to-add-airfreight-pricing-index/</url>
    <title>Baltic Exchange to add airfreight pricing index</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-17T11:33:56+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>business</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Baltic Exchange</topic>
      <topic>Freight Investor Services</topic>
      <topic>Tac Index</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Derivatives trading platform Baltic Exchange will adopt TAC Index airfreight rate data to publish its first index of airfreight prices along major air trade lanes. </p>
      <p>The Baltic Exchange, which traces its routes back to the 1700s, provides benchmark assessments for the maritime markets which are used to settle billions of dollars-worth of derivatives and physical trades every year.</p>
      <p>The Baltic Exchange will undertake a rigorous review of the TAC Index's methodology and processes with a view to establishing a governance structure which will make the index compliant with UK's Financial Conduct Authority's rules for benchmarks.</p>
      <p>A subsidiary of the Singapore Exchange (SGX), endorsement by the Baltic Exchange opens the pathway for International Organization of Securities Commissions approvals and cleared market trading.</p>
      <p>The news was welcomed by derivatives broker Freight Investor Services (FIS), particularly give the current market volatility.</p>
      <p>FIS traded the first Air Freight Forward Agreements (AFFAs) in August 2019.</p>
      <p>TAC Index Managing Director John Peyton Burnett said: "We are very excited to be partnering with the Baltic Exchange. TAC Index has seen its air freight indices become the primary price benchmarks for carriers, lessors, shippers, forwarders and end-buyers globally.</p>
      <p>"The partnership with the Baltic Exchange will drive further integration of air freight into the global commodity markets and put the indices at the heart of a substantial new global forward freight market."</p>
      <p>FIS managing director John Banaszkiewicz said: "The COVID-19 pandemic has thrust air cargo into the spotlight in the short term, however the inability of airfreight businesses to adapt to price volatility and uncertainty have been persistent features of the market historically.</p>
      <p>"In what is a turbulent time for supply chains globally with China to Europe rates rising 147% from February to April, the opportunity now exists for next-generation price risk management."</p>
      <p>Using derivatives can help businesses hedge their exposure to offer more certainty and protect against market drop offs.</p>
      <p>However, they can also limit a company's ability to benefit from an upswing.</p>
      <p>"The timing is right for the airfreight sector to start hedging its risk in volume and with support from several key physical market businesses, the premise for liquidity is strong," added Peter Stallion, FIS Airfreight Derivatives broker.</p>
      <p>"Building on what has been achieved so far, FIS will look to use 2020 to drive market-wide support and involvement, facilitating trading that supports the goals of businesses as we move into a highly uncertain decade."</p>
      <p>The global airfreight market is estimated to be worth $100bn, with 65m tonnes of general cargo moved by air annually.</p>
      <p>Baltic Exchange chief executive Mark Jackson added: "Our status as a regulated benchmark administrator opens up all sorts of possibilities for the air freight market.</p>
      <p>"We are confident that the index will provide a completely independent and uncompromised view of the air freight market and the audited Index will become listed by financial clearing houses. This would provide the industry with new ways of managing its freight rate risk and potentially bring in new market participants."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
</corpus>
