<corpus>
  <document>
    <document_id>1330d5</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/freight-forwarder/geodis-the-latest-forwarder-to-launch-charter-services/</url>
    <title>Geodis the latest forwarder to launch charter services</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T11:45:57+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>freight-forwarder</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>CEVA Logistics</topic>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Dachser</topic>
      <topic>DSV Panalpina</topic>
      <topic>Geodis</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Geodis has become the latest forwarder to launch charter services as it looks to secure air cargo capacity for its customers.</p>
      <p>The SNCF-owned company said that ocean freight continues to be disrupted and air cargo options severely restricted by established passenger carriers cancelling scheduled flights i light of the corona outbreak.</p>
      <p>It has therefore launched a series of air charter flights. The first flight departed from Frankfurt on a one-way operation to Shanghai on February 12.</p>
      <p>In order to facilitate the resurgence in westbound freight out of China, the forwarder followed up on February 21 with the first round-trip service departing from Liege, again with the destination Shanghai Pudong International.</p>
      <p>As of February 28 weekly round-trip flights were established from Frankfurt, with Shanghai departures each Tuesday.</p>
      <p>This schedule will remain in place throughout the month of March, when consideration of a further extension will be made, and is being complemented by flights from Hong Kong to Europe. It will also offer flights from Hong Kong to Guadalajara in March. </p>
      <p>Also, immediately following the decision by US authorities to close its borders to visitors from Europe and to prepare for the consequent sharp decrease in commercial cargo capacity, the company has established a return air charter programme linking Amsterdam and Chicago on a four flights a week schedule. The first flight from Amsterdam will be on March 21.</p>
      <p>Geodis also continues to offer its rail solutions from major cities in China. Two options are scheduled from Xi'an and Chongqing to the German destinations of Hamburg and Duisburg.  The standard services have an 18 day transit time and from Xi'an to Hamburg an express, 12-day solution is provided.  Return routings are also available.</p>
      <p>Geodis is not the only forwarder to have launched airfreight charter operations in recent weeks, with Dachser, Bollore, DSV Panalpina and Ceva all launching services (see links above).</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>d3806f</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/handling-agents-the-cornerstone-of-air-cargo-in-these-times/</url>
    <title>Handling agents – the cornerstone of air cargo in these times</title>
    <author>James Graham</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-08T09:34:30+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Cargo Handling News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>CDG</topic>
      <topic>ECS Group</topic>
      <topic>GSH</topic>
      <topic>Paris</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Paris-based ECS Group pays tribute to the remarkable work of the teams at Global Services Handling (GSH), a French air cargo handling company based at Roissy Charles de Gaulle (CDG) airport in France. Despite the difficulties GSH is facing in this period of unprecedented crisis, ECS Group is highlighting the essential nature of handling and handling teams, without whom airfreight forwarding would quite simply be impossible.</p>
      <p>"As in all sectors, we need to reorganize the way we work because of the crisis, with one further difficulty: remote working isn't possible with goods handling. Our staff levels are down by around 25% but we are continuing to operate 24 hours a day, 7 days a week. We are 100% operational thanks to our extremely hard-working employees. Our priority is still to make sure that cargo leaves and arrives in total safety," says Pierre Perez, GSH's managing director.</p>
      <p>Airlines are doing everything they can to offer more capacity: increasing the number of all-cargo flights, converting passenger flights into freighters, demonstrating greater flexibility, and more – which makes handling agents vital players in ensuring the continuity of the supply chain. Without them, it would be impossible to receive and load cargo, which in turn would also make air freight forwarding impossible.</p>
      <p>In addition to the increased risks and greater workload as a result of reduced staffing levels, GSH's agents also have to tackle the unpredictable nature of flight scheduling. Flight schedules fluctuate from day to day. With extra flights being operated and others postponed, cancelled or delayed for regular flights and even more so for repatriation and all-cargo flights, flexibility and versatility are essential.</p>
      <p>But Perez describes: "An amazing sense of team spirit, togetherness and solidarity" among his colleagues.</p>
      <p>"We're all pulling together – we know that our work is essential in order to transport goods and keep the local and global economy running. Helping to save lives by transporting medical products is also a real source of motivation."</p>
      <p>This remarkable work not only plays a crucial role in transporting goods, it also ensures the continuity of the supply chain and maintains the airfreight ecosystem on which all stakeholders are totally interdependent.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>17f7a5</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/lufthansa-strips-out-seats-to-create-extra-cargo-space/</url>
    <title>Lufthansa strips out seats to create extra cargo space</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-14T10:16:51+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Austrian Airlines</topic>
      <topic>Lufthansa</topic>
      <topic>Lufthansa Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Lufthansa will take out the seats from several of its aircraft as it looks to create space to carry extra cargo.</p>
      <p>The move is part of wider efforts to expand cargo capacity through the addition of extra services to meet a capacity crunch.</p>
      <p>The airline said that in co-operation with sister company Austrian Airlines it will add 51 weekly cargo flights from Germany and Austria to Asia.</p>
      <p>At present, 14 flights a week with Boeing 777F widebody freighters, with a standard load capacity of around 103 tons, operate between Frankfurt and the Chinese mainland.</p>
      <p>From Easter onwards, 35 weekly flights with Lufthansa passenger aircraft will be added exclusively for cargo transport. Since the cabin space of these aircraft can also be loaded with cargo, this results in an average capacity of about 30 tons each in practice.</p>
      <p>Specifically, there will be two daily connections from Frankfurt to Shanghai (PVG) and one daily connection to Beijing (PEK) with Airbus A330-300 aircraft. One Airbus A350-900 each will take off from Munich daily to Shanghai (PVG) and Beijing (PEK).</p>
      <p>In order to further increase the possible cargo volume, especially for the transport of comparatively light goods such as protective masks, parts of the cabin interior, including seats, of initially four Lufthansa aircraft will be removed.</p>
      <p>In Austria, Austrian Airlines is expected to provide 16 flights a week from Vienna International Airport for the transport of cargo from Easter onwards. Shanghai (PVG) will be served eight times a week, Beijing (PEK) five times, Penang (PEN) two times and Xiamen (XMN) once a week. Passenger jets of the type Boeing 767-300 and Boeing 777-200 will be used.</p>
      <p>Lufthansa is not the first airline to remove seats in order to create extra space for cargo. At the start of April, EL AL removed the passenger seats from some of its Boeing 777 aircraft to enable higher volumes of cargo to be transported.</p>
      <p>This step was taken ahead of the carrier ceasing all of its passenger flights on April 4, 2020, due to low demand and travel restrictions caused by the coronavirus.</p>
      <p>The removal of the seats in the passenger aircraft allows the aircraft to carry around 50 tons of cargo.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>d2f49e</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/people/fta-hires-senior-transport-advisor-to-bolster-covid-19-logistics-support/</url>
    <title>FTA hires senior transport advisor to bolster Covid-19 logistics support</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-14T12:35:23+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>people</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>FTA</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>FTA has appointed a new senior transport advisor, Becky Martin, within its Member Advice Centre (MAC) to assist the team in supporting logistics businesses during the Covid-19 outbreak.</p>
      <p>Martin has 12 years' experience working in transport, distribution and retail, and previously held advisory roles at John Lewis Partnership and Marks &amp; Spencer.</p>
      <p>FTA's MAC provides expert advice and answers members' questions on legal, technical and operational matters, on topics including Covid-19 and Brexit.</p>
      <p>On her new role, Martin commented: "I am so excited to be joining FTA; the MAC team are well-known in the industry for their unrivalled knowledge of the legal, technical and operational matters pertaining to logistics and I'm delighted to be joining such a knowledgeable group of advisers.</p>
      <p>"Working together, we will be able to help our members through the challenges of Covid-19, along with many other issues."</p>
      <p>Robert Saunders, manager of MAC at FTA, added: "With so many conditions changing in the market on a daily basis at the moment, it is unsurprising that we are experiencing record numbers of calls to support members during the Covid-19 outbreak.</p>
      <p>"With Martin's in-depth understanding of transport and logistics – in addition to her exceptional customer service skills – we are thrilled to have her join the team to help us assist businesses through the challenging times ahead, from Covid-19, Brexit and beyond."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>f24354</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/ups-enhances-singapore-healthcare-supply-chain-capabilities/</url>
    <title>UPS enhances Singapore healthcare supply chain capabilities</title>
    <author>James Graham</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T10:45:52+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Asia News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>CEIV Pharma certificate</topic>
      <topic>IATA</topic>
      <topic>Singapore</topic>
      <topic>UPS</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>UPS's freight forwarding operation at Changi Airport, Singapore has received IATA CEIV Pharma Certification for pharmaceutical logistics. The certification is the first for UPS in Asia Pacific and strengthens the value proposition of UPS's healthcare logistics offering in the region. It is a further validation of its capabilities in the safe, secure and efficient transportation of high-value pharmaceutical products.</p>
      <p>IATA's CEIV Pharma Certification is an industry certification developed by IATA, regulators and aviation industry stakeholders. It evaluates companies on a comprehensive range of criteria including quality management systems, facilities, equipment, operations and staff expertise.</p>
      <p>"Pharmaceuticals are time and temperature-sensitive, requiring an extra amount of care throughout the transportation process. These are not typical packages, and at times life-saving deliveries as well. This certification is an affirmation of the high standards of handling and transportation that UPS's customers in the healthcare and life sciences sector have come to rely on for their high-value shipments," said Lim Bee Koong, director, Healthcare Strategy, UPS Asia Pacific.</p>
      <p>"Our continual upgrades and technology investments give us a high degree of visibility over the healthcare supply chain. It's this customer-first focus that has helped pave the way for our IATA CEIV Pharma Certification."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>ed3c16</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/jack-ma-foundation-alibaba-foundation-fly-medical-supplies-to-us-africa-spain-slovenia-and-france-in-fight-against-covid-19-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>Jack Ma Foundation, Alibaba Foundation fly medical supplies to US, Africa, Spain, Slovenia and France in fight against Covid-19</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T13:59:00+05:30</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>In its ongoing efforts to contain the spread of Covid-19 and provide aid to afflicted communities across the globe, the Jack Ma Foundation and Alibaba Foundation have committed to sending medical supplies, including masks and test kits, to the US, Africa, Spain, Slovenia and France.</p>
      <p>On his personal Twitter page, Alibaba Group founder Jack Ma stressed the importance of staying one step ahead as the effects of the coronavirus pandemic continue to ripple across the globe.</p>
      <p>The foundations sent 500,000 test kits and one million masks to the US and were received by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, in Spain, with the support of King Felipe VI and the Spanish Ministry of Health, Consumer Affairs and Social Welfare, the foundations were able to deliver an initial batch of 500,000 masks from Shanghai to Zaragoza Airport. Additional supplies are due to arrive in Spain over the next few days.</p>
      <p>On March 18, another cargo plane carrying medical masks departed from Hangzhou and arrived at Liege Airport. A portion of these donated supplies will go to frontline medical staff in Belgium. Also on the chartered flight were masks for Slovenia and France. According to the foundations, Slovenia's Department of Defense and France's Ministère des Affaires sociales et de la Santé provided crucial support in the delivery of these supplies.</p>
      <p>Another day, another flight! One more plane carrying 1.5 million masks has landed in Liege Airport, Belgium. These supplies will be delivered to France, Slovenia and Belgium. More supplies will be delivered to Liege! COVID-19 is still spreading. We need to be faster! pic.twitter.com/Msd7KYAdUd— Jack Ma Foundation (@foundation_ma) March 18, 2020</p>
      <p>The foundations have also committed to donating 100,000 medical masks, 20,000 test kits and 1,000 protective suits to each of the 54 nations on the African continent. The medical supplies donated by the Jack Ma Foundation and Alibaba Foundation will be delivered to Addis Ababa, the capital of Ethiopia, where Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed Ali has agreed to take the lead in overseeing their distribution to other African countries. The foundations also announced plans to provide online training materials to help medical institutions in Africa cope with coronavirus cases.</p>
      <p>Earlier this month, the Jack Ma Foundation and Alibaba Foundation jointly donated surgical masks to Japan and South Korea. The foundations have also sent test kits and masks to European countries, including Italy and Belgium.</p>
      <p>The foundations have also provided funding to establishments such as the Peter Doherty Institute for Infection and Immunity in Australia and Columbia University in the US to support research into coronavirus vaccines and treatment.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>91d1fb</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/cargoguide-launches-new-online-rate-management-platform-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>Cargoguide launches new online rate management platform</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T15:50:00+05:30</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Cargoguide has officially unveiled its new online rate management platform, as part of its mission to simplify rate management and boost global freight forwarding.</p>
      <p>The new platform is a feature-rich search engine for the freight forwarding sector and enables forwarders to meet the key challenges they face in their day-to-day sales operations by increasing transparency and efficiency.</p>
      <p>It builds on the success of its predecessor Cargo Office. The new Cargoguide enables forwarders to compare accurate air freight rates including surcharges, create better rate calculations by including detailed shipment information in the search, create and send custom quotes quickly and easily from within the system and track and manage sales opportunities.</p>
      <p>Cargoguide already works with more than 1,500 forwarders in over 84 countries. Compared to traditional paper-based and scattered digital spreadsheets, Cargoguide allows users to save an average of two hours per day. In addition, as a cloud-based solution, it has no installation time. It can be used to work remotely and provides up-to-date rates and flight schedules. Allowing for simplified rate management, enhanced productivity and ultimately increasing margins.</p>
      <p>Bas van der Putten, growth manager, Cargoguide said, "We believe the freight forwarding process should be transparent, neutral and conducted within a fair market. Cargoguide is the next step in helping make that a reality.</p>
      <p>"This is an exciting time for us and for digital technology in the wider freight forwarding sector. It is however a challenging time for many freight forwarders and carriers, as they look to meet the demands of modern customers while remaining competitive."</p>
      <p>"That's where Cargoguide can add real value. We understand that forwarders and carriers need a platform that connects them through rates and that is continuously innovating and growing with them. The transparent rate calculations and accuracy of Cargoguide's data is unique and truly sets us apart from other platforms."</p>
      <p>Jorre Cobelens, founder and managing director, Cargoguide International, added, "We've established great partnerships over the years, working with the Carriers, GSAs and forwarders as their independent partner. Having created a standard for comparable freight rates since 2003, the platform allows carriers to market their capacity and forwarders to easily compare freight rates.</p>
      <p>"Our mantra is 'Dare to Improve', continuing to innovate and boost global freight forwarding. With our dedicated teams and niche software, we strive to maintain the highest reliability standards. This is an exciting time for us as we enhance our service."</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>4a4202</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/democrats-urge-boeing-to-accept-government-aid/</url>
    <title>Democrats urge Boeing to accept government aid</title>
    <author>James Graham</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-08T08:38:07+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Boeing News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Boeing</topic>
      <topic>Democratic Party</topic>
      <topic>Washington State</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>US House Democrats representing Washington state have urged Boeing to accept US government aid to help weather the Coronavirus pandemic after the planemaker's chief executive balked at the possibility of government equity stakes in exchange for the relief.</p>
      <p>Federal attorney Nick Oberheiden says a government shutdown to commercial passenger travel is very likely. As a representative of pilots and with insights into the FAA, Nick can expand on concerns for the aviation industry as many expect a government order to ground those flights.</p>
      <p>Oberheiden says: "Airlines are looking to work with the FAA and ultimately what I have seen is that airlines are concerned that if they shut down on their own accord, they may risk being part of the stimulus package."</p>
      <p>An ordered grounding of all flights was last seen after 9/11 and a very different situation. Oberheiden notes any form of a shutdown will need to be taken in little gradual steps rather than an abrupt ceasing of flights.</p>
      <p>Responsible for employing about 750,000 people, there is a concern to do something uncoordinated with the government to risk either a smaller or no portion result of the stimulus package.</p>
      <p>The airline industry will suffer regardless if they stay open or not, says Oberheiden, because passengers are not flying as much. Pilots are concerned for their safety right now as they are continuing to work in tight spaces and travel.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>1e2287</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/air-freight-sector-pushes-hard-to-help-and-for-help-to-fight-the-virus/</url>
    <title>Air freight sector pushes hard to help – and for help – to fight the virus</title>
    <author>Alex Lennane</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:30:44+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>IAG Cargo</topic>
      <topic>IATA</topic>
      <topic>Lufthansa Cargo</topic>
      <topic>TIACA</topic>
      <topic>Turkish Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>As Tiaca and Iata continue to lobby governments to relax restrictions on cargo movements, airlines are looking for ways to keep shipments flying.</p>
      <p>IAG Cargo sent a note to customers yesterday, offering its passenger aircraft for charters.</p>
      <p>"To support your freight and to help get it where it needs to be, we are now opening up the opportunity for freight forwarders to charter our aircraft where needed," wrote chief commercial officer John Cheetham.</p>
      <p>Lufthansa Cargo also looked to try to reassure customers.</p>
      <p>"We are doing everything in our power to keep our freighter services stable. On the other side, the extensive changes within our network of passenger flights have a direct impact on the available belly capacities. In order to compensate for these shortfalls, changes in the scheduling of our cargo aircraft are also likely in the coming days."</p>
      <p>It told customers developments were "too dynamic" and urged them to visit its website or Twitter feed to learn of daily flight changes.</p>
      <p>"We will also inform you about currently bookable connections via our API interface and our network page," it added. "We regret the necessary adjustments to the flight schedule and the inconvenience caused – and thank you for your commitment and cooperation in these challenging times."</p>
      <p>Turkish Cargo said it was increasing its freighter frequencies to "full capacity", while also using passenger aircraft for cargo demand.</p>
      <p>"Turkish Cargo will start to serve for cargo transport purposes by making use of the aircraft available in its fleet, in addition to its current cargo freighter capacity, which was increased to 25 from 13 during the last four years."</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, Tiaca this morning joined Iata in lobbying governments for support.</p>
      <p>"The air cargo industry has a decisive role to play in the fight against Covid-19 and the industry's voice must be fully heard by regulators and governments," it said</p>
      <p>"This is why Tiaca has joined the ICAO technical group on joint actions related to Covid-19, other members of which are the WHO, Iata, ACI and GEA."</p>
      <p>It said its goal was to draw attention to the critical role of air cargo, but also to the financial challenges facing the industry. It cited lease payments on aircraft, salaries, energy supplies and other payments, as well as difficulties stemming from travel bans, crew movement restrictions, airport slots and route changes.</p>
      <p>"We support Iata's appeal to have air cargo recognised as vital in the fight against Covid-19, and for action to be taken – in particular, removing all travel restrictions on air cargo operations and taking all necessary measures to allow air cargo to continue to circulate around the world," said Steven Polmans, Tiaca chairman.</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>3cb96d</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/freight-forwarder/hong-kong-logistics-groups-ask-for-rent-relief/</url>
    <title>Hong Kong logistics groups ask for rent relief</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-04-14T10:59:32+00:00</published_time>
    <categories>
      <category>freight-forwarder</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Ten Hong Kong freight and logistics organisations have issued an appeal to landlords to provide the industry with rental relief in light of the enormous negative impact of the Covid-19 outbreak on the industry.</p>
      <p>The organisations argue that the freight and logistics industry is being hit hard by the ongoing Covid-19 pandemic, with the global supply chain severely interrupted.</p>
      <p>They say that 95% of the shipments are cancelled, put on hold or disrupted, and that operators are facing unprecedented threats, tremendous risk of payment defaults and liquidity difficulties.</p>
      <p>"Without timely relief from landlords' high rental costs at this critical moment, it is estimated that a substantial number of SMEs and micro companies operating within the industry will close down or go bankrupt, forcing tens of thousands of workers out of jobs," the groups said.</p>
      <p>"With trading and logistics operations forming one of the four pillars of Hong Kong industry, and cargo throughput topping the list worldwide, the sector occupies substantial office and warehouse space in the city.</p>
      <p>"Leasing of these office premises and warehouse space accounts for the largest proportion of costs in the freight logistics industry. The huge pressure of rental commitments is a deciding factor in determining the survival of a considerable percentage of operators."</p>
      <p>The ten freight and logistics bodies have appealed for the support of landlords in the form of temporary rental relief to help the industry weather the current tumultuous economic environment.</p>
      <p>"The key role of freight logistics operators is to ensure the supply of food, necessities and other goods for Hong Kong citizens and communities affected by Covid-19.</p>
      <p>"It is vital to the future of the industry and to the wider economy, including leasing and rental businesses, to work together to ensure survival in order to be able to maintain the delivery of shipments to users and consumers. Immediate, temporary rental relief is vital, and would go a long way towards tiding the industry over the current crisis."</p>
      <p>Ten freight &amp; logistics bodies (in alphabetical order) are: Federation of Hong Kong Industries Group 21 – Transport &amp; Logistics Services Council (TLSC); Guangdong and Hong Kong Feeder Association (GHKFAL); Hong Kong Association of Aircargo Truckers (HAAT); Hong Kong Association of Freight Forwarding and Logistics (HAFFA); Hong Kong Logistics Association (HKLA); Hong Kong Logistics Management Staff Association (HKLMSA); Hong Kong Sea Transport and Logistics Association (HKSTLA); The Chamber of Hong Kong Logistics Industry (CHKLI); The Chartered Institute of Logistics and Transport in Hong Kong (CILTHK) and The Institute of Purchasing &amp; Supply of Hong Kong (IPSHK).</p>
    </content>
    <terms/>
  </document>
</corpus>
