<corpus>
  <document>
    <document_id>04c1fb</document_id>
    <url>https://aircargoworld.com/allposts/virus-stresses-air-traffic-with-closures-in-midwest-new-york/</url>
    <title>Virus stresses air-traffic with closures in Midwest, New York</title>
    <author>Bloomberg News</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Airports</category>
      <category>Bloomberg</category>
      <category>News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>air traffic control (ATC)</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA)</topic>
      <topic>jfk</topic>
      <topic>LAS</topic>
      <topic>MDW</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Flights over parts of the Midwest were being rerouted Friday and the tower at one of New York’s airports temporarily closed in the latest disruptions to the U.S. aviation system as Covid-19 spread to the federal employees responsible for the air-traffic system.</p>
      <p>Several routes for cross-country traffic were shut by the Federal Aviation Administration after a supervisor tested positive at the agency’s Indianapolis Center, which oversees high-altitude traffic across several states. Flights were handled by other controllers at the same facility, the FAA said in an emailed statement.</p>
      <p>Separately, controllers at New York’s John F. Kennedy International Airport tower are being forced to work in an alternate location after a technician at the facility tested positive for the Covid-19 virus. The airport remains open as the FAA cleans the tower as a precaution, the agency said.</p>
      <p>Such disruptions are relatively routine in the air-traffic system and the FAA has long-standing backup procedures to handle them. But the actions on Friday show how quickly the potent coronavirus is spreading and disrupting critical infrastructure.</p>
      <p>The impacts of earlier virus-related shutdowns at Chicago’s Midway and Las Vegas McCarran International airports continue to reverberate across the system. More than 1,100 flights were canceled at just those two airports as of 11:10 a.m. Eastern Time, according to the flight-tracking website FlightAware.</p>
      <p>About 20% of flights at JFK were also canceled, 259 in total, according to the website. It wasn’t clear how many of the cancellations were due to the tower closure as airlines have been halting international flights in response to the virus, which has cut demand for travel.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>420326</document_id>
    <url>https://aircargoworld.com/allposts/lufthansa-to-cut-95-of-flights-in-survival-mode/</url>
    <title>Lufthansa to cut 95% of flights in survival mode</title>
    <author>Bloomberg News</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Americas</category>
      <category>Asia Pacific</category>
      <category>Carriers</category>
      <category>EMEA</category>
      <category>News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics/>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>(Bloomberg) –Four of the world’s leading airlines laid bare the devastation the coronavirus is inflicting on travel, with three major carriers parking nearly 2,000 planes and Qantas Airways Ltd. temporarily laying off close to 30,000 staff in some of the industry’s deepest cuts to date.</p>
      <p>The measures at Deutsche Lufthansa AG, Europe’s biggest carrier, go furthest, with Chief Executive Officer Carsten Spohr saying he’ll idle 700 aircraft and 95% of seats, shrinking the flight schedule to a level last seen in 1955. Delta Air Lines Inc. is grounding half its fleet to wipe out 70% of capacity, while American Airlines Group Inc. will park 450 aircraft as it cuts international and domestic routes. Qantas is ceasing international operations.</p>
      <p>“The coronavirus has placed the entire global economy and our company in an unprecedented state of emergency,” Spohr said. “No one can foresee the consequences. We have to counter this extraordinary situation with drastic and sometimes painful measures.”</p>
      <p>The cuts highlight the desperation gripping airlines as they shrink operations amid a collapse in demand and moves to close national borders. For many operators that means mothballing the business and taking draconian steps to stop cash draining away while the virus retains its grip. Even then, the sector may need $200 billion in state support to weather the pandemic, according to the International Air Transport Association.</p>
      <p>U.S. carriers are seeking $58 billion in government loan guarantees, grants and tax relief.</p>
      <p>“The longer this crisis lasts, the more likely it is that the future of aviation cannot be guaranteed without state aid,” Spohr said, after new bookings at Lufthansa for the week through March 15 fell almost 70%.</p>
      <p>American’s parked aircraft, representing 29% of its fleet, come as it slashes international flying by 75% and domestic by 30%. That means cutting more than 55,000 April flights, with more reductions coming in May, President Robert Isom told workers in a message Thursday. The Fort Worth, Texas-based carrier is offering voluntary unpaid leaves and early retirement to help trim spending.</p>
      <p>“This is a crisis unlike any we’ve faced in the past,” Isom said. “While these steps are unparalleled, we expect demand to fall even more before it gets better.”</p>
      <p>Delta CEO Ed Bastian told staff Wednesday that revenue this month will drop by almost $2 billion from a year earlier, with April projected to be even worse. About 10,000 Delta workers have applied for voluntary leave and 5,000 flight attendants have agreed to take early retirement.</p>
      <p>“Making swift decisions now to reduce the losses and preserve cash will provide us the resources to rebound from the other side of this crisis,” Bastian said in a memo released by the airline.</p>
      <p>Qantas furloughed most of its 30,000-strong workforce. The Australian company and low-cost unit Jetstar will suspend overseas services from late March until at least the end of May, it said Thursday, with domestic operations cut 60%.</p>
      <p>CEO Alan Joyce said in a note to employees that demand had evaporated. “We have no work for most of our people,” he said. “We have to make difficult decisions to guarantee the future of the national carrier.”</p>
      <p>Qantas Furloughs Most Employees and Halts All Overseas Flights</p>
      <p>Lufthansa is expected to seek a loan from the government, which could take a stake as part of a rescue package, Bloomberg News reported Friday. Spohr said talks have been held with a state bank but that no bailout is needed right now.</p>
      <p>The group’s Italian arm, Air Dolimiti, has already halted flights, while the Austrian brand is set to ground operations and a Belgian division will follow suit in two days. The Swiss unit is parking planes at an airport near Zurich.</p>
      <p>(Updates with American Airlines details in seventh paragraph)</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>3701f9</document_id>
    <url>https://aircargoworld.com/allposts/iata-calls-on-govt-support-pandemic/</url>
    <title>IATA calls on governments to support air cargo during pandemic</title>
    <author>Chelsea Toczauer, News Editor</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Americas</category>
      <category>Asia Pacific</category>
      <category>EMEA</category>
      <category>Freight Trends</category>
      <category>Humanitarian</category>
      <category>News</category>
      <category>Security</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>IATA</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>The International Air Transport Association (IATA) has called on governments to take urgent measures to support the air cargo industry in performing its critical role in global efforts to contain the spread of COVID-19.</p>
      <p>Since the crisis began, air cargo has been a vital partner for governments in delivering medicines and medical equipment, including spare parts and repair components, and in keeping global supply chains functioning for time-sensitive materials. Air cargo has also proved instrumental in transporting food and other products purchased online, thereby facilitating quarantine and social distancing policies implemented by states.</p>
      <p>However, with dramatic travel restrictions and the collapse of passenger demand severely limiting cargo capacity, IATA has called on governments to take urgent measures to ensure air cargo will be available to continue fighting the pandemic.</p>
      <p>“Over 185,000 passenger flights have been cancelled since the end of January in response to government travel restrictions,” said Alexandre de Juniac, IATA’s director general and CEO. “With this, vital cargo capacity has disappeared when it is most urgently needed in the fight against COVID-19. The world’s fleet of freighter aircraft has been mobilized to make up this capacity shortfall. Governments must take urgent measures to ensure that vital supply lines remain open, efficient and effective.”</p>
      <p>According to IATA, governments must see air cargo as an essential part of the fight against the pandemic and take the following actions:</p>
      <p>“As we fight a global health war against COVID-19, governments must take urgent action to facilitate air cargo. Keeping cargo flowing will save lives,” de Juniac concluded.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
</corpus>
