<corpus>
  <document>
    <document_id>c6bfba</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/services/charter-company/chapman-freeborn-and-magma-team-up-on-the-transatlantic/</url>
    <title>Chapman Freeborn and Magma team up on the transatlantic</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T17:15:47+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>services</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Avia Solutions Group</topic>
      <topic>Chapman Freeborn</topic>
      <topic>Magma Aviation</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Charter broker Chapman Freeborn has teamed up with sister company Magma Aviation to offer a series of transatlantic freighter flights.</p>
      <p>Magma Aviation will operate its B747Fs on nine weekly rotations from Europe to the US. The move comes following US president Donald Trump’s travel ban on 26 European countries, which resulted in a sharp drop in cargo capacity on the transatlantic.</p>
      <p>The Avia Solutions Group owned broker said: “Commodities such as food items, pharmaceutical goods, medical supplies, consumer goods etc. that would have typically travelled as belly freight on board passenger aircraft have now entered the ad-hoc cargo market, further tipping the balance of capacity/demand.</p>
      <p>“The capacity issue is exacerbated by the fact that many cargo aircraft are already dedicated to easing the current demand in Asia.”</p>
      <p>As well as the Magma aircraft, Chapman Freeborn has access to aircraft operated by other companies of Avia Solutions Group – Bluebird Nordic, Smartlynx, Avion Express and Klasjet.</p>
      <p>Kim Borgaard, Chapman Freeborn Scandinavia general manager, said: “We have seen a surge in requests for cargo into the US from across Europe. In fact, with the grounding of many passenger fleets, we have seen an increase in cargo demand across the board.</p>
      <p>“Wherever possible, we’re working with clients to consolidate cargo and sell capacity at an affordable rate. It’s times like these that Chapman Freeborn’s global office is a huge benefit – we can transport smaller movements by utilising capacity on booked part-charters.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>8ac79d</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/american-airlines-announces-cargo-only-pax-flights/</url>
    <title>American Airlines announces cargo-only PAX flights</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T11:57:37+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>American Airlines</topic>
      <topic>American Airlines Cargo</topic>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>American Airlines is the latest carriers to announce that it will use passenger aircraft for cargo-only operations.</p>
      <p>In a statement, American Airlines explained that its passenger aircraft, many of which had been grounded up to now because of low demand caused by the coronavirus outbreak, would be used to transport cargo between the US and Europe.</p>
      <p>The Boeing 777-300 used on the route will operate two round trips between Dallas Fort Worth International Airport (DFW) and Frankfurt Airport (FRA) over the course of four days. </p>
      <p>Cargo on the scheduled flights will include medical supplies, mail for those active in the US military, telecommunications equipment and electronics to support people working from home and e-commerce shipments.</p>
      <p>The flights will also provide much-needed cargo capacity for the airline’s regular cargo customers, allowing them to continue operating in what is currently a challenging market.</p>
      <p>American Airlines will also continue carrying cargo in the bellyhold aircraft flying domestically. </p>
      <p>Rick Elieson (pictured), president of cargo and vice president of international operations, commented: “Challenging times call for creative solutions and a team of people across the airline has been working nonstop to arrange cargo-only flight options for our customers.</p>
      <p>“We have a critical role to play in keeping essential goods moving during this unprecedented time and we are proud to do our part and find ways to continue to serve our customers and our communities.”</p>
      <p>Ken Jarrell, fleet service clerk, cargo services, at DFW, added: “It’s an honor to be part of these cargo-only flights. They represent much needed aid for the world and hope for our team. </p>
      <p>“Our team members across the airline are ready and willing to do what it takes to make sure people have the things they need during these unprecedented times.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>23fb98</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/forwarder-group-fiata-backs-iatas-cargo-push/</url>
    <title>Forwarder group FIATA backs IATA’s cargo push</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T11:56:56+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>FIATA</topic>
      <topic>IATA</topic>
      <topic>Tiaca</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Freight forwarder association FIATA has backed IATA’s efforts to ensure that airfreight is not affected by measures put in place to stop the spread of coronavirus.</p>
      <p>Earlier this week, IATA urged governments to take the following actions:</p>
      <p>In response, the forwarder group said: “Government’s do not appear to clearly understand that short term decisions will exacerbate the immediate and short-term ability of economies to meet the challenge of COVID-19 containment and then the economic rebuild.</p>
      <p>“As to those two critical needs, air cargo is vital in delivering emergency relief, medical technical infrastructure componentry and keeping global supply chains functioning with ‘just in time’ intervention.</p>
      <p>“Such delivery has been traditionally through dedicated cargo aircraft and high utilisation of capacity in passenger aircraft (bellyhold).</p>
      <p>“With passenger aircraft now denied cross border access such belly hold capacity has significantly declined, rates have become exorbitant and suppliers, through their international freight forwarder partners, now seeking to move goods through other compromised logistic chains.</p>
      <p>“As international airfreight is instrumental in transporting perishable, short shelf life goods and medical supplies it is time for all governments to address decisions that are counterproductive to the fight of COVID-19.”</p>
      <p>Yesterday, TIACA also came out in support of the IATA initiative.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>1330d5</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/freight-forwarder/geodis-the-latest-forwarder-to-launch-charter-services/</url>
    <title>Geodis the latest forwarder to launch charter services</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T11:45:57+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>freight-forwarder</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>CEVA Logistics</topic>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Dachser</topic>
      <topic>DSV Panalpina</topic>
      <topic>Geodis</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Geodis has become the latest forwarder to launch charter services as it looks to secure air cargo capacity for its customers.</p>
      <p>The SNCF-owned company said that ocean freight continues to be disrupted and air cargo options severely restricted by established passenger carriers cancelling scheduled flights i light of the corona outbreak.</p>
      <p>It has therefore launched a series of air charter flights. The first flight departed from Frankfurt on a one-way operation to Shanghai on February 12.</p>
      <p>In order to facilitate the resurgence in westbound freight out of China, the forwarder followed up on February 21 with the first round-trip service departing from Liege, again with the destination Shanghai Pudong International.</p>
      <p>As of February 28 weekly round-trip flights were established from Frankfurt, with Shanghai departures each Tuesday.</p>
      <p>This schedule will remain in place throughout the month of March, when consideration of a further extension will be made, and is being complemented by flights from Hong Kong to Europe. It will also offer flights from Hong Kong to Guadalajara in March. </p>
      <p>Also, immediately following the decision by US authorities to close its borders to visitors from Europe and to prepare for the consequent sharp decrease in commercial cargo capacity, the company has established a return air charter programme linking Amsterdam and Chicago on a four flights a week schedule. The first flight from Amsterdam will be on March 21.</p>
      <p>Geodis also continues to offer its rail solutions from major cities in China. Two options are scheduled from Xi’an and Chongqing to the German destinations of Hamburg and Duisburg.  The standard services have an 18 day transit time and from Xi’an to Hamburg an express, 12-day solution is provided.  Return routings are also available.</p>
      <p>Geodis is not the only forwarder to have launched airfreight charter operations in recent weeks, with Dachser, Bollore, DSV Panalpina and Ceva all launching services (see links above).</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>491f93</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/policy/tiaca/tiaca-wants-air-cargo-exempt-from-covid-19-travel-bans/</url>
    <title>TIACA wants air cargo exempt from Covid-19 travel bans</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T10:47:32+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>policy</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Tiaca</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>The International Air Cargo Association (TIACA) has called on governments to exempt air cargo from any bans because of the vital role it will play in the fight to stop the spread of the coronavirus.</p>
      <p>TIACA said that the air cargo industry has a decisive role to play in the fight against COVID-19 and the industry’s voice must be fully heard by regulators and governments.</p>
      <p>This is why TIACA has joined the ICAO Technical group on joint actions related to COVID-19.</p>
      <p>“The goal is clear: to draw attention both to the fundamental role that the air cargo industry plays and to the need to protect its continued existence and vitality,” the organisation said.</p>
      <p>“In the current major crisis, airfreight is essential for the transport of food, basic necessities and health-related products – in other words, everything necessary for people to survive. The global economy also needs airfreight to continue to supply businesses and factories.”</p>
      <p>TIACA said that airlines are facing multiple financial issues are emerging: Leasing payments for aircraft; salaries, energy supplies, and payments to service providers and equipment providers; taxation; and difficulties arising from uncoordinated travel bans, restrictions imposed on crew movements, airport slots and route changes, etc.</p>
      <p>“TIACA sees its role in the ICAO Technical Group as using ICAO’s mechanism to reach out to governments and remind them that air cargo is a significant contributor to the global economy and international trade and that it plays a very important role in preventing and battling the disastrous effect of coronavirus,” said Vladimir Zubkov, TIACA secretary general.</p>
      <p>“We support IATA’s appeal to have air cargo recognized as vital in the fight against COVID-19 and for action to be taken – in particular, removing all travel restrictions on air cargo operations and taking all necessary measures to allow air cargo to continue to circulate around the world,” said Steven Polmans, TIACA chairman.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>0b68b0</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/caribbean-cargo-suspends-two-freighter-services/</url>
    <title>Caribbean Cargo suspends two freighter services</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T10:15:16+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Caribbean Airlines Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>In light of the COVID-19 outbreak, Caribbean Airlines Cargo has temporarily suspended two of its freighter services, effective immediately.</p>
      <p>The carrier’s Tuesday service from Miami, US, to Kingston, Jamaica; and its Thursday service from Miami, US, to Port-of-Spain, Trinidad , via San Juan in Puerto Rico, are those that are affected.</p>
      <p>In  statement, the Caribbean Airlines Cargo also advised: “As we continue to optimize our operations given the impact of COVID 19 on international trade, we advise that we may experience flight consolidations or schedule changes to our freighter services”.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>464728</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/freighter-operator/turkish-cargo-ups-freighter-flights/</url>
    <title>Turkish Cargo ups freighter flights</title>
    <author></author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T20:16:17+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Turkish Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Turkish Cargo is increasing the frequencies of its freighter flights to keep customers’ supply chains moving on time.</p>
      <p>The airline said that in response to passenger flight capacity cuts – as a result of the coronavirus outbreak – it would utilise all “the freighters in its fleet in full capacity for the purpose of meeting all requirements of the exportation in Turkey as well as the foreign trade that is of critical importance”.</p>
      <p>Turkish Cargo said that its freighter fleet is the sixth largest in the world, having grown from 13 to 25 freighters over the last four years.</p>
      <p>The carrier said it would continue to serve as a partner for Turkish manufacturers and exporters while also complying with restrictions imposed by authorities.</p>
      <p>It said that as well as its freighters, other aircraft in the Turkish fleet would be made available.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>b0f91e</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/freight-forwarder/ups-achieves-ceiv-pharma-in-singapore/</url>
    <title>UPS achieves CEIV pharma in Singapore</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T12:20:02+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>freight-forwarder</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>UPS</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>The UPS freight forwarding operation at Changi Airport has received IATA CEIV Pharma certification for pharmaceutical logistics — a first for UPS in Asia Pacific.</p>
      <p>IATA’s CEIV Pharma certification is an industry certification developed by IATA, regulators and aviation industry stakeholders.</p>
      <p>The certification requires companies to meet or exceed many existing pharmaceutical standards and guidelines such as IATA Temperature Control Regulations, European Union Good Distribution Practices, World Health Organisation Annex 5 Good Distribution Practices for Pharmaceutical Products and United States Pharmacopeia Standards.</p>
      <p>“Pharmaceuticals are time and temperature-sensitive, requiring an extra amount of care throughout the transportation process. These are not typical packages, and at times life-saving deliveries as well. This certification is an affirmation of the high standards of handling and transportation that UPS’s customers in the healthcare and life sciences sector have come to rely on for their high-value shipments,” said Lim Bee Koong, director, healthcare strategy, UPS Asia Pacific.</p>
      <p>As a biomedical sciences hub for the Asia Pacific region, Singapore is home to eight of the top 10 pharmaceutical companies globally, manufacturing four of the top 10 drugs by global revenue.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>0da11f</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/sectors/pharma-logistics/wfs-handles-largest-single-shipment-at-paris-pharma-centre/</url>
    <title>WFS handles largest single shipment at Paris pharma centre</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T11:12:32+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>sectors</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>WFS</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Worldwide Flight Services’ (WFS) has handled 34 temperature-controlled containers at its new pharma centre at Paris Charles de Gaulle Airport (CDG) – its largest single shipment since it opened the €10 m facility late last year.</p>
      <p>The containers, which were handled on behalf of WFS’ customers AirBridgeCargo Airlines and Kuehne + Nagel, spent 24 to 48 hours at the pharma centre ahead of their delivery to China on an AirBridgeCargo Boeing 747 freighter.</p>
      <p>Hugo Rodrigues, vice president of cargo France, at WFS, explained: “This particular shipment for AirBridgeCargo and Kuehne + Nagel was the biggest so far and helped to demonstrate the capabilities of both the facility and our team.</p>
      <p>“Our decision to invest in this state-of-the-art facility to support our airline and freight forwarder customers, as well as the pharmaceutical industry, has already been validated by the strong demand we are seeing from so many different organisations.</p>
      <p>“With the need for pharma products all over the globe likely to soar in 2020, we will deliver the capacity and quality of service our customers need to ensure the integrity and efficiency of their pharma supply chains.”</p>
      <p>WFS’ pharma centre is the only dedicated facility of its kind at Paris CDG, the second largest airfreight hub in Europe.</p>
      <p>Features of the pharma centre include: a team of 30 experts onsite, temperature-controlled warehousing and handling services and a transport fleet that is suitable for moving pharmaceutical cargo.</p>
      <p>Currently, around 30 airlines and freight forwarding companies regularly use WFS’ pharma centre to support their cold chain shipments.</p>
      <p>WFS estimates that this year it will handle 8,000 tonnes of healthcare and life sciences products at its pharma centre.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>91fa7b</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/lufthansa-mulls-cargo-only-pax-flights-while-it-cuts-capacity/</url>
    <title>Lufthansa mulls cargo-only PAX flights while it cuts capacity</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T10:43:31+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Lufthansa</topic>
      <topic>Lufthansa Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>While announcing its 2019 financial results, Lufthansa said that it was considering using its idled passenger aircraft for freight-only flights while it also revealed drastic capacity cuts in response to the coronavirus.</p>
      <p>The German airline group said it would reduce capacity by 95%, parking up 700 aircraft, as part of measures to respond to the coronavirus.</p>
      <p>Deutsche Lufthansa chairman of the executive board Carsten Spohr said: “The spread of the coronavirus has placed the entire global economy and our company as well in an unprecedented state of emergency.</p>
      <p>“At present, no one can foresee the consequences. We have to counter this extraordinary situation with drastic and sometimes painful measures.”</p>
      <p>He added: “We are doing everything we can to bring as many passengers as possible home on relief flights. In addition, we are doing our utmost to help ensure that supply chains for many thousands of businesses do not break down by mobilising additional capacity for air freight transport.</p>
      <p>“The longer this crisis lasts, the more likely it is that the future of aviation cannot be guaranteed without state aid.”</p>
      <p>Lufthansa Cargo continues to fly its regular programme, except for cancellations to mainland China, keeping the entire freighter fleet in the air.</p>
      <p>This currently consists of seven Boeing 777Fs, six MD11Fs and four B777Fs from Aerologic.</p>
      <p>In addition, the company is currently examining the possibility of using passenger aircraft without passengers as pure cargo aircraft in order to further increase cargo capacity, it said.</p>
      <p>Looking at cargo performance last year, Lufthansa’s logistics division, which includes Lufthansa Cargo, ULD management firm Jettainer, its Aerologic JV with DHL, and time-critical forwarder time:matters, saw revenues decrease by €9m to €2.5bn and earnings before interest and tax (EBIT) slipped to a loss of €33m from a profit of €263m last year.</p>
      <p>“The airfreight industry is traditionally very volatile and saw declines across the market in 2019,” Lufthansa explained.</p>
      <p>“The political situation, especially the trade disputes and uncertainties related to the Brexit, had a significant impact on demand in the sector.</p>
      <p>“Despite reacting early to the challenging market situation and rapidly reducing its MD-11F fleet, Lufthansa Cargo was still unable to match its earnings in the previous two years.”</p>
      <p>Cargo traffic for the year was flat at 8.9bn revenue tonne kms, but the cargo load factor slipped by 4.6 percentage points to 61.3%.</p>
      <p>In terms of fleet in the reporting year, two more B777F aircraft joined the Lufthansa Cargo fleet and four MD-11F freighters were retired from service.</p>
      <p>The fleet modernisation is scheduled for completion by the end of 2020.</p>
      <p>From 2021 Lufthansa Cargo will then operate a uniform fleet of nine highly efficient B777F cargo aircraft. Lufthansa Cargo also brought another two leased B777F freighters into service at AeroLogic.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>b826bf</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/iag-offers-pax-aircraft-for-cargo-charter/</url>
    <title>IAG offers PAX aircraft for cargo charter</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T09:56:58+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>IAG</topic>
      <topic>IAG Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>IAG is offering its passenger to freight forwarders for cargo operations in response to the coronavirus.</p>
      <p>In a short note to customers, IAG Cargo chief commercial officer John Cheetham said: “To support your freight and to help get it where it needs to be, we are now opening up the opportunity for freight forwarders to charter our aircraft where needed.</p>
      <p>“As a business we are looking to move quickly to find working solutions for our customers. If you are interested and you need more information on charter capacity, please do get in touch with your local sales representative.”</p>
      <p>This comes as passenger operations have been cut, resulting in cargo capacity reductions.</p>
      <p>Earlier this week, IAG chief executive Willie Walsh said that governments “need to appreciate” that there is a strong cargo demand, and passenger aircraft carry a large proportion of global airfreight.</p>
      <p>“Our intention is to try and keep as much of our capacity available for critical supplies that need to be shipped around the world,” he said.</p>
      <p>“We may operate some of our passenger aircraft just for belly-hold cargo to ensure we keep critical supplies moving.”</p>
      <p>IAG is set to ground dozens of aircraft over April and May, equivalent to a 75% cut in capacity, in response to falling demand and restrictions imposed on travel.</p>
      <p>In the US, Delta Air Lines has also offered its aircraft up for cargo charter.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, Scoot is operating its passenger aircraft on behalf of sister company SIA Cargo and Cathay Pacific and Korea Air have confirmed that their aircraft are being used to carry cargo.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>cb2ecc</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/freight-forwarder/new-online-rate-platform-from-cargoguide/</url>
    <title>New online rate platform from Cargoguide</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T09:27:51+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>freight-forwarder</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Cargoguide</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Cargoguide has officially unveiled its new online rate management platform as part of efforts to simplify rate management.</p>
      <p>The new platform is a search engine for the freight forwarding sector and enables companies to meet the “key challenges they face in their day-to-day sales operations by increasing transparency and efficiency”.</p>
      <p>It enables users to compare airfreight rates, including surcharges; improve rate calculations by allowing the inclusion of detailed shipment information, create and send custom quotes, track and manage sales opportunities.</p>
      <p>It builds on predecessor Cargo Office, the first independently managed global rate solution with a pre-filled air rate database. Cargoguide already works with more than 1,500 forwarders in over 84 countries. </p>
      <p>As a cloud-based solution, it has no installation time and it can be used to work remotely and provides up-to-date rates and flight schedules.</p>
      <p>Bas van der Putten, growth manager, Cargoguide, said: “We believe the freight forwarding process should be transparent, neutral and conducted within a fair market. Cargoguide is the next step in helping make that a reality.</p>
      <p>“This is an exciting time for us and for digital technology in the wider freight forwarding sector. It is however a challenging time for many freight forwarders and carriers, as they look to meet the demands of modern customers while remaining competitive.”</p>
      <p>“We understand that forwarders and carriers need a platform that connects them through rates and that is continuously innovating and growing with them. The transparent rate calculations and accuracy of Cargoguide’s data is unique and truly sets us apart from other platforms.”</p>
      <p>Jorre Cobelens, founder and managing director, Cargoguide International, added: “We’ve established great partnerships over the years, working with the Carriers, GSAs and forwarders as their independent partner.</p>
      <p>“Having created a standard for comparable freight rates since 2003, the platform allows carriers to market their capacity and forwarders to easily compare freight rates.</p>
      <p>“We look forward to working with our customers to meet the challenges within the freight forwarding market – together.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>00eddc</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/freight-forwarder/damco-moves-into-new-heathrow-facility/</url>
    <title>DAMCO moves into new Heathrow facility</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T09:06:14+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>freight-forwarder</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Damco</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Freight forwarder DAMCO has moved into a new 36,000 sq ft warehouse at London’s Heathrow Airport as part of ongoing investment in its airfreight offering.</p>
      <p>The company has moved its airfreight operations into offices at the North Feltham Trading Estate, within three miles of Heathrow’s cargo terminal, to support a growing customer base of leading UK retailers.</p>
      <p>The bonded facility’s environmental credentials include a Building Research Establishment Environmental Assessment Method (BREEAM) rating of Excellent and a Grade A Energy Performance Certificate (EPC).</p>
      <p>“We are working with our clients closely to help reduce their CO2 footprint,” said Anthony Akerman, managing director, UK and Ireland, DAMCO.</p>
      <p>“Their focus on a triple bottom line to satisfy the goals of finance, environment, and ethical and social drivers to create sustainability means we need to remain creative in our approach.</p>
      <p>“By utilising our new facility, we will help to reduce CO2 on air shipments by consolidating clients’ cargo at origin in order to book on direct flights rather than use transhipment hubs.  </p>
      <p>“This  allows us to kill volumes on the shipments, providing similar non-direct pricing for cargo that actually flies on a direct flight, reducing the CO2 footprint.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>4f1b35</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/business/fedex-cancels-outlook-prepares-for-capacity-crunch/</url>
    <title>FedEx cancels outlook, prepares for capacity crunch</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T12:16:09+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>business</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>FedEx</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>FedEx has cancelled its outlook for 2020 and has warned that airfreight capacity on the transatlantic will come under pressure.</p>
      <p>When announcing its third-quarter results, the express giant said that the unpredictable nature of the market — as a result of the coronavirus outbreak — meant it would not provide an outlook for fiscal 2020.</p>
      <p>“We are suspending our fiscal 2020 earnings forecast for our consolidated and segment results due to the uncertainty caused by the coronavirus pandemic,” said Alan Graf, FedEx Corp executive vice president and chief financial officer.</p>
      <p>“To mitigate these near-term headwinds and position the company for future earnings growth, we are attacking costs throughout the company by managing capacity, retiring our oldest and least-efficient aircraft, integrating TNT Express, and lowering our residential delivery costs by having FedEx Ground deliver FedEx SmartPost and certain day-definite FedEx Express packages.”</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, FedEx is expecting the cargo capacity crunch being experienced on services to and from China to spread to the transatlantic as bellyhold capacity is removed from this market.</p>
      <p>Brie Carere, executive vice president, chief marketing and communications officer, said: “In China, we have seen a rebound week over week since March 3.</p>
      <p>“With the urgent need for stock replenishment and with air capacity shortage in the market, we believe demand will stay elevated. We continue to adjust transit times and spot prices specifically for China outbound to manage demand profitably.</p>
      <p>“We continue to increase the transit differentials between our premium and our economy services to encourage the use of premium service for any time-critical shipments, given the volatility in the market.</p>
      <p>“What started as a relief and recovery effort in China now unfortunately is global. The recently implemented travel ban between Europe and the US is expected to impact cargo capacity significantly since approximately 60% of the air freight capacity between Europe and the US are on passenger flights.</p>
      <p>“We are now employing the same strategies in other parts of the world that have helped us manage demand and capacity constraints in China, including transit time extensions, dynamic spot price management and will also leverage peak surcharges for specific lanes and periods of time as they are required.”</p>
      <p>On intra-Europe, meanwhile, FedEx said it would continue to run its air and ground networks but it is adjusting its network and extending some transit times due to lockdowns.</p>
      <p>Looking at fiscal third quarter financial performance, revenues increased by 2.9% to $17.5bn, operating income dropped by 54.9% to $411m and net income was down 57.4% to $315m.</p>
      <p>Operating results declined due to weaker global economic conditions including the impact of the coronavirus, higher self-insurance accruals, an unfavorable variable incentive compensation comparison, increased FedEx Ground costs from expanded service offerings, the loss of business from a large customer [Amazon], a continuing mix shift to lower-yielding services and a more competitive pricing environment.</p>
      <p>These factors were partially offset by the benefits from volume growth at FedEx Ground, an additional operating weekday, increased yields at FedEx Freight and the shifting of Cyber Week into December.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>e7feed</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/qatar-cargo-freighter-services-unaffected-despite-bellyhold-cuts/</url>
    <title>Qatar Cargo freighter services unaffected despite bellyhold cuts</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T11:15:11+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Qatar Airways</topic>
      <topic>Qatar Airways Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Qatar Airways Cargo announced that its cargo operations — specifically, freighter flights — will remain unaffected following the Qatar government’s recent instructions which state that with immediate effect, “entry to the State of Qatar is allowed for Qatari nationals only”.</p>
      <p>Qatari nationals travelling back to their country will be allowed to enter, but will then have to be quarantined for 14 days as a precaution against the coronavirus.</p>
      <p>Due to low passenger demand caused by the virus Qatar Airways has reduced its passenger flights to select countries, which in turn has reduced bellyhold capacity on these routes.</p>
      <p>However, the carrier explained: “We are working to rebook any cargo on the affected belly-hold flights to alternative flights and would like to assure you that we are doing as much as we can to reduce the impact to your business”.</p>
      <p>The carrier also added that its freighter aircraft services currently remain unaffected.</p>
      <p>“We thank you all for your understanding during these challenging times that we all are going through and appreciate your cooperation, trust and support. Customer-centricity continues to remain at the core of all our operations,” Qatar Airways Cargo said.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, Scoot, Korean Airways and Cathay Pacific are operating passenger aircraft for cargo-only operations to serve the growing need for freight to be moved between China and the rest of the world as factories increase productivity following the extended Chinese New Year break.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>80a101</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/cargo-airport/schiphol-open-for-freighters-following-slot-rule-change/</url>
    <title>Schiphol open for freighters following slot rule change</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T09:12:01+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>cargo-airport</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Amsterdam Airport Schiphol</topic>
      <topic>Schiphol</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Capacity constrained Amsterdam Schiphol Airport will be able to handle extra freighters following changes to slot rules in response to the coronavirus.</p>
      <p>Schiphol’s slot procedure has changed after Airport Coordination Netherlands (ACNL) temporarily lifted the Local Rule 2 (LR2) due to the global COVID-19 outbreak.</p>
      <p>Under LR2, the number of slots available for reallocation is limited, but the temporary lifting of the rule frees up freight operations.</p>
      <p>“In these difficult times, it is important that we work together to ensure that the supply chain keeps moving,” said Bart Pouwels, head of cargo, Amsterdam Airport Schiphol.</p>
      <p>“The lifting of LR2 will enable us to operate temporarily more ad hoc full-freighter flights at AMS, which is much needed to offset the current decline in belly capacity.”</p>
      <p>Effective immediately, ACNL will not use LR2 for ad-hoc slots to be allocated up to and including June 6.</p>
      <p>In addition, slots that have been handed back to the slot coordinator by passenger carriers who are not using them, are to be offered to full freighter operators first on an ad hoc basis until 6th June 2020.</p>
      <p>ACNL said that due to the proposed temporary 80/20 waiver, which required airlines to use 80% of their slots or risk losing them, it expects a large number of slots to be handed back.</p>
      <p>Over the last couple of years the airport had seen freighter operators move to nearby rivals because the airport had reached its slot limit and IATA rules favour regular passenger services.</p>
      <p>LR2 had been introduced to try and protect remaining freighter services, guaranteeing all-cargo airlines access to a limited number of unused slots.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>a62819</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/aei-to-convert-b737-for-nauru-airlines/</url>
    <title>AEI to convert B737 for Nauru Airlines</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T14:00:08+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Aeronautical Engineers Inc</topic>
      <topic>B737-300F</topic>
      <topic>Nauru Airlines</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Aeronautical Engineers, Inc (AEI) will provide Nauru Airlines with a 10-pallet position B737-300SF freighter conversion.</p>
      <p>The flag carrier airline of the Republic of Nauru will use the AEI B737-300SF freighter to transport fresh food, mail, medicines and other freight from various points in the Pacific. The freighter will also be used to support charter flights in the region.</p>
      <p>Modifications to the aircraft (MSN 28732) will begin at Commercial Jet’s Miami, Florida facility in late May 2020.</p>
      <p>The AEI-converted, 10-pallet configuration B737-300SF freighter offers a main deck payload of up to 19,460 kg and incorporates an Ancra CLS capable of carrying:</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>6d3bc3</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/business/dsv-panalpina-withdraws-2020-outlook/</url>
    <title>DSV Panalpina withdraws 2020 outlook</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T10:51:40+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>business</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>DSV Panalpina</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>DSV Panalpina has withdrawn its outlook for 2020 as market conditions remain hard to predict.</p>
      <p>The Copenhagen-based freight forwarder said that financial results for January were on budget but in February were around DKr150m lower than expected.</p>
      <p>“As a result of the current global outbreak of coronavirus, supply chains and the global transport and logistics markets are currently seeing a substantial negative impact,” it said.</p>
      <p>“During February, the impact was mainly related to transports from and to China, but now the impact on supply, demand and transport and logistics capacity is global. </p>
      <p>“Due to the changed outlook for the global supply chains and transport and logistics markets, we expect a negative impact on our business and financial performance in the coming months.</p>
      <p>“Given the rapid day-to-day developments in many markets, we are currently unable to accurately assess the magnitude of this short-term impact, and we thus withdraw our outlook for 2020 pending further clarification of the market developments and the actual financial impact on our business.”</p>
      <p>The company said, however, that it expects the ongoing integration of Panalpina, which it acquired last year, to continue as planned.  </p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>46a718</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/freighter-operator/etihad-cargo-to-expand-freighter-flights-to-key-asian-origins/</url>
    <title>Etihad Cargo to expand freighter flights to key origins</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T10:45:35+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Etihad Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Etihad Cargo is boosting freighter flights to Hong Kong, Hanoi and Singapore and several European destinations for the summer season as it looks to cater for capacity constrained markets.</p>
      <p>Etihad’s cargo division said that running from March 29 to October 28, it will double frequencies to Hong Kong to four flights per week, while Hanoi gains a third-weekly service and Singapore a second weekly flight.</p>
      <p>These additions complete the currently operated seasonal winter schedule across China, India and Bangladesh. </p>
      <p>In Europe, with two extra weekly freighter flights Amsterdam goes to five times weekly service, Milan moves to a twice-weekly turnaround freighter service, while Etihad Cargo will launch new freighter connections linking Abu Dhabi with Paris.</p>
      <p>The new freighter flights will depart Abu Dhabi International Airport for Paris Charles De Gaulle on Thursdays and Saturdays.</p>
      <p>The same day return services will add 200 tons of incremental weekly freight capacity between the UAE and the French capital.</p>
      <p>These services will be complemented by the increase in services into Johannesburg and Nairobi, to twice weekly.</p>
      <p>To North America, the airline will continue its twice-weekly service to Rickenbacker.</p>
      <p>The carrier said that the network changes reflect capacity-constrained markets that are wrestling with decreased passenger operations or temporary travel bans in light of the public health emergency caused by the novel coronavirus (COVID-19).</p>
      <p>Abdulla Mohamed Shadid, managing director cargo and logistics at Etihad Aviation Group, said: “With widespread commercial flight restrictions in numerous international markets, the air cargo environment is evolving daily.</p>
      <p>“After consulting closely with local and international authorities, our optimised summer freighter schedule is designed to significantly boost capacity and service customers in key cargo markets.”</p>
      <p>“Our sincerest thanks to our crew and staff that continue to make these operations possible. The safety of our pilots, loadmasters and ground staff is our number one priority. During these times, additional stringent measures in line with advisories from the UAE Ministry of Health, Abu Dhabi Department of Health, the UAE GCAA and WHO have been implemented, to safeguard the health and wellbeing of our team and main the highest standards of hygiene throughout the operations,” Shadid added.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>44bd0b</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/services/charter-company/ceva-logistics-operates-charters-to-maintain-asia-us-supply-chain/</url>
    <title>CEVA Logistics operates charters to maintain Asia-US supply chain</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T10:27:08+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>services</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>CEVA Logistics</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>CEVA Logistics has contracted 86 freighter flights to help maintain the global supply chain as the coronavirus outbreak continues.</p>
      <p>The company is using the aircraft on a charter basis to deliver parts and supplies to its customers in the automotive, aerospace, computer and hi-tech electronics sectors.</p>
      <p>The majority of flights served routes between Asia (Hong Kong, Shanghai, Bangkok and Singapore) and the US (Dallas, Rockford, Rickenbacker). Other charters served European cities, such as Amsterdam and Brussels.</p>
      <p>CEVA has already operated more than 58 flights – to transport more than 7,700 tonnes or airfreight – to provide urgent stock replenishment for those which could not otherwise be supplied.</p>
      <p>Over the next few weeks, it will operate 28 more charter flights.</p>
      <p>Guillaume Col, CEVA Logistics’ chief operating officer, commented: “Working extremely closely with our customers, we have been able to deliver a robust charter programme to adapt to these difficult circumstances.</p>
      <p>“Acting in close collaboration with the rest of the CMA CGM Group, we are striving to offer fast and accessible alternatives to our clients throughout the world in order to help keep the global economy moving.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
</corpus>
