<corpus>
  <document>
    <document_id>b0f91e</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/freight-forwarder/ups-achieves-ceiv-pharma-in-singapore/</url>
    <title>UPS achieves CEIV pharma in Singapore</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T12:20:02+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>freight-forwarder</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>UPS</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>The UPS freight forwarding operation at Changi Airport has received IATA CEIV Pharma certification for pharmaceutical logistics — a first for UPS in Asia Pacific.</p>
      <p>IATA’s CEIV Pharma certification is an industry certification developed by IATA, regulators and aviation industry stakeholders.</p>
      <p>The certification requires companies to meet or exceed many existing pharmaceutical standards and guidelines such as IATA Temperature Control Regulations, European Union Good Distribution Practices, World Health Organisation Annex 5 Good Distribution Practices for Pharmaceutical Products and United States Pharmacopeia Standards.</p>
      <p>“Pharmaceuticals are time and temperature-sensitive, requiring an extra amount of care throughout the transportation process. These are not typical packages, and at times life-saving deliveries as well. This certification is an affirmation of the high standards of handling and transportation that UPS’s customers in the healthcare and life sciences sector have come to rely on for their high-value shipments,” said Lim Bee Koong, director, healthcare strategy, UPS Asia Pacific.</p>
      <p>As a biomedical sciences hub for the Asia Pacific region, Singapore is home to eight of the top 10 pharmaceutical companies globally, manufacturing four of the top 10 drugs by global revenue.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>0da11f</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/sectors/pharma-logistics/wfs-handles-largest-single-shipment-at-paris-pharma-centre/</url>
    <title>WFS handles largest single shipment at Paris pharma centre</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T11:12:32+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>sectors</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>WFS</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Worldwide Flight Services’ (WFS) has handled 34 temperature-controlled containers at its new pharma centre at Paris Charles de Gaulle Airport (CDG) – its largest single shipment since it opened the €10 m facility late last year.</p>
      <p>The containers, which were handled on behalf of WFS’ customers AirBridgeCargo Airlines and Kuehne + Nagel, spent 24 to 48 hours at the pharma centre ahead of their delivery to China on an AirBridgeCargo Boeing 747 freighter.</p>
      <p>Hugo Rodrigues, vice president of cargo France, at WFS, explained: “This particular shipment for AirBridgeCargo and Kuehne + Nagel was the biggest so far and helped to demonstrate the capabilities of both the facility and our team.</p>
      <p>“Our decision to invest in this state-of-the-art facility to support our airline and freight forwarder customers, as well as the pharmaceutical industry, has already been validated by the strong demand we are seeing from so many different organisations.</p>
      <p>“With the need for pharma products all over the globe likely to soar in 2020, we will deliver the capacity and quality of service our customers need to ensure the integrity and efficiency of their pharma supply chains.”</p>
      <p>WFS’ pharma centre is the only dedicated facility of its kind at Paris CDG, the second largest airfreight hub in Europe.</p>
      <p>Features of the pharma centre include: a team of 30 experts onsite, temperature-controlled warehousing and handling services and a transport fleet that is suitable for moving pharmaceutical cargo.</p>
      <p>Currently, around 30 airlines and freight forwarding companies regularly use WFS’ pharma centre to support their cold chain shipments.</p>
      <p>WFS estimates that this year it will handle 8,000 tonnes of healthcare and life sciences products at its pharma centre.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>91fa7b</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/lufthansa-mulls-cargo-only-pax-flights-while-it-cuts-capacity/</url>
    <title>Lufthansa mulls cargo-only PAX flights while it cuts capacity</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T10:43:31+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Lufthansa</topic>
      <topic>Lufthansa Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>While announcing its 2019 financial results, Lufthansa said that it was considering using its idled passenger aircraft for freight-only flights while it also revealed drastic capacity cuts in response to the coronavirus.</p>
      <p>The German airline group said it would reduce capacity by 95%, parking up 700 aircraft, as part of measures to respond to the coronavirus.</p>
      <p>Deutsche Lufthansa chairman of the executive board Carsten Spohr said: “The spread of the coronavirus has placed the entire global economy and our company as well in an unprecedented state of emergency.</p>
      <p>“At present, no one can foresee the consequences. We have to counter this extraordinary situation with drastic and sometimes painful measures.”</p>
      <p>He added: “We are doing everything we can to bring as many passengers as possible home on relief flights. In addition, we are doing our utmost to help ensure that supply chains for many thousands of businesses do not break down by mobilising additional capacity for air freight transport.</p>
      <p>“The longer this crisis lasts, the more likely it is that the future of aviation cannot be guaranteed without state aid.”</p>
      <p>Lufthansa Cargo continues to fly its regular programme, except for cancellations to mainland China, keeping the entire freighter fleet in the air.</p>
      <p>This currently consists of seven Boeing 777Fs, six MD11Fs and four B777Fs from Aerologic.</p>
      <p>In addition, the company is currently examining the possibility of using passenger aircraft without passengers as pure cargo aircraft in order to further increase cargo capacity, it said.</p>
      <p>Looking at cargo performance last year, Lufthansa’s logistics division, which includes Lufthansa Cargo, ULD management firm Jettainer, its Aerologic JV with DHL, and time-critical forwarder time:matters, saw revenues decrease by €9m to €2.5bn and earnings before interest and tax (EBIT) slipped to a loss of €33m from a profit of €263m last year.</p>
      <p>“The airfreight industry is traditionally very volatile and saw declines across the market in 2019,” Lufthansa explained.</p>
      <p>“The political situation, especially the trade disputes and uncertainties related to the Brexit, had a significant impact on demand in the sector.</p>
      <p>“Despite reacting early to the challenging market situation and rapidly reducing its MD-11F fleet, Lufthansa Cargo was still unable to match its earnings in the previous two years.”</p>
      <p>Cargo traffic for the year was flat at 8.9bn revenue tonne kms, but the cargo load factor slipped by 4.6 percentage points to 61.3%.</p>
      <p>In terms of fleet in the reporting year, two more B777F aircraft joined the Lufthansa Cargo fleet and four MD-11F freighters were retired from service.</p>
      <p>The fleet modernisation is scheduled for completion by the end of 2020.</p>
      <p>From 2021 Lufthansa Cargo will then operate a uniform fleet of nine highly efficient B777F cargo aircraft. Lufthansa Cargo also brought another two leased B777F freighters into service at AeroLogic.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>b826bf</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/iag-offers-pax-aircraft-for-cargo-charter/</url>
    <title>IAG offers PAX aircraft for cargo charter</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T09:56:58+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>IAG</topic>
      <topic>IAG Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>IAG is offering its passenger to freight forwarders for cargo operations in response to the coronavirus.</p>
      <p>In a short note to customers, IAG Cargo chief commercial officer John Cheetham said: “To support your freight and to help get it where it needs to be, we are now opening up the opportunity for freight forwarders to charter our aircraft where needed.</p>
      <p>“As a business we are looking to move quickly to find working solutions for our customers. If you are interested and you need more information on charter capacity, please do get in touch with your local sales representative.”</p>
      <p>This comes as passenger operations have been cut, resulting in cargo capacity reductions.</p>
      <p>Earlier this week, IAG chief executive Willie Walsh said that governments “need to appreciate” that there is a strong cargo demand, and passenger aircraft carry a large proportion of global airfreight.</p>
      <p>“Our intention is to try and keep as much of our capacity available for critical supplies that need to be shipped around the world,” he said.</p>
      <p>“We may operate some of our passenger aircraft just for belly-hold cargo to ensure we keep critical supplies moving.”</p>
      <p>IAG is set to ground dozens of aircraft over April and May, equivalent to a 75% cut in capacity, in response to falling demand and restrictions imposed on travel.</p>
      <p>In the US, Delta Air Lines has also offered its aircraft up for cargo charter.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, Scoot is operating its passenger aircraft on behalf of sister company SIA Cargo and Cathay Pacific and Korea Air have confirmed that their aircraft are being used to carry cargo.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>cb2ecc</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/freight-forwarder/new-online-rate-platform-from-cargoguide/</url>
    <title>New online rate platform from Cargoguide</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T09:27:51+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>freight-forwarder</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Cargoguide</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Cargoguide has officially unveiled its new online rate management platform as part of efforts to simplify rate management.</p>
      <p>The new platform is a search engine for the freight forwarding sector and enables companies to meet the “key challenges they face in their day-to-day sales operations by increasing transparency and efficiency”.</p>
      <p>It enables users to compare airfreight rates, including surcharges; improve rate calculations by allowing the inclusion of detailed shipment information, create and send custom quotes, track and manage sales opportunities.</p>
      <p>It builds on predecessor Cargo Office, the first independently managed global rate solution with a pre-filled air rate database. Cargoguide already works with more than 1,500 forwarders in over 84 countries. </p>
      <p>As a cloud-based solution, it has no installation time and it can be used to work remotely and provides up-to-date rates and flight schedules.</p>
      <p>Bas van der Putten, growth manager, Cargoguide, said: “We believe the freight forwarding process should be transparent, neutral and conducted within a fair market. Cargoguide is the next step in helping make that a reality.</p>
      <p>“This is an exciting time for us and for digital technology in the wider freight forwarding sector. It is however a challenging time for many freight forwarders and carriers, as they look to meet the demands of modern customers while remaining competitive.”</p>
      <p>“We understand that forwarders and carriers need a platform that connects them through rates and that is continuously innovating and growing with them. The transparent rate calculations and accuracy of Cargoguide’s data is unique and truly sets us apart from other platforms.”</p>
      <p>Jorre Cobelens, founder and managing director, Cargoguide International, added: “We’ve established great partnerships over the years, working with the Carriers, GSAs and forwarders as their independent partner.</p>
      <p>“Having created a standard for comparable freight rates since 2003, the platform allows carriers to market their capacity and forwarders to easily compare freight rates.</p>
      <p>“We look forward to working with our customers to meet the challenges within the freight forwarding market – together.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>00eddc</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/freight-forwarder/damco-moves-into-new-heathrow-facility/</url>
    <title>DAMCO moves into new Heathrow facility</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T09:06:14+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>freight-forwarder</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Damco</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Freight forwarder DAMCO has moved into a new 36,000 sq ft warehouse at London’s Heathrow Airport as part of ongoing investment in its airfreight offering.</p>
      <p>The company has moved its airfreight operations into offices at the North Feltham Trading Estate, within three miles of Heathrow’s cargo terminal, to support a growing customer base of leading UK retailers.</p>
      <p>The bonded facility’s environmental credentials include a Building Research Establishment Environmental Assessment Method (BREEAM) rating of Excellent and a Grade A Energy Performance Certificate (EPC).</p>
      <p>“We are working with our clients closely to help reduce their CO2 footprint,” said Anthony Akerman, managing director, UK and Ireland, DAMCO.</p>
      <p>“Their focus on a triple bottom line to satisfy the goals of finance, environment, and ethical and social drivers to create sustainability means we need to remain creative in our approach.</p>
      <p>“By utilising our new facility, we will help to reduce CO2 on air shipments by consolidating clients’ cargo at origin in order to book on direct flights rather than use transhipment hubs.  </p>
      <p>“This  allows us to kill volumes on the shipments, providing similar non-direct pricing for cargo that actually flies on a direct flight, reducing the CO2 footprint.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>4f1b35</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/business/fedex-cancels-outlook-prepares-for-capacity-crunch/</url>
    <title>FedEx cancels outlook, prepares for capacity crunch</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T12:16:09+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>business</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>FedEx</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>FedEx has cancelled its outlook for 2020 and has warned that airfreight capacity on the transatlantic will come under pressure.</p>
      <p>When announcing its third-quarter results, the express giant said that the unpredictable nature of the market — as a result of the coronavirus outbreak — meant it would not provide an outlook for fiscal 2020.</p>
      <p>“We are suspending our fiscal 2020 earnings forecast for our consolidated and segment results due to the uncertainty caused by the coronavirus pandemic,” said Alan Graf, FedEx Corp executive vice president and chief financial officer.</p>
      <p>“To mitigate these near-term headwinds and position the company for future earnings growth, we are attacking costs throughout the company by managing capacity, retiring our oldest and least-efficient aircraft, integrating TNT Express, and lowering our residential delivery costs by having FedEx Ground deliver FedEx SmartPost and certain day-definite FedEx Express packages.”</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, FedEx is expecting the cargo capacity crunch being experienced on services to and from China to spread to the transatlantic as bellyhold capacity is removed from this market.</p>
      <p>Brie Carere, executive vice president, chief marketing and communications officer, said: “In China, we have seen a rebound week over week since March 3.</p>
      <p>“With the urgent need for stock replenishment and with air capacity shortage in the market, we believe demand will stay elevated. We continue to adjust transit times and spot prices specifically for China outbound to manage demand profitably.</p>
      <p>“We continue to increase the transit differentials between our premium and our economy services to encourage the use of premium service for any time-critical shipments, given the volatility in the market.</p>
      <p>“What started as a relief and recovery effort in China now unfortunately is global. The recently implemented travel ban between Europe and the US is expected to impact cargo capacity significantly since approximately 60% of the air freight capacity between Europe and the US are on passenger flights.</p>
      <p>“We are now employing the same strategies in other parts of the world that have helped us manage demand and capacity constraints in China, including transit time extensions, dynamic spot price management and will also leverage peak surcharges for specific lanes and periods of time as they are required.”</p>
      <p>On intra-Europe, meanwhile, FedEx said it would continue to run its air and ground networks but it is adjusting its network and extending some transit times due to lockdowns.</p>
      <p>Looking at fiscal third quarter financial performance, revenues increased by 2.9% to $17.5bn, operating income dropped by 54.9% to $411m and net income was down 57.4% to $315m.</p>
      <p>Operating results declined due to weaker global economic conditions including the impact of the coronavirus, higher self-insurance accruals, an unfavorable variable incentive compensation comparison, increased FedEx Ground costs from expanded service offerings, the loss of business from a large customer [Amazon], a continuing mix shift to lower-yielding services and a more competitive pricing environment.</p>
      <p>These factors were partially offset by the benefits from volume growth at FedEx Ground, an additional operating weekday, increased yields at FedEx Freight and the shifting of Cyber Week into December.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>e7feed</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/qatar-cargo-freighter-services-unaffected-despite-bellyhold-cuts/</url>
    <title>Qatar Cargo freighter services unaffected despite bellyhold cuts</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T11:15:11+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Qatar Airways</topic>
      <topic>Qatar Airways Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Qatar Airways Cargo announced that its cargo operations — specifically, freighter flights — will remain unaffected following the Qatar government’s recent instructions which state that with immediate effect, “entry to the State of Qatar is allowed for Qatari nationals only”.</p>
      <p>Qatari nationals travelling back to their country will be allowed to enter, but will then have to be quarantined for 14 days as a precaution against the coronavirus.</p>
      <p>Due to low passenger demand caused by the virus Qatar Airways has reduced its passenger flights to select countries, which in turn has reduced bellyhold capacity on these routes.</p>
      <p>However, the carrier explained: “We are working to rebook any cargo on the affected belly-hold flights to alternative flights and would like to assure you that we are doing as much as we can to reduce the impact to your business”.</p>
      <p>The carrier also added that its freighter aircraft services currently remain unaffected.</p>
      <p>“We thank you all for your understanding during these challenging times that we all are going through and appreciate your cooperation, trust and support. Customer-centricity continues to remain at the core of all our operations,” Qatar Airways Cargo said.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, Scoot, Korean Airways and Cathay Pacific are operating passenger aircraft for cargo-only operations to serve the growing need for freight to be moved between China and the rest of the world as factories increase productivity following the extended Chinese New Year break.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>80a101</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/cargo-airport/schiphol-open-for-freighters-following-slot-rule-change/</url>
    <title>Schiphol open for freighters following slot rule change</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T09:12:01+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>cargo-airport</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Amsterdam Airport Schiphol</topic>
      <topic>Schiphol</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Capacity constrained Amsterdam Schiphol Airport will be able to handle extra freighters following changes to slot rules in response to the coronavirus.</p>
      <p>Schiphol’s slot procedure has changed after Airport Coordination Netherlands (ACNL) temporarily lifted the Local Rule 2 (LR2) due to the global COVID-19 outbreak.</p>
      <p>Under LR2, the number of slots available for reallocation is limited, but the temporary lifting of the rule frees up freight operations.</p>
      <p>“In these difficult times, it is important that we work together to ensure that the supply chain keeps moving,” said Bart Pouwels, head of cargo, Amsterdam Airport Schiphol.</p>
      <p>“The lifting of LR2 will enable us to operate temporarily more ad hoc full-freighter flights at AMS, which is much needed to offset the current decline in belly capacity.”</p>
      <p>Effective immediately, ACNL will not use LR2 for ad-hoc slots to be allocated up to and including June 6.</p>
      <p>In addition, slots that have been handed back to the slot coordinator by passenger carriers who are not using them, are to be offered to full freighter operators first on an ad hoc basis until 6th June 2020.</p>
      <p>ACNL said that due to the proposed temporary 80/20 waiver, which required airlines to use 80% of their slots or risk losing them, it expects a large number of slots to be handed back.</p>
      <p>Over the last couple of years the airport had seen freighter operators move to nearby rivals because the airport had reached its slot limit and IATA rules favour regular passenger services.</p>
      <p>LR2 had been introduced to try and protect remaining freighter services, guaranteeing all-cargo airlines access to a limited number of unused slots.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>a62819</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/aei-to-convert-b737-for-nauru-airlines/</url>
    <title>AEI to convert B737 for Nauru Airlines</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T14:00:08+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Aeronautical Engineers Inc</topic>
      <topic>B737-300F</topic>
      <topic>Nauru Airlines</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Aeronautical Engineers, Inc (AEI) will provide Nauru Airlines with a 10-pallet position B737-300SF freighter conversion.</p>
      <p>The flag carrier airline of the Republic of Nauru will use the AEI B737-300SF freighter to transport fresh food, mail, medicines and other freight from various points in the Pacific. The freighter will also be used to support charter flights in the region.</p>
      <p>Modifications to the aircraft (MSN 28732) will begin at Commercial Jet’s Miami, Florida facility in late May 2020.</p>
      <p>The AEI-converted, 10-pallet configuration B737-300SF freighter offers a main deck payload of up to 19,460 kg and incorporates an Ancra CLS capable of carrying:</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>6d3bc3</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/business/dsv-panalpina-withdraws-2020-outlook/</url>
    <title>DSV Panalpina withdraws 2020 outlook</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T10:51:40+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>business</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>DSV Panalpina</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>DSV Panalpina has withdrawn its outlook for 2020 as market conditions remain hard to predict.</p>
      <p>The Copenhagen-based freight forwarder said that financial results for January were on budget but in February were around DKr150m lower than expected.</p>
      <p>“As a result of the current global outbreak of coronavirus, supply chains and the global transport and logistics markets are currently seeing a substantial negative impact,” it said.</p>
      <p>“During February, the impact was mainly related to transports from and to China, but now the impact on supply, demand and transport and logistics capacity is global. </p>
      <p>“Due to the changed outlook for the global supply chains and transport and logistics markets, we expect a negative impact on our business and financial performance in the coming months.</p>
      <p>“Given the rapid day-to-day developments in many markets, we are currently unable to accurately assess the magnitude of this short-term impact, and we thus withdraw our outlook for 2020 pending further clarification of the market developments and the actual financial impact on our business.”</p>
      <p>The company said, however, that it expects the ongoing integration of Panalpina, which it acquired last year, to continue as planned.  </p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>46a718</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/freighter-operator/etihad-cargo-to-expand-freighter-flights-to-key-asian-origins/</url>
    <title>Etihad Cargo to expand freighter flights to key origins</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T10:45:35+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Etihad Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Etihad Cargo is boosting freighter flights to Hong Kong, Hanoi and Singapore and several European destinations for the summer season as it looks to cater for capacity constrained markets.</p>
      <p>Etihad’s cargo division said that running from March 29 to October 28, it will double frequencies to Hong Kong to four flights per week, while Hanoi gains a third-weekly service and Singapore a second weekly flight.</p>
      <p>These additions complete the currently operated seasonal winter schedule across China, India and Bangladesh. </p>
      <p>In Europe, with two extra weekly freighter flights Amsterdam goes to five times weekly service, Milan moves to a twice-weekly turnaround freighter service, while Etihad Cargo will launch new freighter connections linking Abu Dhabi with Paris.</p>
      <p>The new freighter flights will depart Abu Dhabi International Airport for Paris Charles De Gaulle on Thursdays and Saturdays.</p>
      <p>The same day return services will add 200 tons of incremental weekly freight capacity between the UAE and the French capital.</p>
      <p>These services will be complemented by the increase in services into Johannesburg and Nairobi, to twice weekly.</p>
      <p>To North America, the airline will continue its twice-weekly service to Rickenbacker.</p>
      <p>The carrier said that the network changes reflect capacity-constrained markets that are wrestling with decreased passenger operations or temporary travel bans in light of the public health emergency caused by the novel coronavirus (COVID-19).</p>
      <p>Abdulla Mohamed Shadid, managing director cargo and logistics at Etihad Aviation Group, said: “With widespread commercial flight restrictions in numerous international markets, the air cargo environment is evolving daily.</p>
      <p>“After consulting closely with local and international authorities, our optimised summer freighter schedule is designed to significantly boost capacity and service customers in key cargo markets.”</p>
      <p>“Our sincerest thanks to our crew and staff that continue to make these operations possible. The safety of our pilots, loadmasters and ground staff is our number one priority. During these times, additional stringent measures in line with advisories from the UAE Ministry of Health, Abu Dhabi Department of Health, the UAE GCAA and WHO have been implemented, to safeguard the health and wellbeing of our team and main the highest standards of hygiene throughout the operations,” Shadid added.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>44bd0b</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/services/charter-company/ceva-logistics-operates-charters-to-maintain-asia-us-supply-chain/</url>
    <title>CEVA Logistics operates charters to maintain Asia-US supply chain</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T10:27:08+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>services</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>CEVA Logistics</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>CEVA Logistics has contracted 86 freighter flights to help maintain the global supply chain as the coronavirus outbreak continues.</p>
      <p>The company is using the aircraft on a charter basis to deliver parts and supplies to its customers in the automotive, aerospace, computer and hi-tech electronics sectors.</p>
      <p>The majority of flights served routes between Asia (Hong Kong, Shanghai, Bangkok and Singapore) and the US (Dallas, Rockford, Rickenbacker). Other charters served European cities, such as Amsterdam and Brussels.</p>
      <p>CEVA has already operated more than 58 flights – to transport more than 7,700 tonnes or airfreight – to provide urgent stock replenishment for those which could not otherwise be supplied.</p>
      <p>Over the next few weeks, it will operate 28 more charter flights.</p>
      <p>Guillaume Col, CEVA Logistics’ chief operating officer, commented: “Working extremely closely with our customers, we have been able to deliver a robust charter programme to adapt to these difficult circumstances.</p>
      <p>“Acting in close collaboration with the rest of the CMA CGM Group, we are striving to offer fast and accessible alternatives to our clients throughout the world in order to help keep the global economy moving.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>fd2018</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/china-airfreight-rates-continue-to-surge/</url>
    <title>China airfreight rates continue to surge</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T09:50:34+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Freight Investor Services</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Airfreight rates out of China have rapidly increased over the last week, but thoughts are now turning to the impact of lower consumer demand in Europe and the US.</p>
      <p>The latest TAC Index figures show that average airfreight rates on services from Shanghai to the US last week increased by 29.7% on the prior week to reach $4.71 per kg. On services from Shanghai to Europe there was a 17.7% week on week increase to $3.19 per kg.</p>
      <p>From Hong Kong to the US there was a 10.4% week on week increase to $3.70 per kg and from Hong Kong to Europe prices were up 10.8% to $2.86 per kg.</p>
      <p>The price increases come as factories in China continue to ramp up production following the extended New Year break and passenger airlines have slashed capacity as result of lower demand.</p>
      <p>It is estimated that flight cancellations have removed more than 5,100 tons of capacity from China per day on average.</p>
      <p>Peter Stallion of air cargo derivatives broker said that freighter operators looked set to benefit from the lack of bellyhold capacity.</p>
      <p>However, he warned that with Europe and the US now introducing social distancing measures, consumer demand could weaken.</p>
      <p>“The dramatic shift in price generated by a severe lack of belly freight capacity, lifting pent up cargo-throughput that was previously bottle-necked in Asia, will be a welcome reprieve from the pain freighter operators endured in 2019.”</p>
      <p>He added: “Even with events such as the 2015 US west coast port strikes in recent memory, COVID-19 has now become an exceptionally disruptive event for supply chains globally.</p>
      <p>“Upstream problems have now become downstream problems, as imports from Asia will now hit slack consumer demand in Europe and North America.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>46b6d1</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/business/neutral-air-partner-adds-24-7-support-desk/</url>
    <title>Neutral Air Partner adds 24/7 support desk</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T09:40:20+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>business</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Neutral Air Partner</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Air cargo network Neutral Air Partner has added a 24/7 support desk to help members trying to meet coronavirus challenges.</p>
      <p>NAP and its time-critical sub group, NAX 24-7, said the support centre will provide assistance and solutions, helping its members connect with the right partners and service providers.</p>
      <p>“Following the increasing and overwhelming flight bans and commercial restrictions due to Covid-19, there will be a need for emergency and time critical supply chain solutions,” NAP said.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>361661</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/iata/iata-highlights-airfreights-importance-in-fight-against-coronavirus/</url>
    <title>IATA highlights airfreight’s importance in fight against coronavirus</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-16T19:49:39+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>IATA</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>IATA has highlighted the importance of airfreight in the global fight against the coronavirus outbreak and has called on governments to take “urgent measures” to ensure that supply chains are maintained in the global fight against COVID-19.</p>
      <p>The Association noted that the airfreight industry has so far helped to deliver essential medical equipment, such as protective clothing and masks and spare parts for medical machinery, as well as time-sensitive and perishable cargo, such as different varieties of foods.</p>
      <p>In a statement, IATA explained: “This has been done through dedicated cargo freighter operations, utilisation of cargo capacity in passenger aircraft and with relief flights to affected areas.”</p>
      <p>IATA’s announcement was made as airlines cancelled selected flights over the past few days due to low passenger demand caused by the virus outbreak, which in turn limited cargo capacity.</p>
      <p>Alexandre de Juniac, IATA’s director general and chief executive explained: “Over 185,000 passenger flights have been cancelled since the end of January in response to government travel restrictions. With this, vital cargo capacity has disappeared when it is most urgently needed in the fight against COVID-19.</p>
      <p>“The world’s fleet of freighter aircraft has been mobilized to make up this capacity shortfall. Governments must take urgent measures to ensure that vital supply lines remain open, efficient and effective.”</p>
      <p>IATA urged governments to take the following actions:</p>
      <p>“Air cargo carriers are working closely with governments and health organizations around the world to safeguard public health while also keeping the global economy moving. Today, as we fight a global health war against COVID-19, governments must take urgent action to facilitate air cargo. Keeping cargo flowing will save lives,” said de Juniac.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>ac02b3</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/delta-cargo-launches-charter-services-in-response-to-covid-19/</url>
    <title>Delta Cargo launches charter services in response to COVID-19</title>
    <author>Rachelle Harry</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-16T19:41:15+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>charter</topic>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Delta Air Lines</topic>
      <topic>Delta Air Lines Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Delta Cargo, the airfreight division of Delta Air Lines, has launched a charter operation to provide “safe and reliable transportation of customers’ goods” during the ongoing coronavirus outbreak.</p>
      <p>The company’s cargo arm will facilitate the chartering of any Delta mainline aircraft to and from participating US airports.</p>
      <p>Shawn Cole, vice president, Delta Cargo, explained in a statement: “Serving our customers and communities where we live, work and serve, is part of Delta’s DNA. Offering new supply chain solutions through Delta Cargo to our customers is one opportunity for us to provide the support our customers tell us they need during this unprecedented business environment.”</p>
      <p>Thirteen US airports are participating in Delta Cargo’s charter operation, as well as more than 70 international airports.</p>
      <p>Delta Cargo’s announcement comes as freight forwarders brace for capacity shortages on the transatlantic as airlines axe capacity between Europe and the US.</p>
      <p>The 13 US airports are:</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>544d4e</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/freighter-operator/air-partner-expects-charter-market-surge/</url>
    <title>Air Partner expects charter market surge</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-16T17:36:59+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Partner</topic>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Charter broker Air Partner has urged companies to book cargo transport early to keep supply chains moving in light of the coronavirus.</p>
      <p>The company said that it has reported a spike in demand while capacity is in short supply as passenger airlines have axed services.</p>
      <p>Air Partner chief executive Mark Briffa said: “We’re seeing a spike in airfreight service requests as many commercial flights are being grounded and at a time when Chinese industrial production is restarting after a month-long shutdown. There is still immediate charter availability, but we foresee that could change in the coming weeks.”</p>
      <p>The broker said that is has access to any freight aircraft between North America and Europe or between North America and China, or South East Asia, “at a moment’s notice”.</p>
      <p>“If availability does decrease, prices will surge,” it warned. “As such, to reduce risk and guarantee availability, Air Partner recommends companies secure aircraft charter solutions as soon as they are needed.”</p>
      <p>It warned that freight rates from China have already begun to increase as demand increases.</p>
      <p>Figures from the latest TAC Index show airfreight prices from Shanghai to North America increased by 32.3% from a week earlier to $4.02 per kg, while prices from the Chinese city to Europe jumped by 15.8% compared with the prior seven days to $2.71 per kg.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, prices from Hong Kong to North America increased by 11.5% week on week to $3.59 per kg and there was a 3.2% increase to $2.58 per kg on services to Europe.</p>
      <p>On the capacity side, Air Partner warned that the US travel ban for Europeans would cause an immediate negative impact on availability and significant increase in pricing for cargo capacity to Europe for at least 30 days.</p>
      <p>For China, it said available cargo capacity from China is down 39% versus last year and flight cancellations on routes to China have removed close to 5,000 tons per day of capacity, with belly capacity down by 85% and maindeck capacity down by 12%.</p>
      <p>It added that more than 40 airlines have temporarily suspended operations to and from China to-date and this is likely to continue to rise with no estimated date to recommence commercial airline operations.</p>
      <p>“With China beginning to slowly ramp up production again, it will take some time for scheduled freight operators to readjust their capacities to normal schedule,” the broker said. </p>
      <p>“During the coronavirus outbreak, Air Partner has seen a large increase in urgent freight requests from companies seeking to transport a number of different commodities between North America, Asia and Europe.” </p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>5243f2</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/freighter-operator/volga-dnepr-group-ready-to-face-market-challenges/</url>
    <title>Volga-Dnepr Group ready to face market challenges</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-16T14:49:47+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>AirBridgeCargo</topic>
      <topic>Coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Volga-Dnepr</topic>
      <topic>Volga-Dnepr Group</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>The Volga-Dnepr Group says it is ready to meet the current challenges faced by the air cargo market.</p>
      <p>In an interview with Air Cargo News, Volga-Dnepr executive president, charter operations, Konstantin Vekshin, said that the group is well positioned to meet any coronavirus-related cargo capacity shortages.</p>
      <p>He explained that in late January, the company had started anticipate the complications that the virus would cause in terms of how to protect crew and make sure equipment was properly sanitised.</p>
      <p>In terms of capacity, the airline group currently operates 16 Boeing 747s, eight An-124s and three IL-76s across AirBridgeCargo and Volga-Dnepr.</p>
      <p>It previously operated 21 B747s but this has been reduced in line with the market conditions at the end of last year.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, one of its An-124s has had its capacity upgraded by 30 tonnes to 150 tonnes and another will be increased by the end of May.</p>
      <p>Four have also been upgraded in terms of avionics to meet western requirements.</p>
      <p>On the market this year, Vekshin said that there was not an unexpected spike in westbound demand after factories in China started to re-open following an extended New Year break.</p>
      <p>However, things have been picking up over recent weeks.</p>
      <p>In the opposite direction, however, there had been an early increase in demand to meet requirements for medical products in China.</p>
      <p>“We are now seeing more and more cargo coming in both directions,” he said. “And we are anticipating additional demand in relation to outbound cargo. We are also anticipating what is going to happen in Europe over the coming weeks.</p>
      <p>“We are ready and will unleash our entire fleet to help our customers and continue to support the bridges that we have been building over the last 30 years.”</p>
      <p>He added that while demand has not reached the level of the US west coast container port strikes of a few years ago, enquiries continue to roll in and forwarders are being pro-active.</p>
      <p>“Customers are contacting us and we are explaining what sort of availability we have, our reaction times, the specifics of the type of cargo we are going to move, whether that is related to coronavirus directly – like bare essentials or even fully-assembled mobile hospitals – or spare parts, assembly parts or components.”</p>
      <p>While the group is ramping up the availability of aircraft for charter and reducing scheduled operations, Vekshin said this reflects customer requirements.</p>
      <p>He explained that over the past year, the market has become more ad hoc in nature and demand harder to predict.</p>
      <p>“The demands are very specific right now, reaction times need to be different, flexibility should be different.</p>
      <p>“The decision to switch gears in the direction of dedicated charters, ad hoc flights, has been dictated by the market.</p>
      <p>“Given our expertise, we have been doing well managing all those short-term, short-notice requirements.”</p>
      <p>He added that AirBridgeCargo is still offering scheduled services and when the market needs a more predictable capacity provision, it will ramp this operation back up when the market is ready.</p>
      <p>On recent reports that the group has been re-negotiating with suppliers, he said this is perfectly normal.</p>
      <p>“It makes sense to touch base [with suppliers] every now and then to see where you are and what you can expect from each other under the circumstances.</p>
      <p>“We have all become part – almost overnight – of this force majeure driven world, it does make sense to stay on the same page and it is always advisable to see what our options may be.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>55ed7a</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargonews.net/airlines/bellyhold-airline/virgin-atlantic-takes-drastic-action-to-safeguard-business/</url>
    <title>Virgin Atlantic takes drastic action to safeguard business</title>
    <author>Damian Brett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-16T14:33:37+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>airlines</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Virgin Atlantic</topic>
      <topic>Virgin Atlantic Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Virgin Atlantic has implemented a “drastic” cost cutting exercise as it takes measures to offset a slump in demand as a result of the coronavirus outbreak.</p>
      <p>The airline noted a sharp and continual drop in demand for flights across its network, meaning “immediate and decisive action is needed”.</p>
      <p>“Today, Virgin Atlantic will put drastic measures in place to ensure cash is preserved, costs are controlled, and the future of the airline is safeguarded,” it said.</p>
      <p>“The situation is deteriorating at pace and the airline has seen several days of negative bookings, driven by a huge volume of cancellations as customers choose to stay at home.</p>
      <p>“Significantly, the European Commission has announced a suspension of the ‘use it or lose it’ slot rules until 30 June 2020, enabling the airline to consolidate schedules and ground aircraft immediately.”</p>
      <p>The following actions will be taken from tomorrow: </p>
      <p>Then the following further action will be taken:</p>
      <p>The carrier had previously implemented other measures including a recruitment, travel and pay freeze.</p>
      <p>The airline has also appealed to the UK government for support: “Our industry needs emergency credit facilities to a value of £5-7.5bn, to bolster confidence and to prevent credit card processors from withholding customer payments.</p>
      <p>“We also need slot alleviation for the full summer 2020 season, so we can match supply to demand – reducing costs and preventing unviable flying and corresponding CO2 emissions.</p>
      <p>“With this support, airlines including Virgin Atlantic, can weather this storm and emerge in a position to assist the nation’s economic recovery and provide the passenger and cargo connectivity that business and people across the country rely on.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
</corpus>
