<corpus>
  <document>
    <document_id>1e2287</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/air-freight-sector-pushes-hard-to-help-and-for-help-to-fight-the-virus/</url>
    <title>Air freight sector pushes hard to help – and for help – to fight the virus</title>
    <author>Alex Lennane</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:30:44+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>IAG Cargo</topic>
      <topic>IATA</topic>
      <topic>Lufthansa Cargo</topic>
      <topic>TIACA</topic>
      <topic>Turkish Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>As Tiaca and Iata continue to lobby governments to relax restrictions on cargo movements, airlines are looking for ways to keep shipments flying.</p>
      <p>IAG Cargo sent a note to customers yesterday, offering its passenger aircraft for charters.</p>
      <p>“To support your freight and to help get it where it needs to be, we are now opening up the opportunity for freight forwarders to charter our aircraft where needed,” wrote chief commercial officer John Cheetham.</p>
      <p>Lufthansa Cargo also looked to try to reassure customers.</p>
      <p>“We are doing everything in our power to keep our freighter services stable. On the other side, the extensive changes within our network of passenger flights have a direct impact on the available belly capacities. In order to compensate for these shortfalls, changes in the scheduling of our cargo aircraft are also likely in the coming days.”</p>
      <p>It told customers developments were “too dynamic” and urged them to visit its website or Twitter feed to learn of daily flight changes.</p>
      <p>“We will also inform you about currently bookable connections via our API interface and our network page,” it added. “We regret the necessary adjustments to the flight schedule and the inconvenience caused – and thank you for your commitment and cooperation in these challenging times.”</p>
      <p>Turkish Cargo said it was increasing its freighter frequencies to “full capacity”, while also using passenger aircraft for cargo demand.</p>
      <p>“Turkish Cargo will start to serve for cargo transport purposes by making use of the aircraft available in its fleet, in addition to its current cargo freighter capacity, which was increased to 25 from 13 during the last four years.”</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, Tiaca this morning joined Iata in lobbying governments for support.</p>
      <p>“The air cargo industry has a decisive role to play in the fight against Covid-19 and the industry’s voice must be fully heard by regulators and governments,” it said</p>
      <p>“This is why Tiaca has joined the ICAO technical group on joint actions related to Covid-19, other members of which are the WHO, Iata, ACI and GEA.”</p>
      <p>It said its goal was to draw attention to the critical role of air cargo, but also to the financial challenges facing the industry. It cited lease payments on aircraft, salaries, energy supplies and other payments, as well as difficulties stemming from travel bans, crew movement restrictions, airport slots and route changes.</p>
      <p>“We support Iata’s appeal to have air cargo recognised as vital in the fight against Covid-19, and for action to be taken – in particular, removing all travel restrictions on air cargo operations and taking all necessary measures to allow air cargo to continue to circulate around the world,” said Steven Polmans, Tiaca chairman.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>236fd3</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/factories-switch-production-to-boost-medical-supplies-to-fight-covid-19/</url>
    <title>Factories switch production to boost medical supplies to fight Covid-19</title>
    <author>Alex Lennane</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:29:00+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Flexport</topic>
      <topic>Humanitarian logistics</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Growing numbers of companies are changing tack, shelving production of normal wares to make hand sanitiser and other medical products.</p>
      <p>Some forwarders, meanwhile, are offering to ship them.</p>
      <p>French luxury group LMVH has switched its luxury perfumes for sanitiser, while small gin distilleries across the UK and Ireland and France’s Pernod Ricard have also stepped in as alcohol supplies in Europe dwindle.</p>
      <p>Flow Water Technologies has offered to supply the Cyprus government with disinfectant free of charge, after it ramped up production of disinfectant compound sodium hypochlorite. It is now capable of making five cubic metres of high-concentrate a day, the equivalent of 60 cubic metres of sanitiser.</p>
      <p>“We have taken the joint decision to put aside our immediate commercial objectives and help assist with the national fight against Covid-19 infection escalation,” said chief executive Mark Hadfield.</p>
      <p>“Cyprus imports chemicals, but it will soon run out. As Flow Water Technologies BWMS solution holds a Cyprus biocide licence for the emergency services, the moral obligation was clear.”</p>
      <p>But it’s not just manufacturers looking to help the fight against coronavirus.</p>
      <p>Flexport.org is to export thousands of coronavirus test kits from Asian suppliers to the US west coast, but added that it had “limited resources to pay for all of these and other urgently needed supplies for the healthcare system”, and called for donations.</p>
      <p>It said: “It’s time to punch back, join humanity’s counterattack by making a tax-deductible donation. 100% of your money will go toward buying and shipping critical products for the world’s healthcare systems in this time of need.”</p>
      <p>Another forwarder, on LinkedIn, commented: “I proudly work for a rival company, but I absolutely applaud these efforts as we all need to work together, especially in the logistics/supply chain community.”</p>
      <p>You can help: click here.</p>
      <p>If you know of any businesses providing humanitarian or charitable services, please let us know and we will help promote it.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>287830</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/working-from-home-can-be-tricky-for-freight-firms-with-onsite-only-tech/</url>
    <title>'Working from home' can be tricky for freight firms with 'onsite-only' tech</title>
    <author>Sam Whelan</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:28:13+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Cogoport</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Digital freight forwarder</topic>
      <topic>Flexport</topic>
      <topic>freight forwarders</topic>
      <topic>FreightBro</topic>
      <topic>Kontainers</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Forwarders and carriers are being stretched to the limit by lockdowns and quarantines sweeping the globe, forcing large-scale remote working and reduced resources.</p>
      <p>And Flemming Frost, president of digital freight marketplace Cogoport, believes remote working will “hurt more” than many realise – “Even among the big players,” he told The Loadstar.</p>
      <p>“I spoke with a top 10 carrier and it is down on resources across many locations, as such staff are flat-out to just keep the daily business together.”</p>
      <p>While investment into freight-tech and digitalisation has been a hot industry topic in recent years, many logistics firms are likely ill-prepared to operate efficiently under “work from home” conditions.</p>
      <p>“The lack of tech and automation means many processes are ‘band-aided’ by ‘human APIs’, and when the humans are either away from work or ill-equipped to work from alternative locations, that will hurt,” explained Mr Frost.</p>
      <p>“A check with a small forwarder gave me the same impression – half the staff are at the office and the rest can only work at half-capacity due to an inability to access all the required material and systems from outside the office.”</p>
      <p>According to Mark Yong, MD for Asia Pacific at multimodal digital supply chain platform Blume Global, many freight companies still rely on legacy systems which can only be operated onsite, due to network security.</p>
      <p>“Medium-size companies are probably suffering the most, as they don’t have adequate tools,” he noted.</p>
      <p>Seko Logistics announced remote working at its global headquarters in Chicago this week. Group commercial director Keith Gaskin said the industry needed to embrace digital transformation at a quicker pace.</p>
      <p>“That includes the archaic bill of lading process,” he said, “especially in times like this when a piece of paper is often still needed to exchange hands [which] is crazy.</p>
      <p>“There are obviously alternatives, but from some regions, L/Cs still stipulate multiple copies of the bills need to be presented. Hard to do if an office is in lockdown or the post office/courier services are unable to work.”</p>
      <p>Flexport, meanwhile, is looking to collaborate, according to CEO Ryan Petersen, who explained: “If you work at a customs brokerage or freight forwarder that can’t maintain operations because of your IT set up, please reach out.</p>
      <p>“This is a crucial time for us to all help each other to keep supply chains moving, especially as there may be life-saving goods in some of these shipments.”</p>
      <p>However, one customs broker said: “We are fully equipped to work remotely with zero service interruptions. Most brokers are.”</p>
      <p>Perhaps sensing a need for greater digital capabilities among forwarders, freight-tech companies Kontainers and FreightBro both announced this week that new users could temporarily access their respective products free of charge.</p>
      <p>Similarly, Australian firm A2B Solution Group, a service partner of the Cargowise One platform, said it had developed an “essential workflow package that will allow your staff to work from home within 24 hours of engagement”.</p>
      <p>“Best of all,” A2B added, “the implementation package comes with a company specific guide and a free roll of toilet paper.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>da44b0</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/global-retailers-cancelling-orders-threatens-bangladesh-garment-industry/</url>
    <title>Global retailers cancelling orders threatens Bangladesh garment industry</title>
    <author>Bangladesh correspondent</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:27:27+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Bangladesh</topic>
      <topic>Chittagong</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>garments</topic>
      <topic>Talking shop: the retail business</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Major retailers are cancelling or postponing orders, putting Bangladesh’s garment industry, the country’s top foreign currency earner and employer, in jeopardy.</p>
      <p>The value of order cancellations up to yesterday reached $124m – but the industry expects more to follow.</p>
      <p>The top buyers so far forced to cancel or withhold orders include C&amp;A, Zara, Pull and Bear, Baby Shop, Blackberrys, Inditex and Primark.</p>
      <p>Apparel manufacturers say that just after Covid-19 hit China, they faced a shortage of raw materials, which disrupted their production.</p>
      <p>Prices of locally available raw materials went up significantly, but the problem had eased to some extent as shipments from China began to resume.</p>
      <p>But now, as the virus spreads all over the world, the US and EU main markets for Bangladeshi apparel are severely affected, and the demand for ready-made garments has dropped, following the lockdown of many areas and clothing stores closing.</p>
      <p>“Every day we are hearing messages from buyers, either for cancellations or withheld [orders],” former president of Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) Siddiqur Rahman told The Loadstar.</p>
      <p>“My three factories faced order cancellations for 1.5 million garment items,” said Mr Rahman, who is also chairman of Bando Design, whose factory supplies clothes for H&amp;M, belk, Matalan, C&amp;A, Walmart, Indian Terrain, Westside, Mango and Zara.</p>
      <p>The company will have a staff meeting today to assess the immediate impact of Coronavirus on the business, he said. “It’s an uncertain situation. No one knows how far it will go.”</p>
      <p>Chairman of Evince Group Anwar-ul Alam Chowdhury said manufacturers were receiving cancellations every hour or more. His factory supplies retailers such as Celio, Tesco, Sears, Carrefour, Debenhams, Lee, DeFacto, Wrangler, kmart, F&amp;F and Bexleys.</p>
      <p>“One retailer asked to halt production in factories up to June. It wanted a 30% discount on ready goods and said it will renegotiate a price for suspended orders,” he said.</p>
      <p>“A factory owner told me yesterday he sent 10 million pieces garments to Chittagong port, but the buyer is now asking him to take them back to the factory,” he added.</p>
      <p>Mr Chowdhury, also a former president of BGMEA, said one of the largest buyers, Inditex, had asked another factory owner to postpone cutting cloth for another 10 million pieces.</p>
      <p>“One of my customers in France said its offices were closed, do not ship the goods, we will let you know. And the order sheets for delivering goods in May and June are yet to come,” he said.</p>
      <p>Many retailers had closed their stores worldwide for weeks and months, he added. “What will they do with goods after taking delivery?”</p>
      <p>He said his government needed to come up with a financial package for the garment makers to save the sector.</p>
      <p>“A crisis fund can be formed to support the industry.”</p>
      <p>Imports and exports of goods through Chittagong port have plummeted since coronavirus hit the globe. In February, imports fell by 17% compared with January. Export earnings also saw a massive nosedive, and the trend may continue through the year.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>0272e6</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/hmm-takes-100000-teu-of-capacity-from-the-2m-to-its-new-alliance/</url>
    <title>HMM takes 100,000 teu of capacity from the 2M to its new alliance</title>
    <author>Mike Wackett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:26:28+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>2M</topic>
      <topic>Alphaliner</topic>
      <topic>Hapag-Lloyd</topic>
      <topic>HMM</topic>
      <topic>Maersk</topic>
      <topic>MSC</topic>
      <topic>THE Alliance</topic>
      <topic>Yang Ming</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>HMM is to receive nine ships back that Maersk and MSC sub-chartered March 2017 as part of the carrier’s slot charter agreement with the 2M.</p>
      <p>The redelivered tonnage includes three 13,092 teu Danaos-owned vessels on long-term charter from the Greek shipowner.</p>
      <p>According to one London broker source, Maersk and MSC took over the charters of the three ships at a discount on the charter party daily hire rate, with HMM paying the difference to owners.</p>
      <p>The source told The Loadstar that, having already exceptionally agreed to discount the daily hire rate to HMM during the carrier’s cost-cutting measures designed to ensure its survival, Danaos “held firm” on the revised rate.</p>
      <p>At the time, HMM was not in a strong negotiating position, needing to become part of an alliance to receive several tranches of desperately needed funding from state-owned banks, but it was denied full membership of the 2M and only able to secure a slot charter deal.</p>
      <p>As a consequence, HMM was unable to deploy its own ships on the Asia to Europe tradelane, and the 2M partners “took them off their hands”, according to the broker.</p>
      <p>However, subsequently HMM has been accepted as a full member of rival THE Alliance, alongside Hapag-Lloyd, ONE and Yang Ming, and will officially join the VSA on 1 April.</p>
      <p>The Danaos ships, along with five 10,081 teu vessels also sub-chartered to Maersk and MSC, will be deployed on THEA’s new east-west network, stemmed to start on 1 April.</p>
      <p>Notwithstanding HMM recording five consecutive years of losses, including $511m last year and $708m in 2018, the carrier is taking delivery of 12 24,000 teu ULCVs between April and September. They will be phased into THEA’s FE4 loop, replacing Hapag-Lloyd’s 11 15,000 teu ships.</p>
      <p>According to Alphaliner, the redelivered vessels and the newbuild ULCVs will add 388,000 teu to HMM’s fleet, taking the carrier’s total capacity to some 790,000 teu. It will leapfrogging its THEA partner, Yang Ming (with around 607,000 teu of capacity), to take eighth place in the carrier league table.</p>
      <p>When the newbuilds have all been delivered, HMM will be some way to achieving president and CEO Jae-hoon Bae’s rehabilitation target for the carrier: reaching one million teu capacity.</p>
      <p>The consultant said the redelivery of the ships to HMM “would not have a significant impact” on the overall fleet deployment of Maersk and MSC, with the outgoing tonnage mainly being replaced by ships returning from scrubber installation.</p>
      <p>Moreover, with so many blanked sailings since Chinese new year due to the coronavirus outbreak, and the fear of a significant global demand slump as the virus causes lockdowns around the world, the 2M partners could be looking to downsize their network offering for the duration of the crisis.</p>
      <p>Indeed, a similar message could follow from THEA partners, obliging HMM to pause delivery of its new scrubber-fitted flagships.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>30a4b4</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/sea-air-services-disrupted-and-rates-soar-as-airlines-suspend-more-flights/</url>
    <title>Sea-air services disrupted and rates soar as airlines suspend more flights</title>
    <author>Alex Lennane</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T14:42:14+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Aeromar</topic>
      <topic>Arise surcharges</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Dubai</topic>
      <topic>SAT Albatros</topic>
      <topic>Sea-air</topic>
      <topic>Singapore</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Sea-air shipments via Dubai and Singapore to Europe and the US have either been suspended or seen prices soar.</p>
      <p>Aeromar, which specialises in sea freight to Dubai and onward travel by air, said it had suspended its services with immediate effect, although all cargo currently on route would continue.</p>
      <p>It said it had been forced to make this decision as airlines began cancelling flights from Dubai.</p>
      <p>“We can fix rates three weeks in advance, but if during the sea voyage, flights get cancelled, it’s pretty difficult to go back and ask a customer for more money to use one of the few carriers left,” said MD Nick Coverdale.</p>
      <p>“And with air cargo rates still not that expensive from Hong Kong and South-east Asia, for example, the sea-air service doesn’t look that attractive, especially with the uncertainties. The only option is to put the goods back on ship going to Europe, but that’s not realistic.</p>
      <p>“Shippers deserve better.”</p>
      <p>He said the company would review the situation over the weekend.</p>
      <p>SAT Albatros, another Dubai-based sea-air outfit, has suspended all rate agreements and added a $1 per kg surcharge on all live shipments.</p>
      <p>It has also suspended sea-air traffic via Singapore and Dubai into the US and its service from Singapore to Europe, the US and South Africa. Only its Dubai-Europe service is available.</p>
      <p>The company told customers: “We are monitoring the situation carefully and will keep you updated. All cargo that is on the way to transit hubs on all routes for uplifting, we will individually advise revised costing and routing amendment.</p>
      <p>“In Dubai, the situation has also changed overnight. Many flights have been taken out and rate levels are moving upwards heavily. All airfreight agreements have been cancelled with immediate effect.</p>
      <p>“It will also affect the shipments we have on hand; shipments that are on the sea or even arrived in Dubai.”</p>
      <p>“In order to ensure live shipments are uplifted, we’ve implemented a short-term emergency surcharge of $1 per kg effective immediately. All existing rate agreements are temporarily suspended. Applicable rates are now to be confirmed on booking.”</p>
      <p>However, one UK-based forwarder said it was still operating sea-air services via Dubai, and that “rates are still a fraction of air freight from Far East/China currently”.</p>
      <p>He added that Singapore still had passenger carriers operating and that rates there “had not fluctuated much”, although reduced flights by the major Chinese carriers would add some pressure.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>dcfb4e</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/queensland-covid-19-vessel-ban-is-reckless-and-indefensible-says-shipping-group/</url>
    <title>Queensland Covid-19 vessel ban is 'reckless and indefensible', says shipping group</title>
    <author>Gavin van Marle</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T14:41:24+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Asia-Australia</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Shipping Australia</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Australian shipping lobby group Shipping Australia has slammed today’s decision by the state of Queensland to introduce restrictions on ships calling at its ports, particularly the container hub of Brisbane.</p>
      <p>Maritime Safety Queensland (MSQ) today banned all commercial ships from entering ports in the state if the ship, or anyone on board, has been in any country outside Australia within the past 14 days.</p>
      <p>Contravention of the MSQ ruling is a criminal offence, for which the maximum penalty is A$66,725 ($40,000) for an individual and A$333,625 for a corporation.</p>
      <p>Shipping Australia said it understood other maritime authorities in the country were considering similar restrictions, and claimed they could put society as a whole at risk.</p>
      <p>“Australian port authorities are now exacerbating an already bad coronavirus situation by restricting the ability of cargo ships to deliver desperately needed goods.</p>
      <p>“This is putting Australian families at risk by potentially causing supply chain shortages of medicines and everyday consumer needs,” it added.</p>
      <p>Shipping Australia’s chief executive, Rod Nairn, said: “The MSQ policy is reckless and indefensible; cargo ship crews are probably the lowest-risk sector in the world, with not one cargo ship crew member yet being confirmed as having Covid-19.”</p>
      <p>The organisation noted that most Asia-Australia shipping services “are only six to eight days’ duration and ships would have to potentially wait around for up to 14 days to enter.</p>
      <p>“And that’s at a cost of A$25,000 a day. When a port entry costs about A$250,000 a time, shipping lines are indicating that these directions from port authorities to stay away are simply unsustainable”, it said.</p>
      <p>It further claimed that some carriers could be forced to omit port calls, which would “lead to massive relocation of cargo away from where it is supposed to be and it will have to be trucked across the continent.</p>
      <p>“Trucking costs could escalate. Australia is a big place – it will take days upon days to get to where it is needed. Costs to everyday Australians could rocket.”</p>
      <p>And it also claimed that the restrictions would also hit container supply chains serving New Zealand and the Pacific Islands, for which Australian ports commonly act as hubs.</p>
      <p>“Blocking shipping’s ability to deliver desperately needed freight to the islands is not an optimal outlook.</p>
      <p>“Meanwhile, New Zealand and Australia both have 14-day exclusion periods. So, as of now, the Aus-New Zealand trade is being killed off,” it said.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>c7c76f</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/artificial-intelligence-comes-to-the-rescue-as-air-route-options-narrow/</url>
    <title>Artificial intelligence comes to the rescue as air route options narrow</title>
    <author>Ian Putzger in Toronto</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T14:40:39+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Airspace Technologies</topic>
      <topic>Artificial Intelligence</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Start-up stars</topic>
      <topic>Transatlantic</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>As more and more airlines slash their operations to the bone, forwarders are increasingly struggling to find lift.</p>
      <p>San Diego-based start-up Airspace Technologies has witnessed a sharp reduction in routing options, but there are still ways to get clients’ traffic to its destination, claims chief revenue officer Steve Ritchie.</p>
      <p>The firm is leveraging artificial intelligence to find and select routings for time-sensitive shipments through a platform that provides automated quotes, routing and real-time tracking.</p>
      <p>The system can use a variety of paradigms, from transit times and rates to elements like a carrier’s efficiency, equipment or experience, while on the ground, shipments are moved by a network of contractors that take urgent shipments to an airport or deliver to the consignee.</p>
      <p>The concept is targeting shippers with time-sensitive traffic – especially the healthcare/life sciences, aerospace and hi-tech sectors.</p>
      <p>Healthcare is the company’s largest arena, followed by aerospace. Demand for urgent parts for aircraft has diminished as a result of the sharp reduction in flying activity, whereas medical traffic has been boosted by demand for moving Covid-19 test kits, Mr Ritchie said.</p>
      <p>Using AI means Airspace Technologies can find the fastest and/or cheapest routing quicker than traditional forwarders, claimed Ben Kozy, senior vice-president operations.</p>
      <p>Mr Ritchie added: “With the constant changes in schedules we’re seeing now, we can re-route shipments in real time. If a flight is cancelled while the driver is on the way to the airport, the computer can find a new route before he gets there.”</p>
      <p>The drastic schedule reductions of recent days have cut down the choices, but they have not stopped any traffic, according to Mr Ritchie.</p>
      <p>“We’re seeing an impact [from schedule reductions], but stock has to move. As long as that demand is there, we will figure out a way to get it to its destination,” he said. “If the only option is to take it on the road, the driver will drive from Washington to Boston.”</p>
      <p>It helps that the types of cargo that Airspace Technologies targets are premium shipments with urgent timelines. This allows the company to revert to OBC or charter options if necessary.</p>
      <p>“We have lined up a lot of charter operations with a standard three-hour window, at some airports two hours, Mr Ritchie said.</p>
      <p>Feeding charter availability and rates into the system requires a bit more work than automatic schedule updates, but the system can shift traffic seamlessly to charter, Mr Kozy said.</p>
      <p>As rates are expected to skyrocket in the coming days, many shippers are facing the prospect of prohibitive pricing for their cargo. So far, this has not been a problem for Airspace Technologies, claimed Mr Ritchie.</p>
      <p>“Right now we’re not seeing prices go to the point of unsustainability.”</p>
      <p>The disappearance of vast numbers of flights, coupled with the travel ban on European visitors by the US administration, has prompted forwarders to explore alternative transatlantic routings, like moving cargo via Canada or Mexico. Airspace Technologies has not had such routings so far. Nor have transit times lengthened significantly, Mr Kozy said.</p>
      <p>The company started out with its focus on the domestic market and, since the beginning of last year, its US network has grown from about 25 locations to 60 – essentially the top 60 population centres.</p>
      <p>International expansion, which is chiefly driven by customer demand, picked up in the past six months and now covers about a dozen countries for US inbound shipments and half a dozen outbound markets – mostly Canada and in Europe, where potential partners have “shown lively interest” in Airspace Technologies’ platform.</p>
      <p>The company also has some funds for expansion. In November, it secured $20m in funding, following an infusion of $8m announced earlier in the year.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>c049e5</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/a-growing-fleet-of-pax-aircraft-flying-without-passengers-but-carrying-cargo/</url>
    <title>A growing fleet of PAX aircraft flying without passengers – but carrying cargo</title>
    <author>Ian Putzger in Toronto &amp; Gavin van Marle</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T14:39:54+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>American Airlines</topic>
      <topic>Calculating Capacity</topic>
      <topic>Cathay Pacfic</topic>
      <topic>Ceva Logistics</topic>
      <topic>Dachser</topic>
      <topic>Delta Air Lines</topic>
      <topic>Korean Air</topic>
      <topic>SEKO Logistics</topic>
      <topic>Singapore Airlines</topic>
      <topic>The curse of empty bellies</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>The European Union’s decision to relax slot rules has stopped ‘ghost flights’ – those operating with nothing on board except flight crews for the sole purpose of retaining slots.</p>
      <p>The industry can now expect to see a growing fleet of passenger aircraft flying without passengers – but with cargo in their bellyholds.</p>
      <p>Delta is the latest carrier to join a lengthening list that have decided to deploy idle aircraft to move cargo, announcing this week it was responding to corporate customers by launching cargo charter operations around the globe.</p>
      <p>The service is available out of 13 US gateways, connecting to over 70 international destinations, “meeting client needs from packages to pallets”.</p>
      <p>Delta Cargo vice president Shawn Cole said: “Offering new supply chain solutions through Delta Cargo to our customers is one opportunity for us to provide the support othey tell us they need during this unprecedented business environment.”</p>
      <p>Delta did not specify how many aircraft it is fielding for the charters, but a company spokesperson reported that the mix covered the airline’s B717s to 777s. She added that widebodies for international routes were proving most popular.</p>
      <p>“We are seeing strong interest, especially in our B777-200/300 variants and our A350-900 aircraft. The A350-900 is a state-of-the-art carbon fibre-bodied aircraft and, owing to its light weight and huge cargo belly, is able to uplift more than 50 tons,” she added.</p>
      <p>Delta is cutting its overall seat capacity by 40% and grounding 300 aircraft, with more to follow if the US government implements a domestic flight ban.</p>
      <p>Its rival, American, is idling 135 widebody aircraft, having slashed international flights between 16 March and 6 May by 75%. Most of the routes cut are to Asia, but services to Latin America, Europe, Australia and New Zealand has also been slashed.</p>
      <p>According to IATA, airlines have cancelled over 185,000 flights since the end of January and are facing a brutal impact on their bottom lines. The association has warned that industry revenue could take a hit of up to US$113bn. The US airline industry has asked Washington for more than $50bn in federal aid to get through the crisis.</p>
      <p>In this situation, the use of passenger aircraft to move cargo offers some financial alleviation, paired with meeting demand for cargo lift in a crisis. Korean Air added that it saved some money on parking fees as well as helping importers and exporters.</p>
      <p>The carrier announced this week it intended to launch cargo flights with passenger aircraft to Qingdao on 21 March and intends to add more destinations in the near future.</p>
      <p>KAL joins two other Asian carriers using passenger planes for cargo charters. Last week, Singapore Airlines offshoot Scoot, which has suspended passenger flights to China until 25 April, announced plans to field B787-9 planes for flights to Guangzhou and Nanjing. And Cathay Pacific has reportedly deployed A330 planes for cargo missions to China and is considering a similar approach to Japan.</p>
      <p>At least one European carrier is also signalling interest in belly cargo charters. IAG, which is set to ground about 75% percent of its seat capacity, has noted “strong demand for cargo” and indicated it “may operate some passenger aircraft just for bellyhold cargo to ensure we keep critical supplies moving”.</p>
      <p>Carsten Spohn, chief executive of Lufthansa, told a German newspaper the airline would “do everything to maintain the supply chains” for providing the German population by air, adding: “We are working full steam on an air bridge for the whole of Germany.”</p>
      <p>The abrupt disappearance of vast chunks of belly capacity as passenger services were axed has left forwarders scrambling for capacity and prompted a flurry of charter arrangements. Ceva disclosed on Monday it had signed contracts for 86 cargo charters “to keep supply chains running and prevent production lines from closing down”.</p>
      <p>Other forwarders that have recently stepped up their arrangements for dedicated freighter lift include Senator and Dachser.</p>
      <p>Brain Bourke, chief growth officer at Seko Logistics, told The Loadstar: “The situation has really stepped up the need for forwarders to find new ways to cooperate – I wouldn’t even call it coopetition, I think it’s gone beyond that.</p>
      <p>“There aren’t enough aircraft to go around and the lines of communication need huge improvement, because the charter companies aren’t able to do it.</p>
      <p>“There may well be three forwarders round me right now who have enough to fill a 747, but who is going to coordinate it? A much greater level of collaboration is almost a requisite now.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>99360d</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/fedex-fights-back-in-q3-but-every-24-hours-something-new-happens/</url>
    <title>FedEx fights back in Q3 – but now 'every 24 hours, something new happens'</title>
    <author>Alex Lennane</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T14:38:47+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>FedEx</topic>
      <topic>financial results</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>FedEx announced better-than-expected third-quarter results yesterday, reporting $17.5bn in adjusted revenue, but after net income plummeted, has suspended its financial forecasts.</p>
      <p>It said operating results declined – by more than half – owing to “weaker global economic conditions, including the impact of coronavirus, higher self-insurance accruals, an “unfavourable variable incentive compensation comparison”, increased FedEx Ground costs from expanded service offerings, the loss of business from a large customer, a continuing mix shift to lower-yielding services and a more competitive pricing environment.</p>
      <p>“These factors were partially offset by the benefits from volume growth at FedEx Ground, an additional operating weekday, increased yields at FedEx Freight and the shifting of Cyber Week into December,” it added.</p>
      <p>Adjusted net income fell 53%.</p>
      <p>FedEx did not put a precise number on how much the coronavirus may have cost, but said it expected to see dampened demand in Europe as shops close and factories start to slow production, and it was replicating the strategy it used in China last month.</p>
      <p>However, demand in China is now strengthening, said Brie Carere, chief marketing and communications officer, with production back at about 65%-75%.</p>
      <p>“In February, we managed the influx of shipment requests to China amid limited capacity by implementing a temporary peak surcharge for US outbound freight shipments and adjusting our transit commitments to China to maximise our capacity utilisation.</p>
      <p>“We have also dynamically adjusted spot prices to and from China.” She added that the market had rebounded this month.</p>
      <p>“With the urgent need for stock replenishment and with air capacity shortage in the market, we believe demand will stay elevated. We continue to adjust transit times and spot prices specifically for China outbound to manage demand profitably.</p>
      <p>“We are now employing the same strategies in other parts of the world that have helped us manage demand and capacity constraints in China, including transit time extensions, dynamic spot price management, and will also leverage peak surcharges for specific lanes and periods of time, as they are required.</p>
      <p>“For our intra-European business, we continue to run our air and ground networks. Due to the lockdown of some areas and enhanced border controls, we are dynamically adjusting our network and, in some lines, we’ve extended transit times.”</p>
      <p>FedEx said that with the pace of change in the market, business was very uncertain.</p>
      <p>“We are really managing this business almost on a day-to-day basis,” said outgoing chief financial officer Alan Graf. “We certainly think we know what’s going to happen in the next week. But I have to tell you, every 24 hours something new happens.</p>
      <p>“Europe had been doing well. Now it seems that Europe and UK are starting to shut down a little bit more and the demand is probably going to be less than I would have told you it was three days ago.</p>
      <p>“I do know that we have great plans in shape from the cost side to go either way, and that’s the best we can tell you right now because it is just so uncertain out there.”</p>
      <p>The company has “frozen and reduced its overheads”, and said technology and efficiencies would also take out costs.</p>
      <p>Mr Graf added that FedEx was also cutting costs by “managing capacity, retiring our oldest and least-efficient aircraft, integrating TNT Express and lowering our residential delivery costs by having FedEx Ground deliver FedEx SmartPost and certain day-definite FedEx Express packages”.</p>
      <p>You can see the earnings call transcript here, and the full results here.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>2ad175</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/carriers-pull-back-on-installing-scrubbers-as-price-of-low-sulphur-fuel-drops/</url>
    <title>Carriers pull back on installing scrubbers as price of low-sulphur fuel drops</title>
    <author>Mike Wackett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T14:37:51+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Idle tonnage</topic>
      <topic>IMO low-sulphur regulations</topic>
      <topic>MSC</topic>
      <topic>Scrubbers</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Ocean carriers are cancelling scrubber retrofits for their ships due to the huge delays at Chinese shipyards and a slump in oil prices, which has raised questions about the economics of the technology.</p>
      <p>According to Alphaliner, the number of containerships currently out of service for the installation of exhaust gas cleaning systems remains at a record high of 117, for 1.1m teu.</p>
      <p>“On top of this, several vessels are stranded at anchor waiting to enter retrofit yards. A number of ships have since abandoned their yard slots to seek alternative deployment opportunities, as owners try to mitigate losses from the extended vessel downtime and off-hire days,” said the consultant.</p>
      <p>It said MSC, which had planned to retrofit around half of its 574 ships with scrubbers, had been “particularly hit by the delays with more than 20 of the carrier’s ships staying at various shipyards for more than 100 days”.</p>
      <p>On a rough calculation – assuming that the 20 idled vessels would cost the carrier say $50,000 a day to replace on the charter market – the indirect cost to MSC could be in the region of a staggering $100m.</p>
      <p>However, several of MSC’s vessels have suffered extended stays of considerably more than 100 days, including its 19,437 teu MSC Erica, which was idled for 175 days.</p>
      <p>According to Alphaliner, MSC still has some 40 ships with ongoing retrofits, having installed scrubbers on around 90 vessels so far. The final number of MSC’s vessels equipped with scrubbers will almost certainly fall well short of its previous plan to fit the technology on around 280.</p>
      <p>The Loadstar understands the carrier has cancelled several scrubber contracts with Chinese yards on the basis of the excessively extended times, compared with the original quotes of six-to-eight weeks.</p>
      <p>This may go some way to explain how the carrier’s 9,784 teu MSC Joanna recently violated IMO’s carriage ban on carrying non-compliant fuel when entering UAE ports. MSC told The Loadstar yesterday 700 tons of heavy fuel oil had remained on the ship in a sealed tank for scrubber testing.</p>
      <p>It said that it was “closely investigating” the incident, adding that the installation of a scrubber system on the ship had been “delayed several months this year”.</p>
      <p>MSC did not confirm whether a scrubber would eventually be fitted to the ship, but it seems unlikely, given the new oil economics.</p>
      <p>With the price premium between the cost of traditional heavy fuel and compliant low-sulphur fuel narrowing to just $60 per ton, carriers and owners are rowing back on plans to install scrubbers on their ships.</p>
      <p>“This low spread greatly reduces the benefits owners of scrubber-fitted ships enjoy, with payback periods stretching to four or five years, against earlier projections of less than one year, based on a spread of over $200 per ton,” said Alphaliner.</p>
      <p>Indeed, one well-informed source told The Loadstar several carriers had apparently tried to sue Chinese yards for compensation, but the yards had been able to claim force majeure because of the coronavirus outbreak.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>410714</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/ec-calls-on-member-states-to-create-priority-freight-traffic-lanes-for-essential-supplies/</url>
    <title>EC calls on member states to create priority freight traffic lanes for essential supplies</title>
    <author>Gavin van Marle</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T14:27:40+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Land</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Bankruptcy Blues</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>European road freight market</topic>
      <topic>IRU</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>The global road freight industry could be looking at an accumulated loss nearing $1trn as a result of the coronavirus outbreak, the International Road Transport Union (IRU) has warned.</p>
      <p>“On the basis of the significant fall in intercontinental container shipments, IRU estimates a decline in global road transport activity of up to 20% in 2020, depending on how long the situation continues.</p>
      <p>“This could lead to a global loss in operator revenues of $800bn,” it said in a statement, revising an earlier figure that estimated losses could top $1trn.</p>
      <p>The organisation added that the situation had become confused, due to “rules and restrictions changing rapidly and often in a haphazard or uncoordinated way”.</p>
      <p>That has become particularly true in Europe, where countries have begun to close land borders, with cross-border movements of road freight at risk.</p>
      <p>The fear of both trucking companies and many of their customers is that, with thin margins and low capital reserves, many road transport operators could go to the wall in a comparatively short space of time.</p>
      <p>“Nearly 6% of all people in employment worldwide work in road transport – largely in small and medium-sized firms that, due to their size, cannot easily cope with external shocks such as the economic impacts of Covid-19.</p>
      <p>“The economic burden is high, and growing, on both workers and the owners of firms. They are doing their best to stay afloat, however functioning supply chains and the mobility of essential workers depend on them remaining in business,” the IRU explained.</p>
      <p>According to the EU Observer, as of yesterday, nine EU countries had closed their land borders: Czech Republic, Cyprus, Denmark, Hungary, Latvia, Lithuania, Poland, Slovakia and Spain.</p>
      <p>And they appear to have been joined by Germany and Estonia this morning, according to the BBC and Euractive respectively.</p>
      <p>One of the first countries to close its land borders was the Czech Republic, although, according to the Czech association of road transport users (CESMAD), the movement of goods was still allowed.</p>
      <p>“Operation of international road haulage remains without restrictions but there are measures to be applied by drivers of the international road haulage.</p>
      <p>“In particular, drivers in international transport are advised to protect themselves when loading/unloading and to limit contact with other people,” it told The Loadstar.</p>
      <p>However, the situation was markedly different in nearby Hungary, which has reportedly closed its borders to all road traffic, including trucks, leading Italy’s Minister of Infrastructure and Transport, Paola De Micheli, to telephone her Hungarian counterpart, László Palkovics, to request the withdrawal of the blockade at the border of the entry of drivers of trucks in transit or arrival in the country.</p>
      <p>“As part of a coordinated action with the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and with the other ministries concerned, the minister asked to ensure the restoration of the regular flow of Italian goods to the markets of Central and Eastern Europe and the Balkans and to return to normal border between Italy and Slovenia.</p>
      <p>“In recent days, similar talks with the same requests from Italy have been the subject of another call between Minister De Micheli and the Slovenian Minister of Infrastructure and Transport, Jernej Vrtovec,” a statement from Italy’s transport and infrastructure ministry said.</p>
      <p>Yesterday the European Commission issued new guidelines to member states to try and ensure European freight movements continue unimpeded, as it was “particularly crucial for essential goods such as food supplies including livestock, vital medical and protective equipment and supplies”, and that “member states should designate priority lanes for freight transport (eg, via ‘green lanes’)”.</p>
      <p>EC president Ursula von der Leyen said: “Our measures to contain the coronavirus outbreak will be effective only if we coordinate on the European level. We have to take exceptional measures to protect the health of our citizens.</p>
      <p>“But let’s make sure goods and essential services continue to flow in our internal market. This is the only way to prevent shortages of medical equipment or food. It’s not only an economic issue, our single market is a key instrument of European solidarity.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>f6c93b</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/keeping-cargo-flowing-will-save-lives-and-may-avoid-airline-bankruptcies/</url>
    <title>Keeping cargo flowing 'will save lives' – and may avoid airline bankruptcies</title>
    <author>Alex Lennane</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T14:26:55+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>airlines</topic>
      <topic>bankruptcy</topic>
      <topic>Bankruptcy Blues</topic>
      <topic>CAPA</topic>
      <topic>ERA</topic>
      <topic>IATA</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Most of the world’s airlines could be bankrupt in just 10 weeks, according to analysis by Capa.</p>
      <p>The analyst, however, noted this was a “catastrophe” that could be avoided, with coordinated government and industry action.</p>
      <p>And as if on cue, IATA stepped up to call on governments to facilitate freighter and freight-only flights.</p>
      <p>In a rare show of concern for cargo, IATA director general Alexandre de Juniac urged governments to “take urgent measures to ensure vital supply lines remain open, efficient and effective”.</p>
      <p>IATA outlined five ways in which they could support the industry: exclude air cargo operations from any Covid-19-related travel restrictions; ensure that standardised measures are in place so that air cargo can continue to move around the world with minimal disruption; exempt air cargo crew members who do not interact with the public from 14-day quarantine requirements; support temporary traffic rights for cargo operations where restrictions may apply; remove economic impediments, such as overfly charges, parking fees and slot restrictions.</p>
      <p>Arguing that air freight was one way to fight Covid-19, Mr de Juniac added: “Air cargo carriers are working closely with governments and health organisations around the world to safeguard public health while also keeping the global economy moving. Today, as we fight a global health war, governments must take urgent action to facilitate air cargo. Keeping cargo flowing will save lives.”</p>
      <p>The European Regions Airlines Association (ERA) also waded in.</p>
      <p>“Legislation, directives and guidance aimed at air passenger operations and the protection of air passengers on commercial flights, does not specifically exempt cargo flights and cargo flight crews.</p>
      <p>“At this moment, some states require that when a cargo flight returns to a country following minimal ground time as part of the turnaround process in a high-risk area, even if the crew do not leave the aircraft, effectively never leaving the territory of the aircraft registration and never entering the country in which they landed, they will be subject to 14 days of mandatory isolation. If this is to continue, airlines will quickly run out of flight crew to continue operations.”</p>
      <p>Atlas Air’s crew have already said they were worried about getting to work, a commute which tends to involve catching passenger flights.</p>
      <p>Capa explained that some airlines may already be technically bankrupt – or “at least substantially in breach of debt covenants”, while cash reserves, it said, “are running down quickly”.</p>
      <p>It added: “Demand is drying up in ways that are completely unprecedented. Normality is not yet on the horizon.”</p>
      <p>Capa said governments were sending mixed messages and there was “little instinct to act cooperatively”.</p>
      <p>“Each nation is adopting the solution that appears best suited to it, right or wrong, without consideration of its neighbours or trading partners,” it noted, adding that President Trump’s unilateral overnight travel ban was a case in point.</p>
      <p>“The fear is that, as a collapsed airline system is reconstituted, similar national self-interest will prevail. That’s important because the aviation industry is about much more than airline health. It is crucial to global communications and trade.”</p>
      <p>Capa blames foreign ownership rules, unionisation and cabotage rules for what is now a “fragmented and largely unviable airline industry”.</p>
      <p>“As things stand, the likely tepid response to the airline crisis will equally be fragmented and nationally based. It will consist mostly of bailing out selected national airlines.</p>
      <p>“If that is the default position, emerging from the crisis will be like entering a brutal battlefield, littered with casualties.” And it said, this could be a unique time to re-write the rules.</p>
      <p>You can read the full article here – it’s well worth it.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>9d457c</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/more-passenger-aircraft-become-freighters-as-borders-stay-open-for-cargo/</url>
    <title>More passenger aircraft become freighters as borders stay open for cargo</title>
    <author>Sam Whelan</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T14:26:07+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>air cargo market</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Korean Air</topic>
      <topic>Qantas</topic>
      <topic>Scan Global Logistics</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>More airlines are resorting to using passenger aircraft as makeshift freighters, as forwarders emphasise borders “remain open” for cargo.</p>
      <p>Following moves last week from Cathay Pacific and Scoot, the low-cost carrier of Singapore Airlines, yesterday Korean Air, Qantas and Delta Cargo all announced passenger aircraft would be used for cargo-only flights.</p>
      <p>Korean Air said it would begin using passenger jets to transport cargo on suspended routes, including Ho Chi Minh City and Qingdao, adding it hoped this would help “overcome the current crisis, as this would cut down expenses and support import and export companies”.</p>
      <p>Walter Cho, chairman of parent company Hanjin Group, said: “As the Covid-19 situation becomes increasingly dire, it is important for us to take a new perspective when looking at the market.</p>
      <p>“If we use the cargo compartment of our parked passenger aircraft, not only can we respond to the changing demand of cargo transport by diversifying our cargo routes, but we can also reduce aircraft parking fees.”</p>
      <p>The carrier said it completed one such cargo flight on Friday, using a 20-ton capacity A330-300 to carry emergency supplies and agricultural products from Korea to Ho Chi Minh City.</p>
      <p>Starting 21 March, Korean Air will deploy additional passenger aircraft to transport cargo to Qingdao, a route suspended on 25 February, and said it planned to expand the number of destinations and cargo to be transported by grounded passenger aircraft.</p>
      <p>Australian flag carrier Qantas is also set to use some domestic passenger aircraft for freight-only flights, replacing lost capacity from regular scheduled services.</p>
      <p>Qantas said today total group international and domestic capacity would be cut by around 90% and 60% respectively, until at least the end of May, following a rapid decline in forward travel demand.</p>
      <p>“This represents the grounding of around 150 aircraft, including almost all of the group’s wide-body fleet,” Qantas noted.</p>
      <p>The cargo division of US carrier Delta has announced it is launching a charter operation to support customers’ supply chains.</p>
      <p>“We recognise that our global supply chains need support for shipping essential goods to businesses and communities,” Delta said, saying 13 US airports and 70 international routes would be served.</p>
      <p>Rickard Ingvarsson, Asia chief executive and global head of airfreight at Scan Global Logistics, said more airlines in Europe, the US and Middle East were planning to introduce similar freighter services utilising grounded passenger fleets.</p>
      <p>“It’s an initiative we welcome with open arms, as this will improve current shortage of supply on the bigger tradelanes,” he told The Loadstar.</p>
      <p>Mr Ingvarsson also emphasised that freight is still moving despite the quarantines and lockdowns spreading around the world.</p>
      <p>“Borders across the globe remain open for cargo – there are no known restrictions, which may be a misconception,” he noted. “Naturally, longer lead-times and significant price volatility is expected as supply and demand changes day by day, however we remain committed to find cost-efficient solutions for all our customers.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
</corpus>
