<corpus>
  <document>
    <document_id>9f9955</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/quarantine-and-supply-chain-disruption-spreads-around-the-world/</url>
    <title>Quarantine and supply chain disruption spreads around the world</title>
    <author>Sam Whelan</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T14:56:07+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Land</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>ASEAN</topic>
      <topic>bill of lading</topic>
      <topic>Cogoport</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Europe</topic>
      <topic>US trucking</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Supply chain disruption outside China continues to spread, alongside the number of quarantines taking place around the world.</p>
      <p>In South-east Asia, Vietnam will seal its border with Cambodia tonight, according to Geodis.</p>
      <p>“No citizens of either country [will be] allowed to cross,” Geodis said. “From a supply chain standpoint, this stops the entire cross-border trucking between both countries.”</p>
      <p>Elsewhere in the region, Manila is in complete lockdown, although cargo is still moving, and the whole of Malaysia began a two-week lockdown on Wednesday. Malaysian citizens are barred from travelling overseas and foreign arrivals are not permitted.</p>
      <p>Similarly, India will suspend all scheduled international flights for one week, from 22 March.</p>
      <p>In Europe, Geodis warned operations could be impacted as its staff “transitioned to remote working”.</p>
      <p>It said: “CCL (Cargo Container Lines) original bill of lading, import and export shipments may not be handled as promptly as expected in most of our European branches. We recommend you use express CCL or ask your suppliers at origin to telex-release the documents through the Geodis offices at origin.”</p>
      <p>The issue of sending and receiving bill of lading documents via courier – still a common practice – could be another bottleneck for ocean freight during the crisis. One forwarder told The Loadstar: “Express companies are rejecting packages from China to Europe.</p>
      <p>“Those collected by them will be returned, as many EU incoming terminals are closed and capacity is cut by airlines as well. But we don’t know yet if this includes documents.”</p>
      <p>In the US, the port of Houston was forced to temporarily close two container terminals on Wednesday night, after a worker was diagnosed with coronavirus, while truckers across the country are having to deal with new restrictions aimed at “flattening the curve” of the virus.</p>
      <p>According The Wall Street Journal, shippers and receivers are asking to switch to electronic methods for documenting pick-ups and deliveries, and some are refusing to allow drivers to enter their building if they have travelled to virus “hot zones”.</p>
      <p>According to Flemming Frost, president of Cogoport, challenges for forwarders and carriers alike will be a lack of both cargo and staff.</p>
      <p>“There will be issues with resources in the ports to handle the volumes,” he told The Loadstar. “Crane and gantry drivers will be down in numbers, as will the trucks to take cargo to/from the port. The back offices will struggle to keep up and deliver on the timeline.</p>
      <p>“Fewer trucks may be available as drivers self-quarantine or follow employer or government direction to do so,” Mr Frost added, and warned of financial catastrophe on the horizon for many in the industry.</p>
      <p>“Ultimately, shippers will not get quotes timely, and may lose the little business they can generate, adding to their bankruptcy risk.</p>
      <p>“Many in Europe have a dream that this is a three-to-four-week event – they may be disappointed when this drags on towards summer,” said Mr Frost.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>e51148</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/force-majeure-getting-it-wrong-can-be-a-very-expensive-business/</url>
    <title>Force majeure: getting it wrong can be a very expensive business</title>
    <author>Alex Lennane</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T14:55:54+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>DHL Global Forwarding</topic>
      <topic>Force Majeure</topic>
      <topic>World Insurance Services</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>DHL Global Forwarding has declared force majeure on its sea and air freight contracts, allowing it to modify its services despite the agreements.</p>
      <p>Invoking force majeure allows companies to protect themselves from legal responsibility, something forwarders have been particularly concerned with.</p>
      <p>However, insurance companies are advising caution before invoking the clause.</p>
      <p>“Force majeure is defined as ‘an event, or a series of related events, that is outside the reasonable control of the party affected’, which can include anything from industrial disputes and riots to a zombie apocalypse,” explained Richard Kamppari Baker, claims manager for World Insurance Services.</p>
      <p>“Many forwarders, shippers, receivers and carriers will be looking over their contracts to see whether they can forfeit their shipments, services agreements or bookings to avoid increased costs and expenditure.</p>
      <p>“The consequences can range from damages and re-shipping costs to cancellation of freight. “</p>
      <p>However, he added: “To invoke the clause is much harder than common belief, and there are even different interpretations between civil and common law jurisdictions.</p>
      <p>“Generally, a delay or interruption in performance will give rise to force majeure, but whether this can be enforced will often come down to the specific wording of that clause. Get this right and you could save thousands of dollars. Getting this wrong could lead to a breach of contract and be very costly.</p>
      <p>“If a government has closed ports, that physically prevents the carrier discharging cargo and this would generally support such a definition, but the shutdown of banks or local offices, even for the heath and safety reasons, may not be sufficient grounds.”</p>
      <p>He also said that a slowdown on shipments or bookings, triggered by an event, would rarely come under force majeure.</p>
      <p>“Many service or slots agreements will no longer fulfil bookings, but regrettably this may not be enough for force majeure, as it could be deemed commercial.”</p>
      <p>While most international conventions, such as Hague Visby rules, refer to force majeure, he said that to successfully enforce it would depend on three factors: The choice of law or jurisdiction in which the contract is governed; specific clauses in the contract and/or overriding exemptions; and seeking legal advice.</p>
      <p>Ironically, DHL itself warned supply chain managers last month about the dangers of companies invoking force majeure.</p>
      <p>“With production and logistics operations across China gradually resuming, supply chain managers across industries like automotive, machinery and chemicals may soon face a new risk dimension pertaining to the coronavirus outbreak – suppliers or buyers invoking force majeure,” noted DHL’s resilience360 website.</p>
      <p>“As [Chinese] authorities seek to provide financial and legal support to companies struggling with the coronavirus fallout, the China Council for the Promotion of International Trade has already issued force majeure certificates to 1,615 companies covering 30 sectors and a total contract value of Rmb109.9bn ($15.7bn) until 16 February.</p>
      <p>“These certificates shield companies from legal and financial damages arising from not performing, or only partially performing, contractual duties such as delivering, transporting or taking cargo, by proving that they are experiencing circumstances beyond their control.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>07bf59</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/disciplined-capacity-management-by-carriers-keeps-freight-rates-in-line/</url>
    <title>Disciplined capacity management by carriers keeps freight rates in line</title>
    <author>Gavin van Marle</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T14:55:25+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Asia-Mediterranean</topic>
      <topic>Asia-North Europe</topic>
      <topic>Asia-US east coast</topic>
      <topic>FBX</topic>
      <topic>Freightos</topic>
      <topic>Rates: the eternal tango</topic>
      <topic>SCFI</topic>
      <topic>Transpacific Trade</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Continued discipline over capacity management by container lines managed to keep freight rates from tumbling this week as increased levels of factory production in China began to be offset by coronavirus crisis that has gripped Europe and North America.</p>
      <p>Last week’s double-digit gain on the transpacific headhaul route from China to the US west coast on the SCFI was reversed this week, with its Shanghai-USWC rate dipping 3.8% to $1,549 per feu.</p>
      <p>Similarly, the Shanghai-US east coast freight rate fell 4.4% to finish the week at $2,785 per feu, as US demand for imports appeared to be declining dramatically, reportedly leading the east coast gateway of Miami to temporarily suspend port operations due to lack of cargo.</p>
      <p>However, there has been a divergence between indices this week, as the Freightos Baltic Index (FBX) has shown a 12% increase in China-USWC prices to $1,477 per feu and a 7% increase on China-US east coast rates to $2,730 per feu.</p>
      <p>“I assume this is a matter of the market stabilising as demand for shipping from China increases (driving prices up), and fewer sailings are blanked (driving prices down),” Freightos chief marketing officer Eytan Buchman told The Loadstar today.</p>
      <p>“We’re continuing to see prices rise and I anticipate this will continue as companies continue to replenish inventories; this week alone (since Monday), the FBX daily increased 8% for shipping from China to the US west coast,” he added.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, Asia-Europe trades also recorded a slight decline as carriers managed capacity in expectation of a steep drop in demand for goods from Asia.</p>
      <p>The SCFI’s Shanghai-North Europe leg fell by 3.6% to $797 per teu, and 1.2% to Mediterranean ports, to end the week at $892 per teu.</p>
      <p>Martin Holst-Mikkelsen, EMEA head of ocean freight for Flexport, explained: “Rates have remained relatively stable in the past four weeks, with only a marginal rate erosion – carriers recognise that there is a limited amount of spot cargo available in the market to shift around and have acted with discipline.</p>
      <p>“Activity has resumed in China, and demand has picked up very well in the past few weeks and will continue in the week to come. But we expect the resumption of demand to be short lived. The impact of Covid-19, and lockdown in an increasing number of countries across Europe, presents us all with unprecedented uncertainty and a set of challenges we have not previously faced.</p>
      <p>“We can expect the recent developments to lead to declining consumer demand across Europe, especially for non-essential goods. Carriers are informing us they have observed this trend during the past few days through an increasing number of cancellations from their large BCO customers, affecting bookings in the month to come.</p>
      <p>“We expect a decline in demand will force carriers to increase the number of blank sailings going into April, in an attempt to address supply/demand imbalance and reduce the risk of significant rate erosion,” he continued.</p>
      <p>In an illuminating blog on LinkedIn this week, SeaIntelligence Consulting partner Lars Jensen warned that the decline in demand in Europe and elsewhere could be unprecedented.</p>
      <p>“Consumers will reduce their spending. Not only are many shops closed, but many consumers will also fear for their jobs and hence scale back on consumption of non-essentials.</p>
      <p>“Likewise, businesses have very little clarity over the immediate future and will halt the ordering of additional goods beyond what they are absolutely certain they can sell.</p>
      <p>“These effects will have a strong impact – and are the exact same effects which impacted the industry during the financial crisis. How strong remains to be seen, but the effect in China was a 20% decline in retail sales in January and February,” he wrote.</p>
      <p>However, he also warned that once the worse effects of the outbreak were over, the outlook for Asia-Europe container supply chains could change rapidly.</p>
      <p>“Once we are past the pandemic and countries revert to normal, we should expect a surge of cargo. Even if the economy remains subdued, businesses might have to re-stock some of their inventories, which itself has a strong impact on container demand.</p>
      <p>“Hence, during this rebound phase, we should expect a shortage of shipping capacity and rising freight rates,” he said.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>355328</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/maersk-bins-its-2020-financial-guidance-due-to-impact-of-pandemic/</url>
    <title>Maersk bins its 2020 financial guidance, due to impact of pandemic</title>
    <author>Mike Wackett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T14:54:20+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>IMO low-sulphur regulations</topic>
      <topic>Maersk</topic>
      <topic>The Purse Strings</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Despite its expectations of delivering a better first-quarter result than last year, Maersk said today it was suspending its guidance on full-year earnings as a result of the coronavirus outbreaks around the world.</p>
      <p>It said the global pandemic was severely impacting global transport and supply chains, “leading to material uncertainties and lack of visibility”.</p>
      <p>It added that while its global operations were “running as normal”, it had decided to suspend its 2020 guidance of an ebitda of around $5.5bn, “pending more clarity on the market development and financial implications”.</p>
      <p>In a trading update, Maersk said that, based on its preliminary figures, it expected a first-quarter ebitda, before restructuring and integration costs, of around $1.24bn, which was “negatively impacted by weak volume development”, but mitigated by strong implementation of IMO 2020 fuel price recovery.</p>
      <p>“We have executed well on our IMO 2020 strategy for how to manage the extra cost involved with the IMO mandated switch to low-sulphur fuel oil from 1 January,” said chief executive Soren Skou.</p>
      <p>“We consequently expect to deliver a Q1 20 which is better than Q1 19, despite declining volumes across our businesses, driven by the Covid-19 pandemic.”</p>
      <p>Maersk said guidance for its 2020 volume growth for liner business was “expected to be in line with, or slightly lower than, market growth”.</p>
      <p>Maersk will publish its first-quarter results on 13 May.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>2cb64f</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/hapag-lloyds-2019-profits-soar-but-it-fears-the-shape-of-things-to-come/</url>
    <title>Hapag-Lloyd's 2019 profits soar, but it fears the shape of things to come</title>
    <author>Mike Wackett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T14:53:39+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Hapag-Lloyd</topic>
      <topic>The Purse Strings</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Hapag-Lloyd outperformed its ocean carrier peers last year, recording a net profit of $418m against $54m in 2018.</p>
      <p>Nevertheless, the carrier has warned that the impact of coronavirus on global demand would require capacity adjustments and adversely affect its earnings in the first half of this year, and beyond.</p>
      <p>During an earnings call presentation today, chief executive Rolf Habben Jansen said “2019 might seem a long time ago”, given the current coronavirus crisis.</p>
      <p>He said current expectation was for a financial hit from May onwards, after volumes carried at the beginning of Q1 were ahead of projections and current bookings were holding up.</p>
      <p>Due to Covid-19 restrictions, he said the majority of Hapag-Lloyd’s staff were working remotely, with a “crisis committee” meeting every other day.</p>
      <p>Hapag-Lloyd’s turnover increased by 3% in 2019, compared with the previous year, to $14.1bn, earned from carryings of 12m teu, which were only up 1.4% in line with the carrier’s strategy to target better-paying cargo.</p>
      <p>Its “deliberate reduction of volume in the intra-Asia trade and focus on more profitable services” saw Hapag-Lloyd’s average rate per teu increase by 2.7% to $1,072 per teu.</p>
      <p>The carrier saw a massive 65% increase in ebitda to $2.22bn, which included the positive effect of around $523m from the impact of the IFRS 16 new accounting rules on vessel charters.</p>
      <p>By contrast, French carrier CMA CGM attributed part of the blame for a $229 net loss last year on the same IFRS 16 regulations.</p>
      <p>“Today we are in rapidly changing and uncertain times, but that does not take away that 2019 was a very good year for Hapag-Lloyd,” said Mr Habben Jansen.</p>
      <p>“We benefited from higher volumes and better freight rates, kept a close eye on our costs and brought down our debt significantly. We also continued implementing our Strategy 2023, and achieved a group net result that is well above the prior year result.”</p>
      <p>After a “decent start” this year, Mr Habben Jansen said Hapag-Lloyd’s guidance of an ebitda of €1.7bn to €2.2bn was subject to “considerably higher uncertainties than normal”.</p>
      <p>Earlier today Maersk suspended its 2020 guidance, citing “current uncertainties”.</p>
      <p>Mr Habben Jansen said: “Hapag-Lloyd anticipates that transport capacity deployments may have to be adjusted in light of coronavirus in the coming months to cope with lower demand. The extent of the coronavirus outbreak cannot be accurately predicted, but Hapag-Lloyd expects it will have an impact on the development of earnings, at least in the first half of 2020.”</p>
      <p>He said the carrier had been obliged to lease an additional 80,000 teu in Asia and 25,000 teu in Europe, due to equipment shortages resulting from the extended blank sailing programme after the Chinese new year.</p>
      <p>As the lead line in THE Alliance, Hapag-Lloyd, along with its VSA partners ONE and Yang Ming and new member HMM, is preparing to launch a revised network from 1 April to coincide with the South Korean carrier joining the group.</p>
      <p>However, given the virus-induced expected demand slump in Europe and the US, the alliance could be obliged to postpone the launch.</p>
      <p>“2020 will be a very unusual year”, with “conditions in many markets changed very quickly over the last weeks”, said Mr Habben Jansen.</p>
      <p>He said the carrier would take “precautionary financial measures to weather the storm”, if it lasted longer than anticipated.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>3a1ec5</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/zim-a-strong-operational-and-financial-performance-in-a-difficult-2019/</url>
    <title>Zim – 'a strong operational and financial performance' in a difficult 2019</title>
    <author>Gavin van Marle</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T14:52:58+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>2M</topic>
      <topic>Asia-Mediterranean</topic>
      <topic>Asia-US Gulf</topic>
      <topic>Asia-US west coast</topic>
      <topic>The Purse Strings</topic>
      <topic>Zim</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Despite a marginal decline in volumes, Israeli container carrier Zim has reported significant improvement in financial results last year.</p>
      <p>In 2019, it earned revenue of $3.3bn, compared with $3.25bn in 2018, a 1.6% increase, which came on the back of a 3.7% increase in the average freight rate to $1,009 per teu compared with $973 per teu in 2018.</p>
      <p>Total volumes were 2.8m teu compared with 2.9m teu in 2018.</p>
      <p>Its adjusted ebitda was $385.9m, compared with $150.7m in 2018, and on this it posted a net loss of $13m compared with a net loss of $119.9m in 2018.</p>
      <p>Eli Glickman, Zim president and chief executive, said: “2019 has been a challenging year for the industry which had to cope with the escalation of the US-China trade war, while simultaneously getting itself ready for the IMO 2020 new regulation enforcement.</p>
      <p>“Despite those difficult market conditions, we delivered a strong operational and financial performance with better ebit margin contribution than most of our peers. We also accelerated the deleveraging of our balance sheet,” he said.</p>
      <p>Its 2019 operating cash flow was $370.6m, compared with $225m in 2018, as the carrier expanded its vessel sharing agreement with the 2M partners Maersk and MSC to three additional trades: Asia-East Mediterranean; Asia-American Pacific Northwest; and Asia-US Gulf.</p>
      <p>“This clearly indicates that our strategy proves to be fruitful and effective and we intend to continue the path we initiated,” Mr Glickmann added.</p>
      <p>“We continue to develop and implement lead innovative solutions, and we remain agile and ready to respond fast to new challenges. I’m convinced that these values will enable us to overcome the current coronavirus crisis, which we all hope will be contained soon.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>454689</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/uk-and-ireland-increase-truckers-working-hours-to-keep-supply-chains-moving/</url>
    <title>UK and Ireland increase truckers' working hours to keep supply chains moving</title>
    <author>Alex Lennane</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:31:43+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Land</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>driver rules</topic>
      <topic>driver shortage</topic>
      <topic>EU</topic>
      <topic>Ireland</topic>
      <topic>UK</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Driver hours restrictions across the UK and Ireland have been relaxed, allowing an extra hour of work before taking a break.</p>
      <p>The new rules in the UK stipulate that drivers may now drive for up to 5.5 hours before a 45-minute break, and the daily driving period has been increased to 11 hours, once a week. Daily rest periods have been cut to nine hours.</p>
      <p>The new rules have been designed to bring greater flexibility and allow drivers to complete journeys without a break, and/or return to a depot rather than parking overnight.</p>
      <p>Ireland’s minister for transport, tourism and sport Shane Ross explained: “We have granted a temporary relaxation of the EU driving and resting time rules due to the Covid-19 public health crisis, recognising the importance of the haulage industry to the economy, and in response to requests from the industry itself.</p>
      <p>“Critically, we are striking a balance between driver welfare, operator flexibility, road safety and minimising disruption to supply chains.</p>
      <p>“I have also requested that these arrangements be kept under continual review. I want to thank our hauliers for their support and hard work in this difficult time. With their help we will keep our chains of supply for food and essential goods moving.”</p>
      <p>It is as yet unclear whether other EU member states are taking similar action, but relaxation of the rules seems inevitable, as media report long truck queues at borders in Europe.</p>
      <p>As borders close, drivers were waiting up to 18 hours at several. The worst, according to Business Insider, was on the A4 between Germany and Poland, where a 60km traffic jam had formed.</p>
      <p>Thousands of trucks were also stuck on the Lithuanian and Polish border after Poland ordered a coronavirus test for every driver. And while Hungary temporarily opened its borders on Tuesday night, by the morning there was a new 27km queue on the Austrian side.</p>
      <p>You can see the UK’s new rules here, and Ireland’s here.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>1e2287</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/air-freight-sector-pushes-hard-to-help-and-for-help-to-fight-the-virus/</url>
    <title>Air freight sector pushes hard to help – and for help – to fight the virus</title>
    <author>Alex Lennane</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:30:44+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>IAG Cargo</topic>
      <topic>IATA</topic>
      <topic>Lufthansa Cargo</topic>
      <topic>TIACA</topic>
      <topic>Turkish Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>As Tiaca and Iata continue to lobby governments to relax restrictions on cargo movements, airlines are looking for ways to keep shipments flying.</p>
      <p>IAG Cargo sent a note to customers yesterday, offering its passenger aircraft for charters.</p>
      <p>“To support your freight and to help get it where it needs to be, we are now opening up the opportunity for freight forwarders to charter our aircraft where needed,” wrote chief commercial officer John Cheetham.</p>
      <p>Lufthansa Cargo also looked to try to reassure customers.</p>
      <p>“We are doing everything in our power to keep our freighter services stable. On the other side, the extensive changes within our network of passenger flights have a direct impact on the available belly capacities. In order to compensate for these shortfalls, changes in the scheduling of our cargo aircraft are also likely in the coming days.”</p>
      <p>It told customers developments were “too dynamic” and urged them to visit its website or Twitter feed to learn of daily flight changes.</p>
      <p>“We will also inform you about currently bookable connections via our API interface and our network page,” it added. “We regret the necessary adjustments to the flight schedule and the inconvenience caused – and thank you for your commitment and cooperation in these challenging times.”</p>
      <p>Turkish Cargo said it was increasing its freighter frequencies to “full capacity”, while also using passenger aircraft for cargo demand.</p>
      <p>“Turkish Cargo will start to serve for cargo transport purposes by making use of the aircraft available in its fleet, in addition to its current cargo freighter capacity, which was increased to 25 from 13 during the last four years.”</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, Tiaca this morning joined Iata in lobbying governments for support.</p>
      <p>“The air cargo industry has a decisive role to play in the fight against Covid-19 and the industry’s voice must be fully heard by regulators and governments,” it said</p>
      <p>“This is why Tiaca has joined the ICAO technical group on joint actions related to Covid-19, other members of which are the WHO, Iata, ACI and GEA.”</p>
      <p>It said its goal was to draw attention to the critical role of air cargo, but also to the financial challenges facing the industry. It cited lease payments on aircraft, salaries, energy supplies and other payments, as well as difficulties stemming from travel bans, crew movement restrictions, airport slots and route changes.</p>
      <p>“We support Iata’s appeal to have air cargo recognised as vital in the fight against Covid-19, and for action to be taken – in particular, removing all travel restrictions on air cargo operations and taking all necessary measures to allow air cargo to continue to circulate around the world,” said Steven Polmans, Tiaca chairman.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>236fd3</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/factories-switch-production-to-boost-medical-supplies-to-fight-covid-19/</url>
    <title>Factories switch production to boost medical supplies to fight Covid-19</title>
    <author>Alex Lennane</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:29:00+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Flexport</topic>
      <topic>Humanitarian logistics</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Growing numbers of companies are changing tack, shelving production of normal wares to make hand sanitiser and other medical products.</p>
      <p>Some forwarders, meanwhile, are offering to ship them.</p>
      <p>French luxury group LVMH has switched its luxury perfumes for sanitiser, while small gin distilleries across the UK and Ireland and France’s Pernod Ricard have also stepped in as alcohol supplies in Europe dwindle.</p>
      <p>Flow Water Technologies has offered to supply the Cyprus government with disinfectant free of charge, after it ramped up production of disinfectant compound sodium hypochlorite. It is now capable of making five cubic metres of high-concentrate a day, the equivalent of 60 cubic metres of sanitiser.</p>
      <p>“We have taken the joint decision to put aside our immediate commercial objectives and help assist with the national fight against Covid-19 infection escalation,” said chief executive Mark Hadfield.</p>
      <p>“Cyprus imports chemicals, but it will soon run out. As Flow Water Technologies BWMS solution holds a Cyprus biocide licence for the emergency services, the moral obligation was clear.”</p>
      <p>But it’s not just manufacturers looking to help the fight against coronavirus.</p>
      <p>Flexport.org is to export thousands of coronavirus test kits from Asian suppliers to the US west coast, but added that it had “limited resources to pay for all of these and other urgently needed supplies for the healthcare system”, and called for donations.</p>
      <p>It said: “It’s time to punch back, join humanity’s counterattack by making a tax-deductible donation. 100% of your money will go toward buying and shipping critical products for the world’s healthcare systems in this time of need.”</p>
      <p>Another forwarder, on LinkedIn, commented: “I proudly work for a rival company, but I absolutely applaud these efforts as we all need to work together, especially in the logistics/supply chain community.”</p>
      <p>You can help: click here.</p>
      <p>If you know of any businesses providing humanitarian or charitable services, please let alex@theloadstar.com know and we will help promote it.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>287830</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/working-from-home-can-be-tricky-for-freight-firms-with-onsite-only-tech/</url>
    <title>'Working from home' can be tricky for freight firms with 'onsite-only' tech</title>
    <author>Sam Whelan</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:28:13+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Cogoport</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Digital freight forwarder</topic>
      <topic>Flexport</topic>
      <topic>freight forwarders</topic>
      <topic>FreightBro</topic>
      <topic>Kontainers</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Forwarders and carriers are being stretched to the limit by lockdowns and quarantines sweeping the globe, forcing large-scale remote working and reduced resources.</p>
      <p>And Flemming Frost, president of digital freight marketplace Cogoport, believes remote working will “hurt more” than many realise – “Even among the big players,” he told The Loadstar.</p>
      <p>“I spoke with a top 10 carrier and it is down on resources across many locations, as such staff are flat-out to just keep the daily business together.”</p>
      <p>While investment into freight-tech and digitalisation has been a hot industry topic in recent years, many logistics firms are likely ill-prepared to operate efficiently under “work from home” conditions.</p>
      <p>“The lack of tech and automation means many processes are ‘band-aided’ by ‘human APIs’, and when the humans are either away from work or ill-equipped to work from alternative locations, that will hurt,” explained Mr Frost.</p>
      <p>“A check with a small forwarder gave me the same impression – half the staff are at the office and the rest can only work at half-capacity due to an inability to access all the required material and systems from outside the office.”</p>
      <p>According to Mark Yong, MD for Asia Pacific at multimodal digital supply chain platform Blume Global, many freight companies still rely on legacy systems which can only be operated onsite, due to network security.</p>
      <p>“Medium-size companies are probably suffering the most, as they don’t have adequate tools,” he noted.</p>
      <p>Seko Logistics announced remote working at its global headquarters in Chicago this week. Group commercial director Keith Gaskin said the industry needed to embrace digital transformation at a quicker pace.</p>
      <p>“That includes the archaic bill of lading process,” he said, “especially in times like this when a piece of paper is often still needed to exchange hands [which] is crazy.</p>
      <p>“There are obviously alternatives, but from some regions, L/Cs still stipulate multiple copies of the bills need to be presented. Hard to do if an office is in lockdown or the post office/courier services are unable to work.”</p>
      <p>Flexport, meanwhile, is looking to collaborate, according to CEO Ryan Petersen, who explained: “If you work at a customs brokerage or freight forwarder that can’t maintain operations because of your IT set up, please reach out.</p>
      <p>“This is a crucial time for us to all help each other to keep supply chains moving, especially as there may be life-saving goods in some of these shipments.”</p>
      <p>However, one customs broker said: “We are fully equipped to work remotely with zero service interruptions. Most brokers are.”</p>
      <p>Perhaps sensing a need for greater digital capabilities among forwarders, freight-tech companies Kontainers and FreightBro both announced this week that new users could temporarily access their respective products free of charge.</p>
      <p>Similarly, Australian firm A2B Solution Group, a service partner of the Cargowise One platform, said it had developed an “essential workflow package that will allow your staff to work from home within 24 hours of engagement”.</p>
      <p>“Best of all,” A2B added, “the implementation package comes with a company specific guide and a free roll of toilet paper.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>da44b0</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/global-retailers-cancelling-orders-threatens-bangladesh-garment-industry/</url>
    <title>Global retailers cancelling orders threatens Bangladesh garment industry</title>
    <author>Bangladesh correspondent</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:27:27+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Bangladesh</topic>
      <topic>Chittagong</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>garments</topic>
      <topic>Talking shop: the retail business</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Major retailers are cancelling or postponing orders, putting Bangladesh’s garment industry, the country’s top foreign currency earner and employer, in jeopardy.</p>
      <p>The value of order cancellations up to yesterday reached $124m – but the industry expects more to follow.</p>
      <p>The top buyers so far forced to cancel or withhold orders include C&amp;A, Zara, Pull and Bear, Baby Shop, Blackberrys, Inditex and Primark.</p>
      <p>Apparel manufacturers say that just after Covid-19 hit China, they faced a shortage of raw materials, which disrupted their production.</p>
      <p>Prices of locally available raw materials went up significantly, but the problem had eased to some extent as shipments from China began to resume.</p>
      <p>But now, as the virus spreads all over the world, the US and EU main markets for Bangladeshi apparel are severely affected, and the demand for ready-made garments has dropped, following the lockdown of many areas and clothing stores closing.</p>
      <p>“Every day we are hearing messages from buyers, either for cancellations or withheld [orders],” former president of Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) Siddiqur Rahman told The Loadstar.</p>
      <p>“My three factories faced order cancellations for 1.5 million garment items,” said Mr Rahman, who is also chairman of Bando Design, whose factory supplies clothes for H&amp;M, belk, Matalan, C&amp;A, Walmart, Indian Terrain, Westside, Mango and Zara.</p>
      <p>The company will have a staff meeting today to assess the immediate impact of Coronavirus on the business, he said. “It’s an uncertain situation. No one knows how far it will go.”</p>
      <p>Chairman of Evince Group Anwar-ul Alam Chowdhury said manufacturers were receiving cancellations every hour or more. His factory supplies retailers such as Celio, Tesco, Sears, Carrefour, Debenhams, Lee, DeFacto, Wrangler, kmart, F&amp;F and Bexleys.</p>
      <p>“One retailer asked to halt production in factories up to June. It wanted a 30% discount on ready goods and said it will renegotiate a price for suspended orders,” he said.</p>
      <p>“A factory owner told me yesterday he sent 10 million pieces garments to Chittagong port, but the buyer is now asking him to take them back to the factory,” he added.</p>
      <p>Mr Chowdhury, also a former president of BGMEA, said one of the largest buyers, Inditex, had asked another factory owner to postpone cutting cloth for another 10 million pieces.</p>
      <p>“One of my customers in France said its offices were closed, do not ship the goods, we will let you know. And the order sheets for delivering goods in May and June are yet to come,” he said.</p>
      <p>Many retailers had closed their stores worldwide for weeks and months, he added. “What will they do with goods after taking delivery?”</p>
      <p>He said his government needed to come up with a financial package for the garment makers to save the sector.</p>
      <p>“A crisis fund can be formed to support the industry.”</p>
      <p>Imports and exports of goods through Chittagong port have plummeted since coronavirus hit the globe. In February, imports fell by 17% compared with January. Export earnings also saw a massive nosedive, and the trend may continue through the year.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>0272e6</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/hmm-takes-100000-teu-of-capacity-from-the-2m-to-its-new-alliance/</url>
    <title>HMM takes 100,000 teu of capacity from the 2M to its new alliance</title>
    <author>Mike Wackett</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:26:28+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>2M</topic>
      <topic>Alphaliner</topic>
      <topic>Hapag-Lloyd</topic>
      <topic>HMM</topic>
      <topic>Maersk</topic>
      <topic>MSC</topic>
      <topic>THE Alliance</topic>
      <topic>Yang Ming</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>HMM is to receive nine ships back that Maersk and MSC sub-chartered March 2017 as part of the carrier’s slot charter agreement with the 2M.</p>
      <p>The redelivered tonnage includes three 13,092 teu Danaos-owned vessels on long-term charter from the Greek shipowner.</p>
      <p>According to one London broker source, Maersk and MSC took over the charters of the three ships at a discount on the charter party daily hire rate, with HMM paying the difference to owners.</p>
      <p>The source told The Loadstar that, having already exceptionally agreed to discount the daily hire rate to HMM during the carrier’s cost-cutting measures designed to ensure its survival, Danaos “held firm” on the revised rate.</p>
      <p>At the time, HMM was not in a strong negotiating position, needing to become part of an alliance to receive several tranches of desperately needed funding from state-owned banks, but it was denied full membership of the 2M and only able to secure a slot charter deal.</p>
      <p>As a consequence, HMM was unable to deploy its own ships on the Asia to Europe tradelane, and the 2M partners “took them off their hands”, according to the broker.</p>
      <p>However, subsequently HMM has been accepted as a full member of rival THE Alliance, alongside Hapag-Lloyd, ONE and Yang Ming, and will officially join the VSA on 1 April.</p>
      <p>The Danaos ships, along with five 10,081 teu vessels also sub-chartered to Maersk and MSC, will be deployed on THEA’s new east-west network, stemmed to start on 1 April.</p>
      <p>Notwithstanding HMM recording five consecutive years of losses, including $511m last year and $708m in 2018, the carrier is taking delivery of 12 24,000 teu ULCVs between April and September. They will be phased into THEA’s FE4 loop, replacing Hapag-Lloyd’s 11 15,000 teu ships.</p>
      <p>According to Alphaliner, the redelivered vessels and the newbuild ULCVs will add 388,000 teu to HMM’s fleet, taking the carrier’s total capacity to some 790,000 teu. It will leapfrogging its THEA partner, Yang Ming (with around 607,000 teu of capacity), to take eighth place in the carrier league table.</p>
      <p>When the newbuilds have all been delivered, HMM will be some way to achieving president and CEO Jae-hoon Bae’s rehabilitation target for the carrier: reaching one million teu capacity.</p>
      <p>The consultant said the redelivery of the ships to HMM “would not have a significant impact” on the overall fleet deployment of Maersk and MSC, with the outgoing tonnage mainly being replaced by ships returning from scrubber installation.</p>
      <p>Moreover, with so many blanked sailings since Chinese new year due to the coronavirus outbreak, and the fear of a significant global demand slump as the virus causes lockdowns around the world, the 2M partners could be looking to downsize their network offering for the duration of the crisis.</p>
      <p>Indeed, a similar message could follow from THEA partners, obliging HMM to pause delivery of its new scrubber-fitted flagships.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>30a4b4</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/sea-air-services-disrupted-and-rates-soar-as-airlines-suspend-more-flights/</url>
    <title>Sea-air services disrupted and rates soar as airlines suspend more flights</title>
    <author>Alex Lennane</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T14:42:14+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Aeromar</topic>
      <topic>Arise surcharges</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Dubai</topic>
      <topic>SAT Albatros</topic>
      <topic>Sea-air</topic>
      <topic>Singapore</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Sea-air shipments via Dubai and Singapore to Europe and the US have either been suspended or seen prices soar.</p>
      <p>Aeromar, which specialises in sea freight to Dubai and onward travel by air, said it had suspended its services with immediate effect, although all cargo currently on route would continue.</p>
      <p>It said it had been forced to make this decision as airlines began cancelling flights from Dubai.</p>
      <p>“We can fix rates three weeks in advance, but if during the sea voyage, flights get cancelled, it’s pretty difficult to go back and ask a customer for more money to use one of the few carriers left,” said MD Nick Coverdale.</p>
      <p>“And with air cargo rates still not that expensive from Hong Kong and South-east Asia, for example, the sea-air service doesn’t look that attractive, especially with the uncertainties. The only option is to put the goods back on ship going to Europe, but that’s not realistic.</p>
      <p>“Shippers deserve better.”</p>
      <p>He said the company would review the situation over the weekend.</p>
      <p>SAT Albatros, another Dubai-based sea-air outfit, has suspended all rate agreements and added a $1 per kg surcharge on all live shipments.</p>
      <p>It has also suspended sea-air traffic via Singapore and Dubai into the US and its service from Singapore to Europe, the US and South Africa. Only its Dubai-Europe service is available.</p>
      <p>The company told customers: “We are monitoring the situation carefully and will keep you updated. All cargo that is on the way to transit hubs on all routes for uplifting, we will individually advise revised costing and routing amendment.</p>
      <p>“In Dubai, the situation has also changed overnight. Many flights have been taken out and rate levels are moving upwards heavily. All airfreight agreements have been cancelled with immediate effect.</p>
      <p>“It will also affect the shipments we have on hand; shipments that are on the sea or even arrived in Dubai.”</p>
      <p>“In order to ensure live shipments are uplifted, we’ve implemented a short-term emergency surcharge of $1 per kg effective immediately. All existing rate agreements are temporarily suspended. Applicable rates are now to be confirmed on booking.”</p>
      <p>However, one UK-based forwarder said it was still operating sea-air services via Dubai, and that “rates are still a fraction of air freight from Far East/China currently”.</p>
      <p>He added that Singapore still had passenger carriers operating and that rates there “had not fluctuated much”, although reduced flights by the major Chinese carriers would add some pressure.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>dcfb4e</document_id>
    <url>https://theloadstar.com/queensland-covid-19-vessel-ban-is-reckless-and-indefensible-says-shipping-group/</url>
    <title>Queensland Covid-19 vessel ban is 'reckless and indefensible', says shipping group</title>
    <author>Gavin van Marle</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T14:41:24+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Loadstar posts</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Asia-Australia</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Shipping Australia</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Australian shipping lobby group Shipping Australia has slammed today’s decision by the state of Queensland to introduce restrictions on ships calling at its ports, particularly the container hub of Brisbane.</p>
      <p>Maritime Safety Queensland (MSQ) today banned all commercial ships from entering ports in the state if the ship, or anyone on board, has been in any country outside Australia within the past 14 days.</p>
      <p>Contravention of the MSQ ruling is a criminal offence, for which the maximum penalty is A$66,725 ($40,000) for an individual and A$333,625 for a corporation.</p>
      <p>Shipping Australia said it understood other maritime authorities in the country were considering similar restrictions, and claimed they could put society as a whole at risk.</p>
      <p>“Australian port authorities are now exacerbating an already bad coronavirus situation by restricting the ability of cargo ships to deliver desperately needed goods.</p>
      <p>“This is putting Australian families at risk by potentially causing supply chain shortages of medicines and everyday consumer needs,” it added.</p>
      <p>Shipping Australia’s chief executive, Rod Nairn, said: “The MSQ policy is reckless and indefensible; cargo ship crews are probably the lowest-risk sector in the world, with not one cargo ship crew member yet being confirmed as having Covid-19.”</p>
      <p>The organisation noted that most Asia-Australia shipping services “are only six to eight days’ duration and ships would have to potentially wait around for up to 14 days to enter.</p>
      <p>“And that’s at a cost of A$25,000 a day. When a port entry costs about A$250,000 a time, shipping lines are indicating that these directions from port authorities to stay away are simply unsustainable”, it said.</p>
      <p>It further claimed that some carriers could be forced to omit port calls, which would “lead to massive relocation of cargo away from where it is supposed to be and it will have to be trucked across the continent.</p>
      <p>“Trucking costs could escalate. Australia is a big place – it will take days upon days to get to where it is needed. Costs to everyday Australians could rocket.”</p>
      <p>And it also claimed that the restrictions would also hit container supply chains serving New Zealand and the Pacific Islands, for which Australian ports commonly act as hubs.</p>
      <p>“Blocking shipping’s ability to deliver desperately needed freight to the islands is not an optimal outlook.</p>
      <p>“Meanwhile, New Zealand and Australia both have 14-day exclusion periods. So, as of now, the Aus-New Zealand trade is being killed off,” it said.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
</corpus>
