<corpus>
  <document>
    <document_id>653f01</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/air-malta-suspends-all-commercial-flights/</url>
    <title>Air Malta suspends all commercial flights</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T15:22:14+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Airline News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>Air Malta Cargo</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>covid19</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>In an effort to contain coronavirus, Malta is banning all commercial travel to country as of Saturday March 21. The ban does not apply to ferry, cargo and humanitarian and repatriation of special flights and Air Malta shall conduct these flights in line with the island government’s orders.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>f54ca1</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/record-shipment-for-wfs-new-paris-pharma-centre/</url>
    <title>Record shipment for WFS’ new Paris Pharma Centre</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T15:17:24+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Latest News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>Paris Charles de Gaulle Airport</topic>
      <topic>pharma centre</topic>
      <topic>WFS Pharma Centre</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Worldwide Flight Services’ new Pharma Centre at Paris Charles de Gaulle Airport has handled its biggest single shipment so far – 34 temperature-controlled containers for customers AirBridgeCargo Airlines and Kuehne + Nagel.</p>
      <p>The outbound shipment, which was destined for Beijing, spent 24-48 hours at the Pharma Centre where it was maintained within 2-8 degrees Celsius, before being sent to China on a Boeing 747 freighter.</p>
      <p>AirBridgeCargo has been a regular customer of WFS’ IATA CEIV certified Pharma Centre since the €10 million facility opened in the second half of 2019. To confirm compliance with its own requirements, Kuehne + Nagel also conducted its own audit of the Centre before commencing shipments.</p>
      <p>WFS’ Pharma Centre is the only dedicated facility at Paris CDG, the second largest air cargo gateway in Europe. The centre offers temperature-controlled warehousing and handling services as well as a transport fleet specifically adapted to guarantee the integrity of pharmaceutical shipments. Already, some 30 airlines and freight forwarders are using the Pharma Centre regularly to support their strict pharma product requirements, and WFS expects the operation to process over 8,000 tonnes of healthcare and life science products in 2020.</p>
      <p>Hugo Rodrigues, vice president of cargo in France at WFS, has commented that: “Our decision to invest in this state-of-the-art facility to support our airline and freight forwarder customers, as well as the pharmaceutical industry, has already been validated by the strong demand we are seeing from so many different organisations. This particular shipment for AirBridgeCargo and Kuehne + Nagel was the biggest so far and helped to demonstrate the capabilities of both the facility and our team. With the need for pharma products all over the globe likely to soar in 2020, we will deliver the capacity and quality of service our customers need to ensure the integrity and efficiency of their pharma supply chains.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>0fb979</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/delta-hits-the-pause-button/</url>
    <title>Delta hits the ‘pause button’</title>
    <author>James Graham</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:16:04+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Airline News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Covid-19</topic>
      <topic>Delta</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>In a memo to all Delta employees on Wednesday, March 18 CEO Ed Bastian outlined additional steps the company is taking to endure the COVID-19 crisis.</p>
      <p>He wrote: “First and foremost, I want to remind everyone of the importance of your health and safety. Following the national emergency that was declared by the US president, demand for travel has dropped significantly. Revenue for the month of March is now expected to decline by almost $2 billion over last year, with our projection for April falling even more. Therefore, we will continue to make significant capacity reductions with a 70% systemwide pullback planned until demand starts to recover. Our international operation will take the largest reduction, with over 80% of flying reduced over the next two to three months.”</p>
      <p>He continued: “We are having constructive discussions with the White House and Congress, and remain optimistic that our industry will receive support to help address this crisis. That said, we have to continue to take all necessary self-help measures. Cash preservation remains our top financial priority right now. Making swift decisions now to reduce the losses and preserve cash will provide us the resources to rebound from the other side of this crisis and protect Delta’s future.”</p>
      <p>The airline is deferring nearly all of its capital spending, including all new aircraft deliveries, he continued, until there is better clarity on the duration and severity of the situation.</p>
      <p>“In addition, we are looking to secure more than $4 billion in cash savings in the June quarter alone. This will include capacity-related savings as we suspend flying.</p>
      <p>“All Delta officers will take a 50% pay cut through June 30, with directors and managing directors taking a 25% cut during that same period,” he wrote</p>
      <p>He continued: “I’ve cut my own salary by 100% through the next six months. We are reducing our active fleet size by parking at least half of our fleet – more than 600 aircraft. We also will be accelerating retirements of older aircraft like our MD-88/90s and some of our 767s.</p>
      <p>“As we draw down our operation, I know how painful it is to essentially hit the “pause button” on so many things that are core to what we do for our customers and our mission to connect the world. But what will never stop is the spirit of the Delta people, which is shining through brighter than ever even in this dark moment.</p>
      <p>“Make no mistake – we will get through this. This is a temporary health crisis and an end will, hopefully soon, be in sight.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>74c0c1</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/turkish-cargo-increases-freighter-flights/</url>
    <title>Turkish Cargo increases freighter flights</title>
    <author>James Graham</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T12:13:31+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Airline News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Turkish Airlines</topic>
      <topic>Turkish Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Turkish Cargo is increasing the frequencies of its freighter flights for the purpose of avoiding any loss of capacity resulting from the contingency bringing about the effects that are experienced intensely on global basis (COVID-19),</p>
      <p>The carrier will start to make use of the aircraft available in its fleet, in addition to its current cargo freighter capacity, which was increased to 25 from 13 during the last four years.</p>
      <p>Turkish Cargo supports all of the efforts made by the International Air Transport Association (IATA) for fighting against the corona virus globally.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>f24354</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/ups-enhances-singapore-healthcare-supply-chain-capabilities/</url>
    <title>UPS enhances Singapore healthcare supply chain capabilities</title>
    <author>James Graham</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T10:45:52+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Asia News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>CEIV Pharma certificate</topic>
      <topic>IATA</topic>
      <topic>Singapore</topic>
      <topic>UPS</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>UPS’s freight forwarding operation at Changi Airport, Singapore has received IATA CEIV Pharma Certification for pharmaceutical logistics. The certification is the first for UPS in Asia Pacific and strengthens the value proposition of UPS’s healthcare logistics offering in the region. It is a further validation of its capabilities in the safe, secure and efficient transportation of high-value pharmaceutical products.</p>
      <p>IATA’s CEIV Pharma Certification is an industry certification developed by IATA, regulators and aviation industry stakeholders. It evaluates companies on a comprehensive range of criteria including quality management systems, facilities, equipment, operations and staff expertise.</p>
      <p>“Pharmaceuticals are time and temperature-sensitive, requiring an extra amount of care throughout the transportation process. These are not typical packages, and at times life-saving deliveries as well. This certification is an affirmation of the high standards of handling and transportation that UPS’s customers in the healthcare and life sciences sector have come to rely on for their high-value shipments,” said Lim Bee Koong, director, Healthcare Strategy, UPS Asia Pacific.</p>
      <p>“Our continual upgrades and technology investments give us a high degree of visibility over the healthcare supply chain. It’s this customer-first focus that has helped pave the way for our IATA CEIV Pharma Certification.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>c8c7f0</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/airports-urge-governments-to-rethink-flight-bans/</url>
    <title>Airports urge governments to rethink flight bans</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T16:15:42+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Association News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>Airport Council International</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>The Airport Council International (ACI) has voiced concerns over the effectiveness of imposing travel bans. “While the EU balks at the imposition of a transatlantic travel ban by the US, an increasing number of EU countries are imposing their own unilateral restrictions to air connectivity within Europe. Besides further damaging European aviation and worsening the economic fallout of COVID-19, the fact that these measures do not appear aligned with WHO recommendations raises serious doubts as to their effectiveness,” Olivier Jankovec, director general of ACI Europe has said.</p>
      <p>The WHO continues to advise against travel restrictions to countries experiencing COVID-19 outbreaks, stating that “in general, evidence shows that restricting the (international) movement of people during public health emergencies is ineffective in most situations”.</p>
      <p>The WHO recognises that restrictions on international air travel can be justified at the beginning of an outbreak, to prevent or at best delay imported cases from other countries. But once local transmission occurs, these restrictions no longer serve their purpose. The fact that Italy was the first European country to ban all flights to China but still became the European epicentre of the COVID-19 epidemic is a case in point.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>27d22b</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/virgin-atlantic-takes-drastic-action-to-safeguard-survival/</url>
    <title>Virgin Atlantic takes drastic action to safeguard survival</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T16:05:16+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Airline News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>Virgin Atlantic</topic>
      <topic>Virgin Atlantic Airlines</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>From March 17, Virgin Atlantic has taken drastic measures to safeguard themselves. This will include an 80% reduction in schedule to prioritise core routes based on customer demand. Approximately 75% of Virgin’s fleet will be grounded by March 26, which may increase to 85% at points in April.</p>
      <p>Staff will be asked to take eight weeks unpaid leave over the next three months, with the cost spread over six months’ salary, to drastically reduce costs without job losses. Virgin will also offer a one-time voluntary severance package to all employees or a sabbatical of 6-12 months. Other measures to reduce costs include deferring annual pay increases until review in January 2021, reducing employer pension contribution for one year and CEO Shai Weiss reducing his pay by 20%, with the executive leadership team following with a 15% pay reduction until the end of 2020.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>138cb8</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/air-partner-encourages-advance-freight-arrangements/</url>
    <title>Air Partner encourages advance freight arrangements</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T15:57:26+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Coronavirus</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>Air Partner</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Amongst uncertainty around COVID-19, Air Partner is imploring companies to book air cargo transport in advance to secure availability and keep their supply chains moving.“We’re seeing a spike in air freight service requests as many commercial flights are being grounded and at a time when Chinese industrial production is restarting after a month-long shutdown. There is still immediate charter availability, but we foresee that could change in the coming weeks,” Mark Briffa, CEO of Air Partner has said.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>6a2157</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/cacc-cargolinx-egyptian-operations-as-normal/</url>
    <title>CACC Cargolinx’ Egyptian operations as normal</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T15:53:50+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Coronavirus</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>cargolinx</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Egypt</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Despite Egyptian Airports halting air traffic until March 31, all CACC Cargolinx’ terminals will be operating and all services and activities will be carried out normally. Cargo freighters will not be affected by the travel restrictions.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>c47df4</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/delta-cargo-launches-charter-operation/</url>
    <title>Delta Cargo launches charter operation</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-17T15:46:20+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Airline News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>Delta Air Lines Cargo</topic>
      <topic>Delta Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Delta Cargo is launching charter operations to satisfy demand from corporate customers who need reliable transportation services in this time of uncertainty. The following 13 US airports are participating in the programme, as well as over 70 available international destination airports: JFK, Chicago O’Hare International Airport, San Francisco International Airport, Seattle-Tacoma International Airport, Daniel K. Inouye International Airport, Los Angeles International Airport, Hartsfield-Jackson Atlanta International Airport, Washington-Dulles International Airport, Newark Liberty International Airport, Dallas/Fort Worth International Airport, Detroit Metropolitan Airport, Boston Logan International Airport, and Miami International Airport.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
</corpus>
