<corpus>
  <document>
    <document_id>1448a7</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/farnborough-international-airshow-2020-cancelled/</url>
    <title>Farnborough International Airshow 2020 cancelled</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T15:17:36+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Coronavirus</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>Farnborough Air Show</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Farnborough International Airshow 2020, that was due to take place in July, has been cancelled.</p>
      <p>A statement from the air show comments: “After very careful consideration, the unprecedented impact of the global Coronavirus pandemic has forced this decision in the interests of the health and safety of our exhibitors, visitors, contractors and staff. This decision was reached taking into consideration several major factors surrounding the outbreak of COVID-19, all of which we have concluded, make it is impossible for us to create and host the Airshow this July.”</p>
      <p>The show is planning to return in 2022.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>981038</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/postponed-smart-airports-conference-exhibition/</url>
    <title>Postponed: SMART Airports Conference &amp; Exhibition</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T15:09:36+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Coronavirus</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>air cargo</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>San Antonio</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>In light of the current situation, San Antonio International Airport has taken the decision to postpone the upcoming SMART Airports Conference &amp; Exhibition, that was due to take place in San Antonio, Texas in April.</p>
      <p>Following this it has been announced that the event will be rescheduled and take place Monday 2 to Wednesday 4 November 2020. By November, Jesus H. Saenz, director or airports at San Antonio Airport System (SAAS), notes: “we will be celebrating as we will have concluded our SAAS development plan, charting the path forward for the next 20+ of growth.” Finding the silver lining in the situation, Saenz also adds, “November is a great time to visit our beautiful and vibrant city!”</p>
      <p>“The 2020 SMART Airports and Regions Conference will provide you with a unique opportunity to learn from a host of specialised presenters on innovative strategies in airport design, construction and development, commercial development, real estate and non-aeronautical revenue, customer service excellence and community engagement. We’re looking forward to sharing our vision with you and sharing some of our world-famous warm and welcoming San Antonio hospitality,” said Saenz.</p>
      <p>The November conference is expected to attract over 500 airport industry leader, represent over 50 countries and host over 90 airport/industry expert speakers.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>96af08</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/online-management-platform-for-forwarders-launched/</url>
    <title>Online management platform for forwarders launched</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T15:45:12+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>IT News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>Cargoguide</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Cargoguide has officially unveiled its new online management platform, which aims to increase transparency and efficiency in the freight forwarding sector. The new Cargoguide enables forwarders to compare accurate air freight rates including surcharges, create better rate calculations, create and send custom quotes and also track and manage sales opportunities.</p>
      <p>“We believe the freight forwarding process should be transparent, neutral and conducted within a fair market. Cargoguide is the next step in helping make that a reality,” commented Bas van der Putten, Cargoguide’s growth manager.</p>
      <p>“This is an exciting time for us and for digital technology in the wider freight forwarding sector. It is however a challenging time for many freight forwarders and carriers, as they look to meet the demands of modern customers while remaining competitive.</p>
      <p>“That’s where Cargoguide can add real value. We understand that forwarders and carriers need a platform that connects them through rates and that is continuously innovating and growing with them.  The transparent rate calculations and accuracy of Cargoguide’s data is unique and truly sets us apart from other platforms.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>82a52d</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/heidi-capozzi-to-leave-boeing-as-livingston-steps-up/</url>
    <title>Heidi Capozzi to leave Boeing as Livingston steps up</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T15:38:26+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Boeing News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>Boeing</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Boeing has announced that Heidi Capozzi, senior vice president of human resources will leave the company in early April to pursue another opportunity.Capozzi joined Boeing in 2009 and since 2016 has led the company’s leadership and learning, talent planning, employee and labour relations, total rewards, and diversity and inclusion initiatives.</p>
      <p>“For more than a decade, Heidi has demonstrated a deep commitment to engaging and inspiring our people, strengthening our culture and supporting our business,” said Boeing president and CEO David Calhoun. “During this time, she also built a world-class Human Resources team and helped elevate Boeing as an employer of choice, globally. We owe Heidi sincere gratitude for all she has accomplished, and we wish her well as she pursues a new opportunity.”</p>
      <p>Following an orderly transition, Wendy Livingston, currently vice president of corporate human resources, will replace Capozzi on an interim basis until a permanent successor is named.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>236e23</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/tiaca-calls-for-recognition-of-air-cargo-in-the-fight-against-covid-19/</url>
    <title>TIACA calls for recognition of air cargo in the fight against COVID-19</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T15:25:49+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Association News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>ICAO</topic>
      <topic>TIACA</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>TIACA has joined the “ICAO Technical group on joint actions related to COVID-19,” along with other bodies including WHO, IATA, ACI and GEA. TIACA aims at highlighting the important role that the air cargo industry plays in this unprecedented crisis and stresses that the industry’s voice must be heard by regulators and governments.</p>
      <p>In the current major crisis, airfreight is essential for the transport of food, basic necessities and health-related products. The global economy also needs air freight to continue to supply businesses and factories. TIACA has described that in the current situation multiple financial issues have emerged. This includes, leasing payments for expensive aircraft, salaries, energy supplies, and payments to service providers and equipment providers, taxation, as well as difficulties arising from uncoordinated travel bans, restrictions imposed on crew movements, airport slots and route changes, and so on.</p>
      <p>“TIACA sees its role in the ICAO Technical Group as using ICAO’s mechanism to reach out to governments and remind them that air cargo is a significant contributor to the global economy and international trade, and that it plays a very important role in preventing and battling the disastrous effect of coronavirus,” Vladimir Zubkov, TIACA secretary general, has commented.</p>
      <p>TIACA has also urged governments to exempt the movement of cargo from any bans. “We support IATA’s appeal to have air cargo recognized as vital in the fight against COVID-19 and for action to be taken – in particular, removing all travel restrictions on air cargo operations and taking all necessary measures to allow air cargo to continue to circulate around the world,” said Steven Polmans, chairman of TIACA.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>653f01</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/air-malta-suspends-all-commercial-flights/</url>
    <title>Air Malta suspends all commercial flights</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T15:22:14+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Airline News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>Air Malta Cargo</topic>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>covid19</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>In an effort to contain coronavirus, Malta is banning all commercial travel to country as of Saturday March 21. The ban does not apply to ferry, cargo and humanitarian and repatriation of special flights and Air Malta shall conduct these flights in line with the island government’s orders.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>f54ca1</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/record-shipment-for-wfs-new-paris-pharma-centre/</url>
    <title>Record shipment for WFS’ new Paris Pharma Centre</title>
    <author>Yasmin Turner</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T15:17:24+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Latest News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week</topic>
      <topic>Air Cargo Week (ACW)</topic>
      <topic>Paris Charles de Gaulle Airport</topic>
      <topic>pharma centre</topic>
      <topic>WFS Pharma Centre</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Worldwide Flight Services’ new Pharma Centre at Paris Charles de Gaulle Airport has handled its biggest single shipment so far – 34 temperature-controlled containers for customers AirBridgeCargo Airlines and Kuehne + Nagel.</p>
      <p>The outbound shipment, which was destined for Beijing, spent 24-48 hours at the Pharma Centre where it was maintained within 2-8 degrees Celsius, before being sent to China on a Boeing 747 freighter.</p>
      <p>AirBridgeCargo has been a regular customer of WFS’ IATA CEIV certified Pharma Centre since the €10 million facility opened in the second half of 2019. To confirm compliance with its own requirements, Kuehne + Nagel also conducted its own audit of the Centre before commencing shipments.</p>
      <p>WFS’ Pharma Centre is the only dedicated facility at Paris CDG, the second largest air cargo gateway in Europe. The centre offers temperature-controlled warehousing and handling services as well as a transport fleet specifically adapted to guarantee the integrity of pharmaceutical shipments. Already, some 30 airlines and freight forwarders are using the Pharma Centre regularly to support their strict pharma product requirements, and WFS expects the operation to process over 8,000 tonnes of healthcare and life science products in 2020.</p>
      <p>Hugo Rodrigues, vice president of cargo in France at WFS, has commented that: “Our decision to invest in this state-of-the-art facility to support our airline and freight forwarder customers, as well as the pharmaceutical industry, has already been validated by the strong demand we are seeing from so many different organisations. This particular shipment for AirBridgeCargo and Kuehne + Nagel was the biggest so far and helped to demonstrate the capabilities of both the facility and our team. With the need for pharma products all over the globe likely to soar in 2020, we will deliver the capacity and quality of service our customers need to ensure the integrity and efficiency of their pharma supply chains.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>0fb979</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/delta-hits-the-pause-button/</url>
    <title>Delta hits the ‘pause button’</title>
    <author>James Graham</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T14:16:04+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Airline News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Covid-19</topic>
      <topic>Delta</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>In a memo to all Delta employees on Wednesday, March 18 CEO Ed Bastian outlined additional steps the company is taking to endure the COVID-19 crisis.</p>
      <p>He wrote: “First and foremost, I want to remind everyone of the importance of your health and safety. Following the national emergency that was declared by the US president, demand for travel has dropped significantly. Revenue for the month of March is now expected to decline by almost $2 billion over last year, with our projection for April falling even more. Therefore, we will continue to make significant capacity reductions with a 70% systemwide pullback planned until demand starts to recover. Our international operation will take the largest reduction, with over 80% of flying reduced over the next two to three months.”</p>
      <p>He continued: “We are having constructive discussions with the White House and Congress, and remain optimistic that our industry will receive support to help address this crisis. That said, we have to continue to take all necessary self-help measures. Cash preservation remains our top financial priority right now. Making swift decisions now to reduce the losses and preserve cash will provide us the resources to rebound from the other side of this crisis and protect Delta’s future.”</p>
      <p>The airline is deferring nearly all of its capital spending, including all new aircraft deliveries, he continued, until there is better clarity on the duration and severity of the situation.</p>
      <p>“In addition, we are looking to secure more than $4 billion in cash savings in the June quarter alone. This will include capacity-related savings as we suspend flying.</p>
      <p>“All Delta officers will take a 50% pay cut through June 30, with directors and managing directors taking a 25% cut during that same period,” he wrote</p>
      <p>He continued: “I’ve cut my own salary by 100% through the next six months. We are reducing our active fleet size by parking at least half of our fleet – more than 600 aircraft. We also will be accelerating retirements of older aircraft like our MD-88/90s and some of our 767s.</p>
      <p>“As we draw down our operation, I know how painful it is to essentially hit the “pause button” on so many things that are core to what we do for our customers and our mission to connect the world. But what will never stop is the spirit of the Delta people, which is shining through brighter than ever even in this dark moment.</p>
      <p>“Make no mistake – we will get through this. This is a temporary health crisis and an end will, hopefully soon, be in sight.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>74c0c1</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/turkish-cargo-increases-freighter-flights/</url>
    <title>Turkish Cargo increases freighter flights</title>
    <author>James Graham</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T12:13:31+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Airline News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>coronavirus</topic>
      <topic>Turkish Airlines</topic>
      <topic>Turkish Cargo</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Turkish Cargo is increasing the frequencies of its freighter flights for the purpose of avoiding any loss of capacity resulting from the contingency bringing about the effects that are experienced intensely on global basis (COVID-19),</p>
      <p>The carrier will start to make use of the aircraft available in its fleet, in addition to its current cargo freighter capacity, which was increased to 25 from 13 during the last four years.</p>
      <p>Turkish Cargo supports all of the efforts made by the International Air Transport Association (IATA) for fighting against the corona virus globally.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>f24354</document_id>
    <url>https://www.aircargoweek.com/ups-enhances-singapore-healthcare-supply-chain-capabilities/</url>
    <title>UPS enhances Singapore healthcare supply chain capabilities</title>
    <author>James Graham</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T10:45:52+00:00</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Asia News</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>CEIV Pharma certificate</topic>
      <topic>IATA</topic>
      <topic>Singapore</topic>
      <topic>UPS</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>UPS’s freight forwarding operation at Changi Airport, Singapore has received IATA CEIV Pharma Certification for pharmaceutical logistics. The certification is the first for UPS in Asia Pacific and strengthens the value proposition of UPS’s healthcare logistics offering in the region. It is a further validation of its capabilities in the safe, secure and efficient transportation of high-value pharmaceutical products.</p>
      <p>IATA’s CEIV Pharma Certification is an industry certification developed by IATA, regulators and aviation industry stakeholders. It evaluates companies on a comprehensive range of criteria including quality management systems, facilities, equipment, operations and staff expertise.</p>
      <p>“Pharmaceuticals are time and temperature-sensitive, requiring an extra amount of care throughout the transportation process. These are not typical packages, and at times life-saving deliveries as well. This certification is an affirmation of the high standards of handling and transportation that UPS’s customers in the healthcare and life sciences sector have come to rely on for their high-value shipments,” said Lim Bee Koong, director, Healthcare Strategy, UPS Asia Pacific.</p>
      <p>“Our continual upgrades and technology investments give us a high degree of visibility over the healthcare supply chain. It’s this customer-first focus that has helped pave the way for our IATA CEIV Pharma Certification.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
</corpus>
