<corpus>
  <document>
    <document_id>c68eaa</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/aei-signs-freighter-conversion-deal-with-nauru-airlines-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>AEI signs freighter conversion deal with Nauru Airlines</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T13:58:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>c525a9</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/cathay-pacific-group-to-launch-terminal-charge-concession-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>Cathay Pacific Group to launch terminal charge concession</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T14:14:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>065b72</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/envirotainer-airbridgecargo-kuehnenagel-partner-to-deliver-medical-supplies-from-italy-to-china-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>Envirotainer, AirBridgeCargo, Kuehne+Nagel partner to deliver medical supplies from Italy to China</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T11:16:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Envirotainer, a cool chain solutions provider for airfreight, AirBridgeCargo (ABC) and logistics partner Kuehne + Nagel joined hands to deliver a huge consignment of medicines from Italy to China for a global pharmaceutical company.  The shipment was to be sent from their production facility in Italy to their distribution center in China.</p>
      <p>One of the key challenges for this particular shipment of medicines was the share volume that needed to be shipped at one single time. Thanks to good dialogues between all involved parties, the 27 RKN e1 active containers were loaded in AirBridgeCargo’s freighter in less than one hour and safely on their way to China before any changes in weather could interfere with flight schedules.</p>
      <p>“One key success factor to make this happen was the choice to use Envirotainer’s active temperature-controlled units, the RKN e1 in this case. As these units are Unit Load Devices (ULD), they fit snuggly into the airplane and utilizes space extremely efficiently,” explains Claudio Caccia, strategic account manager at Envirotainer. He continues, “If you would have tried to ship the same volume of medicines in a passive solution, it would have required something like another 2-3 Boeing 747 to fit it all because of all the insulation taking up space.”</p>
      <p>“We are proud to be given this opportunity to demonstrate the quality of the pharma solutions we can provide together with our global partner – Envirotainer. And of course, we are also proud to have earned the trust of our customer for the organization of vaccines transportation. This is the latest demonstration of AirBridgeCargo’s and Envirotainer’s commitment to provide the best possible solution for customers requiring high quality pharma logistics,” highlighted Yulia Celetaria, global director, Pharma for AirBridgeCargo Airlines.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>b6bad2</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/american-airlines-use-grounded-passenger-planes-to-move-cargo-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>American Airlines use grounded passenger planes to move cargo</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-20T10:35:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>American Airlines is utilising its currently grounded passenger aircraft to move cargo between the United States and Europe, ensuring the world’s goods continue to get where they need to go.</p>
      <p>The first cargo-only flight departs from Dallas Fort Worth International Airport (DFW) tomorrow, March 20, landing at Frankfurt Airport (FRA) March 21. The Boeing 777-300 will operate two round trips between DFW and FRA over the course of four days, carrying only cargo and necessary flight personnel. This is the first scheduled cargo-only flight since 1984 when American retired the last of its Boeing 747 freighters.</p>
      <p>The 777-300 has 14 cargo positions for large pallets and can carry more than 100,000 pounds. The four scheduled flights this weekend are expected to be booked to capacity and transport medical supplies, mail for active US military, telecommunications equipment and electronics that will support people working from home, and e-commerce packages. The flights provide much-needed cargo capacity for many of the airline’s regular cargo customers, allowing them to continue operating in this challenging environment.</p>
      <p>Air cargo has always played a key role in times of crisis, delivering lifesaving medical supplies and materials to keep the world’s infrastructure intact. In the face of the coronavirus (COVID-19) outbreak, this role has never been more important as the world relies more on e-commerce to support basic needs during quarantines and social distancing. The airlines’ role is deemed a critical infrastructure industry by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).</p>
      <p>“We have a critical role to play in keeping essential goods moving during this unprecedented time, and we are proud to do our part and find ways to continue to serve our customers and our communities,” said Rick Elieson, President of Cargo and Vice President of International Operations. “Challenging times call for creative solutions, and a team of people across the airline has been working nonstop to arrange cargo-only flight options for our customers.”</p>
      <p>Cargo-only flights, while not carrying customers, continue to require a group effort from American’s team members across every function. From the first call to a customer to the last cargo offloaded from the plane, team members and vendor partners contribute to these efforts.</p>
      <p>“It’s an honor to be part of these cargo-only flights,” said Ken Jarrell, fleet service clerk, Cargo Services – DFW. “They represent much needed aid for the world and hope for our team. Our team members across the airline are ready and willing to do what it takes to make sure people have the things they need during these unprecedented times.”</p>
      <p>Domestically, American continues to carry cargo on all of its planes. The smaller narrowbody aircraft are especially vital in supporting the world’s economy, delivering medicine and e-commerce goods. This week the airline also transported its first shipment of COVID-19 test kits from Raleigh-Durham International Airport to Chicago O’Hare Airport. American continues to work to provide solutions for our customers and world governments to protect the public health and keep the global economy moving during this time of need.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>c60d89</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/tiaca-joins-iatas-appeal-to-have-air-cargo-recognized-as-vital-in-the-fight-against-covid19/</url>
    <title>TIACA joins IATA’s appeal to have air cargo recognized as vital in the fight against Covid-19</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T20:39:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>06c428</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/covid19-turkish-cargo-to-push-all-its-freighters-at-full-capacity-to-meet-global-trade-demands-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>Covid-19: Turkish Cargo to push all its freighters at full capacity to meet global trade demands</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T17:43:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content/>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>22bab3</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/lufthansa-group-may-use-passenger-aircraft-as-pure-cargo-aircraft-to-further-increase-cargo-capacity-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>Lufthansa Group may use passenger aircraft as pure cargo aircraft to further increase cargo capacity</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T16:14:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Lufthansa Group has warned that the spread of Covid-19 is leading to an unpredictable situation with drastic reduction in capacity and the longer this crisis lasts, the more likely it is that “the future of aviation cannot be guaranteed without state aid.” However, the freight arm Lufthansa Cargo continues to fly its regular programme, except for mainland China, which means that its entire freighter fleet of seven Boeing 777Fs, six MD-11Fs and four 777Fs at AeroLogic will still remain in the air.</p>
      <p>Carsten Spohr, chairman of the executive board of Deutsche Lufthansa AG, said, “The spread of the coronavirus has placed the entire global economy and our company as well in an unprecedented state of emergency. At present, no one can foresee the consequences. We have to counter this extraordinary situation with drastic and sometimes painful measures. At the same time, we must live up to the special responsibility that airlines bear in their home countries. We are doing everything we can to bring as many passengers as possible home on relief flights.”</p>
      <p>Spohr, however, stressed that the airline is doing its best to ensure that supply chains for many thousands of businesses do not break down by mobilising additional capacity for air freight transport. “The longer this crisis lasts, the more likely it is that the future of aviation cannot be guaranteed without state aid. In view of the massive impact of the corona crisis, today's publication of our results for the past financial year is unfortunately sidelined,” he added.</p>
      <p>At 2 billion euros, the Lufthansa Group reported that the adjusted EBIT was in line with the forecast despite considerable charges. The main drivers for the decline were a 600 million euro increase in fuel costs and a noticeable economic slowdown, especially in the Group's home markets. Earnings development was also impacted by high price pressure in the European market due to overcapacity and the weakening of the global airfreight market. Lufthansa Group revenue in 2019 rose by 2.5 per cent to 36.4 billion euros (previous year: 35.5 billion euros). The adjusted EBIT margin was 5.6 per cent (previous year: 8.0 per cent). Consolidated net profit fell by 44 per cent to 1.2 billion euros (previous year: 2.2 billion euros).</p>
      <p>Unit revenues of the passenger airlines in the Group fell by 2.5 per cent in 2019, adjusted for exchange rate effects, in particular due to the overcapacity in the Lufthansa Group's home markets. At the same time, unit costs adjusted for fuel and currency effects were reduced by 1.5 per cent in 2019, the fourth year in succession.</p>
      <p>In 2019, the Lufthansa Group invested 3.6 billion euros (previous year: 3.8 billion euros), a large part of which in new aircraft. Adjusted free cash flow fell to 203 million euros (previous year: 288 million euros) due to lower profits and higher tax payments. Return on capital employed (adjusted ROCE) after taxes decreased to 6.6 percent (prior year: 10.8 percent).</p>
      <p>At year-end, interest-bearing net liabilities amounted to 4.3 billion euros. Including lease liabilities of 2.4 billion euros recognized for the first time as a result of the application of IFRS 16, net debt thus amounted to around 6.7 billion euros (prior year: 3.5 billion euros). Pension liabilities rose by 14 percent to 6.7 billion euros (previous year: 5.9 billion euros), mainly due to the lower interest rate used to discount pension obligations, which fell to 1.4 percent (previous year: 2.0 percent).</p>
      <p>In order to secure its strong financial position, the Lufthansa Group has raised additional funds of around 600 million euros in recent weeks. In actuarial terms, the Group thus has liquidity of around 4.3 billion euros. In addition, there are unused credit lines of around 800 million euros. Further funds are currently being raised. Among other things, the Lufthansa Group will use aircraft financing for this purpose.</p>
      <p>“The Lufthansa Group is financially well equipped to cope with an extraordinary crisis situation such as the current one. We own 86 per cent of the Group's fleet, which is largely unencumbered and has a book value of around 10 billion euros. In addition, we have decided to propose to the Annual General Meeting that the dividend payment be suspended, and we are proposing short-time working in our home markets,” said Ulrik Svensson, chief financial officer of Deutsche Lufthansa AG.</p>
      <p>The Lufthansa Executive Board has also decided to waive 20 per cent of its basic remuneration in 2020.</p>
      <p>Corona crisis: Drastic cuts in Lufthansa Group flight operations / numerous special relief flights planned and carried out</p>
      <p>Due to entry restrictions in many countries and a collapse in demand, the Lufthansa Group was forced to make drastic cutbacks in its flight operations. Air Dolomiti conducted its last flight for the time being on March 18. The last regular scheduled flight of Austrian Airlines landed in Vienna today. With the exception of special flights, Austrian Airlines is suspending its flight operations until March 28. Brussels Airlines will not be offering any regular flights in the period from March 21 to April 19.</p>
      <p>Lufthansa is discontinuing its long-haul operations in Munich and will initially only offer long-haul flights from Frankfurt. SWISS will offer only three weekly long-haul flights a week to Newark (USA) in addition to a substantially reduced short- and medium-haul schedule. Lufthansa’s short-haul program will also be substantially reduced further, and only Lufthansa CityLine services will be operated from Munich. From the hubs in Frankfurt, Munich and Zurich, only a few European metropolitan areas will be served. The relief flight schedule runs until April 19 and only provides for a total of about five percent of the originally planned program. Around 700 of the Lufthansa Group's 763 aircraft will be temporarily parked.</p>
      <p>In order to bring as many people as possible back home quickly, Lufthansa Group airlines are also operating numerous special relief flights around the world. This is also possible due to the unparalleled support and solidarity of the crews as well as ground staff, who at a moment’s notice volunteered their assistance.</p>
      <p>In close consultation with the governments of their home countries and on behalf of tour operators, Lufthansa Group airlines are currently offering around 140 special relief flights. More than 20,000 passengers are thus flying home with Lufthansa, Eurowings, SWISS, Austrian Airlines, Brussels Airlines and Edelweiss. The figures alone include the special flights that were firmly planned until yesterday. Numerous other special flights will follow in the next few days.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>ed3c16</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/jack-ma-foundation-alibaba-foundation-fly-medical-supplies-to-us-africa-spain-slovenia-and-france-in-fight-against-covid-19-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>Jack Ma Foundation, Alibaba Foundation fly medical supplies to US, Africa, Spain, Slovenia and France in fight against Covid-19</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T13:59:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>In its ongoing efforts to contain the spread of Covid-19 and provide aid to afflicted communities across the globe, the Jack Ma Foundation and Alibaba Foundation have committed to sending medical supplies, including masks and test kits, to the US, Africa, Spain, Slovenia and France.</p>
      <p>On his personal Twitter page, Alibaba Group founder Jack Ma stressed the importance of staying one step ahead as the effects of the coronavirus pandemic continue to ripple across the globe.</p>
      <p>The foundations sent 500,000 test kits and one million masks to the US and were received by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, in Spain, with the support of King Felipe VI and the Spanish Ministry of Health, Consumer Affairs and Social Welfare, the foundations were able to deliver an initial batch of 500,000 masks from Shanghai to Zaragoza Airport. Additional supplies are due to arrive in Spain over the next few days.</p>
      <p>On March 18, another cargo plane carrying medical masks departed from Hangzhou and arrived at Liege Airport. A portion of these donated supplies will go to frontline medical staff in Belgium. Also on the chartered flight were masks for Slovenia and France. According to the foundations, Slovenia’s Department of Defense and France’s Ministère des Affaires sociales et de la Santé provided crucial support in the delivery of these supplies.</p>
      <p>Another day, another flight! One more plane carrying 1.5 million masks has landed in Liege Airport, Belgium. These supplies will be delivered to France, Slovenia and Belgium. More supplies will be delivered to Liege! COVID-19 is still spreading. We need to be faster! pic.twitter.com/Msd7KYAdUd— Jack Ma Foundation (@foundation_ma) March 18, 2020</p>
      <p>The foundations have also committed to donating 100,000 medical masks, 20,000 test kits and 1,000 protective suits to each of the 54 nations on the African continent. The medical supplies donated by the Jack Ma Foundation and Alibaba Foundation will be delivered to Addis Ababa, the capital of Ethiopia, where Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed Ali has agreed to take the lead in overseeing their distribution to other African countries. The foundations also announced plans to provide online training materials to help medical institutions in Africa cope with coronavirus cases.</p>
      <p>Earlier this month, the Jack Ma Foundation and Alibaba Foundation jointly donated surgical masks to Japan and South Korea. The foundations have also sent test kits and masks to European countries, including Italy and Belgium.</p>
      <p>The foundations have also provided funding to establishments such as the Peter Doherty Institute for Infection and Immunity in Australia and Columbia University in the US to support research into coronavirus vaccines and treatment.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>a676aa</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/damco-works-towards-trimming-carbon-footprint-with-new-energy-efficient-warehouse-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>DAMCO works towards trimming carbon footprint with new energy-efficient warehouse</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T11:11:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>DAMCO has moved into a new 36,000 sq ft energy-efficient warehouse at London’s Heathrow Airport as part of ongoing investment in its airfreight offering.</p>
      <p>The freight forwarder has moved its airfreight operations into offices at the North Feltham Trading Estate, within three miles of Heathrow’s cargo terminal, to support a growing customer base of leading UK retailers.</p>
      <p>The bonded facility’s environmental credentials include a Building Research Establishment Environmental Assessment Method (BREEAM) rating of Excellent and a Grade A Energy Performance Certificate (EPC).</p>
      <p>“We are working with our clients closely to help reduce their CO2 footprint,” said Anthony Akerman, managing director, UK and Ireland, DAMCO.</p>
      <p>“Their focus on a triple bottom line to satisfy the goals of finance, environment, and ethical and social drivers to create sustainability means we need to remain creative in our approach.</p>
      <p>“By utilising our new facility, we will help to reduce CO2 on air shipments by consolidating clients’ cargo at origin in order to book on direct flights rather than use transhipment hubs.</p>
      <p>“This  allows us to kill volumes on the shipments, providing similar non-direct pricing for cargo that actually flies on a direct flight, reducing the CO2 footprint.</p>
      <p>“By choosing a new build, we were able to ensure a more energy-efficient facility, benefitting from solar power on the roof and electrical charging points for our vehicles, and we have invested in recycled office furniture.”</p>
      <p>The new facility, which is open seven days a week, is located at SEGRO Central Spacewaye in the North Feltham Trading Estate.</p>
      <p>“With its prime location close to Heathrow Airport, excellent road connections and quality of workspace, Central Spacewaye provides a compelling proposition to occupiers, particularly those committed to a robust sustainability agenda,” said Alan Holland, Business Unit Director, Greater London, SEGRO.</p>
      <p>DAMCO, which is a UK Civil Aviation (CAA) Regulated Agent, has invested in the new facility as part of ongoing global growth and development underpinned by its Business Resilience and its Digitalisation Programmes.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>74dcf8</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/wfs-new-paris-pharma-centre-handles-record-shipment-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>WFS' new Paris pharma centre handles record shipment</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-19T10:33:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Worldwide Flight Services’ (WFS) new Pharma Centre at Paris Charles de Gaulle Airport has handled its biggest single shipment so far of 34 temperature-controlled containers for customers AirBridgeCargo Airlines and Kuehne + Nagel.</p>
      <p>Maintained within a +2-8 degrees Celsius temperature environment, the outbound shipment to Beijing spent 24-48 hours in the Pharma Centre in preparation for its delivery to China onboard one of AirBridgeCargo’s Boeing 747 freighters.</p>
      <p>AirBridgeCargo has been a regular customer of WFS’ IATA CEIV certified Pharma Centre since the €10 million facility opened in the second half of 2019. To confirm compliance with its own requirements, Kuehne + Nagel also conducted its own audit of the Centre before commencing shipments.</p>
      <p>WFS’ Pharma Centre is the only dedicated facility at Paris CDG – the second largest air cargo gateway in Europe. With a team of highly-trained and dedicated pharma handling experts, the Centre offers temperature-controlled warehousing and handling services as well as a transport fleet specifically adapted to guarantee the integrity of pharmaceutical shipments. Already, some 30 airlines and freight forwarders are using the Pharma Centre regularly to support their strict pharma product requirements, and WFS expects the operation to process over 8,000 tonnes of healthcare and life science products in 2020.</p>
      <p>Hugo Rodrigues, vice president Cargo France at WFS, said, “Our decision to invest in this state-of-the-art facility to support our airline and freight forwarder customers, as well as the pharmaceutical industry, has already been validated by the strong demand we are seeing from so many different organisations. This particular shipment for AirBridgeCargo and Kuehne + Nagel was the biggest so far and helped to demonstrate the capabilities of both the facility and our team. With the need for pharma products all over the globe likely to soar in 2020, we will deliver the capacity and quality of service our customers need to ensure the integrity and efficiency of their pharma supply chains.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>da3783</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/cathay-pacific-group-sees-7-fall-in-cargo-and-mail-figures-in-february-posts-hk2-bn-overall-loss-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>Cathay Pacific Group sees 7% fall in cargo and mail figures in February; posts HK$2 bn overall loss</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T16:14:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>The Cathay Pacific Group reported a significant hit in its cargo, mail and passenger figures for February 2020 from the coronavirus outbreak. The group posted an overall unaudited loss of HK$2 billion for the month.</p>
      <p>The two airlines (Cathay Pacific and Cathay Dragon) carried 118,711 tonnes of cargo and mail last month, or 698,019,000 revenue freight tonne kilometres (RFTKs) – a decrease of 6.9 percent compared to the same month last year. The cargo and mail load factor increased by 5.8 percentage points to 66.6 percent, while capacity, measured in available freight tonne kilometres (AFTKs), was down by 15.1 percent.</p>
      <p>Cathay Pacific, group chief customer and commercial officer, Ronald Lam said, “We are facing an unprecedented challenge as the COVID-19 pandemic continues to cause widespread disruption to our operation and business. In February alone, we made a significant unaudited loss of more than HK$2 billion at the full-service airline level (Cathay Pacific and Cathay Dragon).”</p>
      <p>“The situation has further deteriorated since February. We have already announced around 65 percent passenger flight capacity reduction for March. Governments around the world have since introduced more travel restrictions, with the most recent ones starting to affect our major long-haul markets including Europe, the United States and Southwest Pacific. Given the expected further drop in travel demand, we are planning to only operate a bare skeleton passenger flight schedule for April, which represents up to 90 percent capacity reduction,” Lim added.</p>
      <p>“If we do not see a relaxation of travel restrictions in the near future, we expect the same arrangement will have to continue into May,” he said.</p>
      <p>While the carrier’s freighter capacity remains intact, the reduction of its passenger flights has had a significant impact on its overall cargo capacity as well as its ability to carry cargo to destinations only served by our passenger flights. However, we remain flexible in deploying additional cargo capacity, including mounting additional freighter flights as well as cargo-only passenger flights.</p>
      <p>“The prolonged Chinese New Year holiday together with efforts to contain the coronavirus outbreak in early February led to a delay in the resumption of production in mainland China. Demand for outbound airfreight from the mainland and Hong Kong only began to recover progressively from mid-February,” he said.</p>
      <p>In contrast, there was an overflow of demand for cargo services into mainland China and Hong Kong partly due to significant capacity cutbacks and a surge of pharmaceutical-related orders. The carrier’s cargo load factor grew 5.8 percentage points with stable yield in February when compared with last year.</p>
      <p>“The scale of the challenge we are currently facing is unprecedented and no one can predict when conditions will improve. Our advance passenger bookings show no clear signs of recovery at this stage, and the gap in bookings compared to 2019 continues to widen,” Lim warned.</p>
      <p>“We already made it known last week that a substantial loss in the first half of this year is expected. Nevertheless, Cathay Pacific is a resilient company and we remain confident in the future of the company, of Hong Kong as an aviation hub, and in our ability to thrive in this region over the long term,” he concluded.</p>
    </content>
  </document>
  <document>
    <document_id>91d1fb</document_id>
    <url>https://www.stattimes.com/news/cargoguide-launches-new-online-rate-management-platform-air-cargo/</url>
    <title>Cargoguide launches new online rate management platform</title>
    <author>The STAT TRADE TIMES</author>
    <published_time>2020-03-18T15:50:00+05:30</published_time>
    <terms/>
    <categories>
      <category>Air Cargo</category>
    </categories>
    <topics>
      <topic>international air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo news</topic>
      <topic>aviation industry news</topic>
      <topic>air freight forwarders news</topic>
      <topic>air cargo world news</topic>
      <topic>air freight news</topic>
    </topics>
    <links/>
    <content>
      <p>Cargoguide has officially unveiled its new online rate management platform, as part of its mission to simplify rate management and boost global freight forwarding.</p>
      <p>The new platform is a feature-rich search engine for the freight forwarding sector and enables forwarders to meet the key challenges they face in their day-to-day sales operations by increasing transparency and efficiency.</p>
      <p>It builds on the success of its predecessor Cargo Office. The new Cargoguide enables forwarders to compare accurate air freight rates including surcharges, create better rate calculations by including detailed shipment information in the search, create and send custom quotes quickly and easily from within the system and track and manage sales opportunities.</p>
      <p>Cargoguide already works with more than 1,500 forwarders in over 84 countries. Compared to traditional paper-based and scattered digital spreadsheets, Cargoguide allows users to save an average of two hours per day. In addition, as a cloud-based solution, it has no installation time. It can be used to work remotely and provides up-to-date rates and flight schedules. Allowing for simplified rate management, enhanced productivity and ultimately increasing margins.</p>
      <p>Bas van der Putten, growth manager, Cargoguide said, “We believe the freight forwarding process should be transparent, neutral and conducted within a fair market. Cargoguide is the next step in helping make that a reality.</p>
      <p>“This is an exciting time for us and for digital technology in the wider freight forwarding sector. It is however a challenging time for many freight forwarders and carriers, as they look to meet the demands of modern customers while remaining competitive.”</p>
      <p>“That's where Cargoguide can add real value. We understand that forwarders and carriers need a platform that connects them through rates and that is continuously innovating and growing with them. The transparent rate calculations and accuracy of Cargoguide's data is unique and truly sets us apart from other platforms.”</p>
      <p>Jorre Cobelens, founder and managing director, Cargoguide International, added, “We've established great partnerships over the years, working with the Carriers, GSAs and forwarders as their independent partner. Having created a standard for comparable freight rates since 2003, the platform allows carriers to market their capacity and forwarders to easily compare freight rates.</p>
      <p>“Our mantra is ‘Dare to Improve', continuing to innovate and boost global freight forwarding. With our dedicated teams and niche software, we strive to maintain the highest reliability standards. This is an exciting time for us as we enhance our service.”</p>
    </content>
  </document>
</corpus>
